ETC.. NO IT'S OKAY.
THERE WE GO OR NO. >> READY?
OKAY. >> ALL RIGHT.
GOOD AFTERNOON. WELCOME TO THE DECEMBER 16TH,
2025 REGULAR MEETING OF THE SAN FRANCISCO BOARD OF SUPERVISORS.
>> MADAM CLERK, WILL YOU PLEASE CALL THE ROLL?
THANK YOU, MR. PRESIDENT. SUPERVISOR CHAN CHAN PRESIDENT.
SUPERVISOR. CHEN CHEN PRESIDENT.
SUPERVISOR. DORSI.
DORSI PRESENT SUPERVISOR FIELDER.
FIELDER PRESIDENT. SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD
PRESENT SUPERVISOR MANDELSON RESIDENT MANDEL PRESENT
SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR PRESENTS SUPERVISOR SAUTER SADR
PRESENT SUPERVISOR CHERYL SHERRELL PRESENT SUPERVISOR
WALTON WALTON PRESENT AND SUPERVISOR HUANG WONG WONG
PRESENT TO MR. PRESIDENT ALL MEMBERS ARE PRESENT.
>> THANK YOU MADAM CLERK. THE SAN FRANCISCO BOARD OF
SUPERVISORS ACKNOWLEDGES THAT WE ARE ON THE UNCEDED ANCESTRAL
HOMELAND OF THE RAMAKRISHNA LONEY WHO ARE THE ORIGINAL
INHABITANTS OF THE SAN FRANCISCO PENINSULA.
AS THE INDIGENOUS STEWARDS OF THIS LAND AND IN ACCORDANCE
WITH THEIR TRADITIONS THE RAW MATERIAL ONI HAVE NEVER CEDED
LOST NOR FORGOTTEN THEIR RESPONSIBILITIES AS THE
CARETAKERS OF THIS PLACE AS WELL AS FOR ALL PEOPLES WHO
RESIDE IN THEIR TRADITIONAL TERRITORY.
AS GUESTS WE RECOGNIZE THAT WE BENEFIT FROM LIVING AND WORKING
ON THEIR TRADITIONAL HOMELANDS .
WISH TO PAY OUR RESPECTS BY ACKNOWLEDGING THE ANCESTORS
ELDERS AND RELATIVES OF THE RAMAKRISHNA ALONI COMMUNITY
AND BY AFFIRMING THEIR SOVEREIGN RIGHTS AS FIRST
PEOPLES. COLLEAGUES, WILL YOU JOIN ME
IN RECITING THE PLEDGE OF ALLEGIANCE?
I PLEDGE ALLEGIANCE TO THE FLAG OF THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA
AND TO THE REPUBLIC FOR WHICH IT STANDS ONE NATION UNDER GOD,
INDIVISIBLE, WITH LIBERTY AND JUSTICE FOR ALL.
ON BEHALF OF THE BOARD I WANT TO ACKNOWLEDGE THE STAFF AT
S.F. GOV TV TODAY THAT IS ESPECIALLY KALEENA MENDOZA.
THEY RECORD EACH OF OUR MEETINGS AND MAKE OUR
TRANSCRIPTS AVAILABLE TO THE PUBLIC ONLINE.
>> AND WITH THAT, MADAM CLERK, CAN YOU TAKE US TO OUR 2 P.M.
SPECIAL ORDER? >> YES, THE 2 P.M. SPECIAL
ORDER IS THE APPEARANCE BY THE HONORABLE MAYOR DANIEL LURIE.
HE SHALL DISCUSS ELIGIBLE TOPICS SUBMITTED FROM ELIGIBLE
DISTRICTS. THE MAYOR MAY ADDRESS THE BOARD
INITIALLY FOR UP TO FIVE MINUTES.
>> WELCOME, MR. MAYOR. DO YOU HAVE ANY OPENING
REMARKS? >> GOOD AFTERNOON BOARD
PRESIDENT MANAGEMENT AND MEMBERS OF THE BOARD.
AS WE COME TO THE CLOSE OF THIS FINAL BOARD OF SUPERVISORS
SESSION OF THE YEAR WE ALSO MARK NEARLY ONE FULL YEAR OF
WORKING SIDE BY SIDE IN SERVICE TO THE CITY THAT I KNOW WE ALL
LOVE. >> MOMENTS LIKE THIS INVITE
REFLECTION AND GRATITUDE. >> I WANT TO THANK EACH OF YOU
FOR YOUR DEDICATION TO THE PEOPLE OF SAN FRANCISCO
AND YOUR WILLINGNESS TO WORK TOGETHER BECAUSE OF THE
COLLABORATION WE HAVE SEEN THIS PAST YEAR.
SAN FRANCISCO IS A CITY ON THE RISE.
TODAY 62% OF SAN FRANCISCANS FEEL THAT WAY COMPARED TO JUST
28% LAST YEAR. THAT CONFIDENCE IS EARNS
THROUGH OUR SHARED COMMITMENT TO RESULTS AND TO MAKING CITY
GOVERNMENT WORK BETTER FOR THE PEOPLE THAT WE SERVE.
BOARD PRESIDENT MANAGEMENT. FROM MY FIRST DAY IN OFFICE YOU
HAVE SET THE TONE FOR THIS BODY AND FOR THE STRONG
COLLABORATION ACROSS SUPERVISORS AND DEPARTMENTS.
THANK YOU FOR WORKING TOGETHER TO MAKE IT EASIER FOR SMALL
BUSINESSES AND RESTAURANTS BY ELIMINATING PERMITS AND FEES
FOR SIMPLY PLACING TABLES AND CHAIRS ON THE SIDEWALK.
I LOOK FORWARD TO CONTINUING OUR WORK TO REFORM THE CHARTER
AND MAKE IT MORE EFFECTIVE AND ACCOUNTABLE TO OUR
RESIDENTS. I AM ALSO DEEPLY GRATEFUL FOR
THE ADVICE AND COUNSEL YOU HAVE GENEROUSLY SHARED WITH ME SINCE
MY FIRST DAY IN OFFICE. SUPERVISOR CHAN.
WE WORK TOGETHER COLLABORATING COLLABORATIVELY TO PUT FORWARD
A BALANCED BUDGET THAT FOCUSED ON CORE SERVICES AND SET OUR
CITY UP FOR SUCCESS. I APPRECIATE YOU AND THANK YOU
FOR YOUR PARTNERSHIP. >> SUPERVISOR SHERYL.
WE'VE WORKED TOGETHER TO HELP OUR SMALL BUSINESSES.
YOU HAVE BEEN A CHAMPION IN PROVIDING RESOURCES TO HELP
OUR SMALL BUSINESSES THRIVE THROUGH PERMIT S.F.
SPECIFICALLY ENTERTAINMENT PERMITS AND FIRST YEAR FREE.
THANK YOU. SUPERVISOR CHERYL.
SUPERVISOR SOUDER. YOU AND I BOTH UNDERSTAND THAT
PUBLIC SAFETY IS KEY TO OUR COMEBACK.
THE SIDESHOW LEGISLATION YOU PUT FORWARD WILL HELP KEEP OUR
COMMUNITY SAFE BY RAISING THE FINES FOR THESE DANGEROUS
SIDESHOWS TO BE IN LINE WITH OUR NEIGHBORING COUNTIES.
>> THANK YOU FOR YOUR LEADERSHIP ON THAT.
>> SUPERVISOR SOUDER. SUPERVISOR WONG IN YOUR FIRST
WEEK IN OFFICE YOU STARTED WORKING TO REPRESENT THE PEOPLE
OF THE SUNSET AND PARK SIDE WITH PRIDE FOR DAY 300 OF
PERMIT S.F.. YOU PARTNERED WITH MY OFFICE TO
INTRODUCE LEGISLATION THAT WILL MODERNIZE OUR OUTDATED STREET
TREE PERMITTING PROCESS AND IN TURN SAVE RESIDENTS TIME
AND MONEY. THANK YOU.
SUPERVISOR HUANG. SUPERVISOR MAHMUD.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR PARTNERSHIP IN SECURING $3.4 MILLION
IN PHILANTHROPIC FUNDING FOR IMMIGRANT LEGAL DEFENSE.
THE FUNDS HELPED OUR PUBLIC DEFENDERS IMMIGRATION DEFENSE
UNIT AND ENSURES THAT SAN FRANCISCANS AND SAN FRANCISCO
STANDS UP FOR OUR VALUES. >> THANK YOU.
SUPERVISOR MAHMUD. SUPERVISOR DORSEY.
THROUGH OUR PARTNERSHIP WE HAVE OPENED OVER 500 TREATMENT BEDS
AND RECOVERY BEDS IN SAN FRANCISCO AND I'M PROUD TO HAVE
WORKED TOGETHER WITH YOU TO MAKE SAN FRANCISCO A RECOVERY
FIRST CITY. >> THANK YOU, SUPERVISOR.
SUPERVISOR MELGAR. >> LAST WEEK ALONGSIDE YOU
AND MANY IN THIS ROOM I SIGNED THE FAMILY ZONING PLAN THAT
WOULD NOT HAVE HAPPENED OR BEEN POSSIBLE WITHOUT YOUR DILIGENT
WORK CHAIRING THE LAND USE COMMITTEE THAT INCLUDED LONG
HEARINGS AND MULTIPLE AMENDMENTS.
YOU HELPED MAKE THE LEGISLATION STRONGER.
THANK YOU. SUPERVISOR MELGAR.
SUPERVISOR FIELDER. WHEN THE FEDERAL GOVERNMENT WAS
PREPARED TO LET FAMILIES IN SAN FRANCISCO GO WITHOUT FOOD, WE
WORKED TOGETHER TO PROVIDE EMERGENCY FUNDING FOR SNAP
RECIPIENTS. >> THANK YOU.
SUPERVISOR FIELDER SUPERVISOR WALTON.
>> THANK YOU FOR YOUR LEADERSHIP IN DELIVERING THE
GATEWAY PROJECT. AT 749 TOLAND STREET IN THE
HEART OF THE BAYVIEW HUNTERS POINT INDUSTRIAL COURT.
THIS PROJECT WILL HELP SAN FRANCISCO CREATE GREAT JOBS
GOOD JOBS WHILE DELIVERING MEANINGFUL COMMUNITY BENEFITS.
THANK YOU SUPERVISOR WALTON AND SUPERVISOR CHEN.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR WORK ON THE TENANT PROTECTION PROTECTION
ORDINANCE WHICH HAS EARNED THE CO-SPONSORSHIP OF EVERY SINGLE
MEMBER OF THIS BOARD. I LOOK FORWARD TO SIGNING IT
AND WORKING WITH YOUR OFFICE TO ENSURE OUR CITY CAN BUILD
HOUSING AND CONTINUE TO PROTECT TENANTS.
AS WE LOOK AHEAD TO THE COMING YEAR I AM CONFIDENT IN WHAT WE
CAN ACCOMPLISH TOGETHER. THE CHALLENGES FACING SAN
FRANCISCO ARE REAL BUT SO IS THE PROGRESS WE'VE MADE AND SO
IS THE STRENGTH OF THIS PARTNERSHIP.
IF WE CONTINUE TO LEAD WITH COLLABORATION, FOCUS ON RESULTS
AND KEEP OUR EYES ON THE PEOPLE THAT WE SERVE THERE IS NO DOUBT
THAT OUR BEST DAYS ARE STILL AHEAD OF US.
I WANT TO THANK ALL 11 OF YOU FOR YOUR SERVICE AND FOR YOUR
COMMITMENT TO MOVING SAN FRANCISCO FORWARD.
>> LET'S GO. >> THANK YOU, MR. MAYOR.
MADAM CLERK, COULD YOU PLEASE CALL THE TOPIC FOR DISTRICT
FIVE? >> YES.
THE DISTRICT FIVE TOPIC FROM SUPERVISOR MAHMUD IS THE
FENTANYL STATE OF EMERGENCY ORDINANCE.
>> SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD, PLEASE ASK YOUR OPENING QUESTION.
>> THANK YOU, PRESIDENT. EARLIER THIS YEAR THE BOARD
VOTED TO GIVE THE MAYOR GREATER POWER TO ADDRESS THE FENTANYL
CRISIS QUICKLY AND AVOID BUREAUCRATIC DELAYS.
>> MAYOR WHAT SPECIFIC RESOURCES TOOLS AND CONTRACTS
HAVE BEEN USED UNDER THE FENTANYL STATE OF EMERGENCY
ORDINANCE TO ADDRESS THE FENTANYL CRISIS IN THIS LAST
YEAR? >> THANK YOU FOR YOUR QUESTION
SUPERVISOR MAHMUD AND FOR YOUR SUPPORT OF THIS FENTANYL STATE
OF EMERGENCY ORDINANCE. SINCE ITS PASSAGE WE HAVE MOVED
QUICKLY TO UNLOCK RESOURCES AND DEPLOY NEW TOOLS TO GET
FENTANYL OFF OUR STREETS AND KEEP SAN FRANCISCANS SAFE.
THE ORDINANCE ACCELERATED THE IMPLEMENTATION OF CRITICAL
INITIATIVES UNLOCKING FUNDING, EXPEDITED HIRING
AND CONTRACTING AND ENABLED THE RAPID EXPANSION OF TREATMENT
CAPACITY. IT ALSO SUPPORTED NEW
BEHAVIORAL HEALTH INITIATIVES AND ACCELERATED HIRING OF KEY
PUBLIC SAFETY STAFF AS A RESULT.
THE ORDINANCE ENABLED SAGE TO EXECUTE 31 CONTRACTS AND ONE
LEASE AND EXPEDITING THE LAUNCH OF NEW SERVICES.
THESE INCLUDE 219 NEW INTERIM HOUSING BEDS, 60 OF THEM
RECOVERY FOCUSED AND 594 NEW SCATTERED SITE HOUSING SLOTS
AND EXPANDED SUPPORT FOR THE CITY'S LARGE VEHICLE STRATEGY.
AMMO CD HAS ALSO USED THE AUTHORITY PROVIDED BY THE
ORDINANCE TO ADVANCE FIVE CRITICAL PERMANENT SUPPORTIVE
HOUSING PROJECTS. HAS SIMILARLY LEVERAGED THE
ORDINANCE TO QUICKLY STAND UP NEW BEHAVIORAL HEALTH PROGRAMS.
THE DEPARTMENT USES THE ORDINANCE CONTRACTING
PROVISIONS FIVE TIMES INCLUDING RAPIDLY OPENING OPENING
APPROXIMATELY 150 NEW MENTAL HEALTH AND SUBSTANCE USE
TREATMENT AND RECOVERY BEDS. DIEM AND HSA WORK TOGETHER TO
EXPEDITE GRANTS UNDER THIS ORDINANCE THAT CONTINUED
ESSENTIAL COMMUNITY SAFETY AMBASSADOR PROGRAMS SUPPORTING
CRITICAL NEIGHBORHOODS INCLUDING THE TENDERLOIN
MID-MARKET AND THE MISSION. FINALLY MY OFFICE OF INNOVATION
IN PARTNERSHIP WITH S.F. P.D. USED THE ORDINANCE TO BRING ON
PRO BONO CONSULTANT THROUGH THE CIVIC BRIDGE PROGRAM TO SUPPORT
ACCELERATED POLICE HIRING. THESE ACTIONS DEMONSTRATE THE
FENTANYL STATE OF EMERGENCY. THE ORDINANCE IS DELIVERING
REAL IMMEDIATE RESULTS MOVING FASTER THAN OUR TRADITIONAL
SYSTEMS ALLOW EXPANDING CARE AND HOUSING AND STRENGTHENING
PUBLIC SAFETY. IT HAS GIVEN THE CITY THE
FLEXIBILITY IT NEEDED TO RESPOND TO A CRISIS WITH
URGENCY, COORDINATION AND ACCOUNTABILITY AND IT
CONTINUES TO BE A CRITICAL TOOL IN OUR EFFORTS TO SAVE LIVES
AND RESTORE SAFETY TO OUR STREETS.
>> THANK YOU FOR THE QUESTION. >> THANK YOU, MAYOR LURIE.
SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD, YOU MAY NOW ASK A FOLLOW UP QUESTION
DIRECTLY RELATED TO THE OPENING QUESTION.
>> THANK YOU, MAYOR, AND APPRECIATE THE FOCUS ON THE
METRICS AND THE IMPACT OVER THE LAST YEAR.
NEXT QUESTION AND FOLLOW UP IS ABOUT LARGER REVISIONS TO
STRATEGY. PART OF THE EMERGENCY ORDER WAS
ALSO ABOUT FINDING NEW APPROACHES TO TACKLE THE
FENTANYL CRISIS AND HOLISTIC DIFFERENT WAY.
ONE SUCH APPROACH THAT THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS SUPPORTED
TO BE A MAJORITY OF US ON A RESOLUTION WAS AROUND A DRUG
MARKET INTERVENTION STRATEGY WHICH HAS SUCCESSFULLY ENDED
OPIOID MARKETS ACROSS THE UNITED STATES.
I WANTED TO ASK YOU TODAY WHETHER YOU WOULD ADD YOUR NAME
TO SUPPORT ON A DRUG MARKET INTERVENTION APPROACH TO PUT IT
INTO PRACTICE AFTER THE BOARD HAS ENDORSED THE PLAN AS WELL?
>> YES, I WILL. >> AND I LOOK FORWARD TO
WORKING WITH YOU. SUPERVISOR MCMURRAY AND YOU
SUPERVISOR DORSEY AND ALL OF THE OTHERS AT THE BOARD TO
TACKLE THIS CRISIS IN THE TENDERLOIN AND SOMA
AND WHEREVER ELSE IT DEMANDS OUR ATTENTION.
I APPRECIATE YOUR LEADERSHIP ON THIS ISSUE.
THANK YOU, MAYOR. THANK YOU.
ALL RIGHT. MR. MAYOR, I BELIEVE THAT YOU
MAY LET'S SEE WHERE'S OUR LITTLE WHERE'S MY PROMPT?
>> YOU MAY ASK? WELL, HAVE YOU DONE THIS
BEFORE? >> I KNOW YOU KNOW WHAT I'M
DOING. YOU CAN ASK.
WOULD YOU LIKE TO ASK NO SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD OR ANY
MEMBER OF THE BOARD A QUESTION? NO, I WANT TO I WANT TO I WANT
TO WISH EVERYBODY IN THESE CHAMBERS AND ALL ALL THE
SUPERVISORS A HAPPY AND HEALTHY HOLIDAY SEASON.
TAKE CARE OF YOURSELVES AND I WILL SEE YOU IN 2026.
>> ALL RIGHT. ALL RIGHT.
THANK YOU, MR. MAYOR. APPRECIATE YOU.
>> AND THAT'S IS IT. THANK YOU, MAYOR LARRY FOR
JOINING US TODAY. THE MATTER HAS BEEN DISCUSSED
AND WILL BE FILED AFTER GENERAL PUBLIC COMMENT.
MADAM CLERK, THAT'S GOING TO TAKE US BACK I THINK TO
COMMUNICATIONS. >> I WOULD NOTE I THINK WE HAVE
I THINK WE HAVE THE SUPERVISOR AMOS BROWN IN THE CHAMBER.
I THOUGHT I SAW HIM. >> HE MAY HAVE BEEN HERE ALL
RIGHT. ANYWAY, MADAM CLERK, DO WE HAVE
ANY COMMUNICATIONS? >> YES, MR. PRESIDENT, WE DO.
THANK YOU ALL FOR ATTENDING THIS MEETING IN PERSON.
IF YOU'RE UNABLE TO MAKE IT, PLEASE WATCH IT ON CHANNEL 26
OR IF YOU WOULD LIKE TO LIVE STREAM IT AT W W W DOT SFR GO V
T V.ORG IF YOU HAVE PUBLIC COMMENT YOU'D LIKE TO SUBMIT
YOU CAN DO SO BY EITHER SENDING AN EMAIL TO BOSS AT S.F.
GOV.ORG OR USE THE U.S. POSTAL SERVICE THE SAN FRANCISCO BOARD
OF SUPERVISORS THE NUMBER ONE DR. CARLTON SHOULD BE GOODLAND
PLACE CITY HALL ROOM 244 SAN FRANCISCO CALIFORNIA 94102 IF
YOU NEED TO MAKE A REASONABLE ACCOMMODATION FOR A FUTURE
MEETING UNDER THE AMERICANS WITH DISABILITIES ACT OR TO
REQUEST LANGUAGE ASSISTANCE, PLEASE CONTACT THE CLERK'S
OFFICE TWO BUSINESS DAYS IN ADVANCE BY CALLING
(415) 554-5184. THANK YOU, MR. PRESIDENT.
>> THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK. LET'S GO TO APPROVAL OF OUR
MEETING MINUTES THE APPROVAL OF THE NOVEMBER 10TH, 2025 SPECIAL
BOARD MEETING MINUTES CAN I HAVE A MOTION TO APPROVE THE
MINUTES AS PRESENTED MOVED BY CHAN SECONDED BY DORSEY MADAM
CLERK, WILL YOU PLEASE CALL THE ROLL ON THE MINUTES AS
PRESENTED SUPERVISOR MANDOLIN I MANDOLIN I SUPERVISOR MELGAR I
MELGAR I SUPERVISOR SADR SADR I SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL I
SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON I SUPERVISOR WONG WONG I
SUPERVISOR CHAN CHIN I SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN I
SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY I SUPERVISOR FIELDER FIELDER I
AND SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD I THERE ARE TEN EYES WITHOUT
OBJECTION THE MINUTES MISPRESENT I MISSTATED THERE
ARE 11 EYES OKAY THANK YOU AND SO WITHOUT OBJECTION THE
MINUTES WILL BE APPROVED AFTER PUBLIC COMMENT AS PRESENTED
AND MADAM CLERK LET'S GO TO OUR CONSENT AGENDA ITEMS TWO
THROUGH FOUR ITEMS TWO THROUGH FOUR ON CONSENT.
THESE ITEMS ARE CONSIDERED TO BE ROUTINE IF A MEMBER OBJECTS
AN ITEM MAY BE REMOVED AND CONSIDERED SEPARATELY.
>> THESE CALL THE ROLL ON ITEMS TWO THROUGH FOUR SUPERVISORS
ARE MANDOLIN MANDOLIN EYES SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR EYES
SUPERVISOR SADR SADR EYES SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL EYES
SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON EYES SUPERVISOR WONG WONG EYES
SUPERVISOR CHAN CHU CHAN EYES SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN I
SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY I SUPERVISOR FIELDER FIELDER I
AND SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD EITHER ARE LEBANESE WITHOUT
OBJECTION THE ORDINANCE IS FINALLY PASSED AND THE
RESOLUTIONS ARE ADOPTED MADAM CLERK LET'S GO TO OUR REGULAR
AGENDA UNFINISHED BUSINESS PLEASE CALL ITEM FIVE ITEM FIVE
THIS IS AN ORDINANCE TO AMEND THE BUSINESS AND TAX
REGULATIONS CODE TO EXTEND THE SUSPENSION OF THE CANNABIS
BUSINESS TAX THROUGH DECEMBER 31ST 2035 AND TO REMOVE
REFERENCES TO THE CANNABIS BUSINESS TAX FROM THE COMMON
ADMINISTRATIVE PROVISIONS OF THE CODE PLEASE CALL THE ROLL
ON ITEM FIVE SUPERVISE HER MANDOLIN MANDOLIN EYES
SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR I SUPERVISOR SADR SADR EYES
SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL I SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON NO
SUPERVISOR WONG A SUPERVISOR WAS THAT A NO WONG NO
SUPERVISOR CHAN CHIN NO SUPERVISOR CHEN CHIN EYES
SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY EYES SUPERVISOR FIELDER FIELDER
FIELDER I AND SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD I THERE ARE
EIGHT EYES AND THREE NOSE WITH SUPERVISORS WALTON WONG
AND CHAN VOTING NO THE ORDINANCE IS FINALLY PASSED
MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM SIX ITEM SIX THIS IS AN
ORDINANCE TO AUTHORIZE SETTLEMENT OF THE LAWSUIT FILED
BY DEVON ANDERSON. BEVERLY L SWEENEY ON BEHALF OF
THEMSELVES AND ALL OTHER SIMILARLY SITUATED CURRENT
AND FORMER EMPLOYEES AGAINST THE CITY AND COUNTY FOR UP TO
20 MILLION. THIS LAWSUIT INVOLVES AN
EMPLOYMENT DISPUTE. >> PLEASE CALL THE ROLL ON ITEM
SIX SUPERVISOR RANDLEMAN I RANDLEMAN I SUPERVISOR MELGAR
MELGAR I SUPERVISOR SADR SADR I SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL I
SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON I SUPERVISOR WONG WONG I
SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN EYES SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN I
SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY I SUPERVISOR FIELDER FIELDER I
SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMUT I THERE ARE 11 EYES WITHOUT
OBJECTION THE ORDINANCE IS FINALLY PASSED MADAM CLERK
PLEASE CALL ITEM NUMBER SEVEN ITEM SEVEN THIS IS AN ORDINANCE
TO AMEND THE BUILDING CODE TO REVISE THE TIMING OF EXPIRATION
OF CERTAIN BUILDING PERMITS AND BUILDING PERMIT
APPLICATIONS AND TO AFFIRM THE SEQUEL DETERMINATION PLEASE
CALL THE ROLL ON ITEM SEVEN SUPERVISOR RANDLEMAN HI
RANDLEMAN I'M SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR I SUPERVISOR SADR SADR I
SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL I SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON KNOWS
SUPERVISOR WONG WONG I SUPERVISOR CHAN CHIN NO
SUPERVISOR CHEN CHIN NO SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY I
SUPERVISOR FIELDER FIELDER NO AND SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD
I THERE ARE SEVEN EYES AND FOUR NOSE WITH SUPERVISORS WALTON
CHAN CHEN AND FIELDER VOTING NO THE ORDINANCE IS FINALLY PASSED
MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM EIGHT ITEM EIGHT THIS IS AN
ORDINANCE TO AMEND THE PLANNING CODE TO ALLOW THE CITY TO WAIVE
THE INCLUSIONARY HOUSING FEE AND OTHER REQUIREMENTS
IN CERTAIN RESIDENTIAL AND NEIGHBORHOOD COMMERCIAL
DISTRICTS OUTSIDE OF THE PRIORITY EQUITY GEOGRAPHIES
SPECIAL USE DISTRICT IN EXCHANGE FOR A PROJECT
SPONSORS AGREEMENT TO SUBJECT ALL UNITS IN THE PROJECT TO
RENT CONTROL AND TO ALLOW PROJECTS IN CERTAIN RESIDENTIAL
AND NEIGHBORHOOD COMMERCIAL DISTRICTS OUTSIDE OF THE
PRIORITY EQUITY GEOGRAPHIES AS SUCH TO COMPLY WITH THE
INCLUSIONARY HOUSING ORDINANCE BY DEDICATING LAND TO THE CITY
REQUIRING PERIODIC REPORTS TO THE PLANNING COMMISSION AND TO
AFFIRM THE SECOND DETERMINATION AND TO MAKE THE APPROPRIATE
FINDINGS. >> PLEASE CALL THE ROLL ON ITEM
EIGHT SUPERVISOR RANDLEMAN HI MENDELSON I SUPERVISOR MELGAR
MELGAR I SUPERVISOR SADR SADR I SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL I
SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON I SUPERVISOR WONG WONG I
SUPERVISOR CHEN CHAN I SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN I
SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY I SUPERVISOR FIELDER FIELDER I
AND SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD I THERE ARE THREE LEBANESE
WITHOUT OBJECTION THE ORDINANCE IS FINALLY PASSED MADAM CLERK
PLEASE CALL ITEM NUMBER NINE ITEM NINE THIS IS AN ORDINANCE
TO AMEND THE ADMINISTRATIVE CODE TO ESTABLISH THE
REPARATIONS FUND AND WE CAN TAKE THAT ITEM SAME HOUSE, SAME
CALL. WITHOUT OBJECTION THE ORDINANCE
IS FINALLY PASSED. >> MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL
ITEM TEN. ITEM TEN THIS IS AN ORDINANCE
TO AMEND THE PLANNING CODE AND THE ADMINISTRATIVE CODE BY
SUPERSEDING CERTAIN PROVISIONS OF ORDINANCE NUMBER 149 DASH 16
TO INCREASE THE SURCHARGES ON CERTAIN PLANNING DEPARTMENT
FEES TO COMPENSATE THE CITY FOR APPEALS OF PLANNING DEPARTMENT
ACTIONS TO THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS TO AFFIRM THE SCORE
DETERMINATION AND TO MAKE THE APPROPRIATE FINDINGS.
>> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL. WITHOUT OBJECTION THE ORDINANCE
IS PASSED ON FIRST READING MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM 11
. >> ITEM 11 THIS IS A RESOLUTION
TO RETROACTIVELY AUTHORIZE AND APPROVE THE OFFICE OF THE
TREASURER AND TAX COLLECTOR TO EXECUTE THE FOURTH AMENDMENT
FOR A SERVICE AND SUPPORT AGREEMENT WITH COLLECTION
SOLUTION SOFTWARE INC TO ENABLE THE COLLECTION OF DELINQUENT
TAXES AND OTHER DEBTS TO EXTEND THE CONTRACT TERM FIVE YEARS
FOR A TOTAL TERM OF DECEMBER FIRST 2016 THROUGH NOVEMBER
30TH 2030 WITH ONE OPTION TO RENEW FOR AN ADDITIONAL FIVE
YEARS TO INCREASE THE CONTRACT AMOUNT BY 2.5 MILLION FOR A NEW
TOTAL OF 6.9 MILLION. >> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL
WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTION ADOPTED MADAM CLERK,
PLEASE CALL ITEM 12 ITEM 12 THIS IS A RESOLUTION TO APPROVE
THE THIRD AMENDMENT TO THE GRANT AGREEMENT BETWEEN THE
CITY ACTING BY AND THROUGH THE DEPARTMENT OF HOMELESSNESS
AND SUPPORT OF HOUSING AND CATHOLIC CHARITIES FOR
FAMILY EVICTION PREVENTION COLLABORATIVE HOMELESSNESS
PREVENTION. TO EXTEND THE TERM BY 30 MONTHS
FOR A TOTAL TERM NOW JULY 1ST, 2021 THROUGH JUNE 30TH 2028 TO
INCREASE THE AGREEMENT BY APPROXIMATELY 8.6 MILLION FOR A
NEW TOTAL OF 18.5 MILLION. >> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL.
WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTIONS ADOPTED.
MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEM NUMBER 13 ITEM 13 THIS IS A
RESOLUTION TO RETROACTIVELY AUTHORIZE THE FIRE DEPARTMENT
TO ACCEPT AND EXPEND AN APPROXIMATE $2.7 MILLION GRANT
FROM THE FEDERAL EMERGENCY MANAGEMENT AGENCY TO PURCHASE
SELF-CONTAINED BREATHING APPARATUS UNITS FOR THE
PERFORMANCE PERIOD OF SEPTEMBER 26TH, 2024 THROUGH SEPTEMBER
25TH 2026 AND TO WAIVE INDIRECT COSTS AND TO DO THAT SAME HOUSE
SAME CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTIONS ADOPTED.
>> MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEM 14 ITEM 14 THIS RESOLUTION
APPROVES AND AUTHORIZES THE GENERAL MANAGER OF THE SAN
FRANCISCO PUBLIC UTILITIES COMMISSION TO EXECUTE THE FIRST
AMENDMENT TO A CONTRACT FOR ENGINEERING SERVICES FOR DAMS
AND RESERVOIRS WITH GE CONSULTANTS INKS TO INCREASE
THE CONTRACT AMOUNT BY 7 MILLION FOR A NEW CONTRACT
AMOUNT OF 18 MILLION. DURATION IS THE SAME ESTIMATED
COMPLETION DATE OF APRIL 2031. TO ADD DESIGN SERVICES FOR THE
MOCCASIN DAM AND THE RESERVOIR LONG TERM IMPROVEMENT PROJECT
AND PLANNING AND DESIGN SERVICES TO THE O'SHAUGHNESSY
DAM OUTLET WORKS PHASE TWO PROJECT UNDER THE HATCH
HATCHERY WATER CAPITAL IMPROVEMENT PROGRAM.
>> SAME HOUSE. SAME CALL.
WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED.
MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEM 15.
>> ITEM 15 THIS RESOLUTION APPROVES THE FIRST AMENDMENT TO
THE AGREEMENT BETWEEN THE CITY ACTING A BUY IN THROUGH THE
DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC HEALTH AND COMMUNITY FORWARD AS IF TO
PROVIDE MEDICAL RESPITE AND SOBERING CENTER SERVICES TO
EXTEND THE TERM THREE YEARS AND SIX MONTHS FOR A TOTAL TERM
JULY FIRST 2024 THROUGH JUNE 30TH 2029 AND TO INCREASE THE
AMOUNT BY 22 MILLION FOR A NEW TOTAL OF 32 MILLION SAME HOUSE
SAME CALL. >> WITHOUT OBJECTION THE
RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED. MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEM
16 ITEM 16 RESOLUTION TO AUTHORIZE THE DIRECTOR OF
PROPERTY TO EXECUTE A SECOND AMENDMENT TO A LEASE BETWEEN
THE CITY AND LA COCINA INC RELATED TO THE LEASE OF CITY
OWNED PROPERTY LOCATED AT 101 HYDE STREET TO EXTEND THE LEASE
FOR AN ADDITIONAL FIVE YEARS JANUARY FIRST, 2027 FOR A TOTAL
TERM THROUGH DECEMBER 31ST 2031 WITH NO CHANGE TO THE ANNUAL
BASE RENT OF 12,000 TO MAKE CERTAIN OTHER MODIFICATIONS TO
THE SECOND AMENDMENT TO LEASE AND TAKE CERTAIN ACTIONS
IN FURTHERANCE OF THIS RESOLUTION.
>> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION THE
RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED. MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEM
17 THROUGH 20 TOGETHER. >> YES THESE FOR RETROACTIVE
RESOLUTIONS AUTHORIZE AND ACCEPT AND EXPEND GRANTS
FOR THE DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC HEALTH.
ITEM 17 AUTHORIZES A CALIFORNIA DEPARTMENT OF HEALTH CARE
SERVICES GRANT THROUGH BLUE CROSS OF CALIFORNIA PARTNERSHIP
PLAN INC ANTHEM FOR PARTICIPATION IN A PROGRAM
ENTITLED HOUSING AND HOMELESSNESS INCENTIVE
PROGRAM THROUGH JUNE 30TH, 2026.
ITEM 18 AUTHORIZES A $2.5 MILLION GRANT INCREASE FROM THE
CALIFORNIA DEPARTMENT OF HEALTH CARE SERVICES THROUGH THE SAN
FRANCISCO HEALTH PLAN TO PARTICIPATE IN A PROGRAM
ENTITLED HOUSING AND HOMELESSNESS INCENTIVE
PROGRAM FOR A TOTAL AMOUNT OF 7.6 AND A TERM THROUGH NOVEMBER
1ST, 2026 AND TO APPROVE THE NOTICE OF THE AWARD AGREEMENT
ITEM 19 THIS APPROVES A $2 MILLION GRANT FROM THE CENTERS
FOR DISEASE CONTROL AND PREVENTION TO PARTICIPATE
IN A PROGRAM ENTITLED HIGH IMPACT HIV PREVENTION
AND SURVEILLANCE PROGRAMS FOR HEALTH DEPARTMENTS FOR 7
MILLION FOR THE TERM JUNE 1ST, 2025 THROUGH MAY 31ST, 2026
AND A TOTAL GRANT AMOUNT OF 12.7 MILLION THROUGH MAY 31ST
2026 AND FOR ITEM 20 THIS RESOLUTION AUTHORIZES A GRANT
FROM THE NATIONAL INSTITUTES OF HEALTH THROUGH FLORIDA STATE
UNIVERSITY TO PARTICIPATE IN A PROGRAM ENTITLED ADOLESCENT
MEDICINE TRIALS NETWORK FOR HIV AND AIDS INTERVENTION
SCIENTIFIC LEADERSHIP CENTER FOR AN INCREASED AMOUNT OF
APPROXIMATELY 62,000 FOR A TOTAL AMOUNT OF 235,358
EFFECTIVE ON MAY 21ST 2025 AND WE CAN TAKE THOSE ITEMS
SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTIONS ARE
ADOPTED. >> MADAM CLERK LET'S GO TO OUR
230 SPECIAL ORDER YES OUR 230 SPECIAL ORDER IS THE
COMMENDATION FOR THE RECOGNITION OF MERITORIOUS
SERVICE TO THE CITY AND COUNTY OF SAN FRANCISCO AND I BELIEVE
WE'RE GOING TO START TODAY WITH DISTRICT NINE SUPERVISOR
FIELDER THANK YOU. AND I'M GOING TO ASK CAMEO
HOUSE TO PLEASE COME UP TO THE PODIUM.
>> COLLEAGUES, I AM THRILLED TO PRESENT THIS COMMENDATION FOR
CAMEO HOUSE, ONE OF THE FEW DIRECT SERVICE PROGRAMS RUN BY
THE CENTER ON JUVENILE AND CRIMINAL JUSTICE.
CAMEO HOUSE WAS FOUNDED IN 1998 AND TODAY PROVIDES AN ESSENTIAL
ALTERNATIVE SENTENCING AND TRANSITIONAL HOUSING
PROGRAM FOR JUSTICE INVOLVED MOTHERS THREE UNIQUE
PARTNERSHIP RUN BY S.J. S.J. THAT IS PREDOMINANTLY FUNDED BY
THE SAN FRANCISCO SHERIFF'S OFFICE.
>> CAMEO HOUSE IS A CHARMING THREE STOREY EDWARDIAN HOME
BUILT IN 1911 LOCATED AT 4 TO 4 GROVE STREET.
>> AS IT HAPPENS LAST NIGHT THERE WAS AN EXPLOSION AT THE
GAS STATION IMMEDIATELY ADJACENT TO THE HOME.
THANKFULLY ALL OF THE WOMEN, CHILDREN AND STAFF FROM THE
SITE ARE OKAY AND THEIR EMERGENCY EVACUATION PROGRAM
PROTOCOLS WERE SWIFT AND COMMENDABLE.
TODAY, IN ADDITION TO BEING HERE TO ACCEPT THIS
COMMENDATION STAFF ARE WORKING TO ENSURE THE FAMILY'S LIVES
AREN'T NEGATIVELY IMPACTED AS THEY STILL HAVE COURT AND OTHER
JUSTICE MANDATES TO MEET ALONG WITH FAMILY REUNIFICATION
VISITS AND OTHER SCHEDULED EVENTS THAT THEY NEED TO
CONTINUE ITS PLANNED CAMEO HOUSE.
AT ITS CORE IS A SUPPORTIVE SAFE AND COMFORTABLE SPACE.
RESIDENTS RECEIVE MENTAL AND PHYSICAL HEALTH SERVICES
SUBSTANCE USE TREATMENT, PARENTING AND LIFE SKILLS
TRAINING ASSISTANCE, NAVIGATING JUSTICE AND SOCIAL SERVICE
SYSTEMS. VOCATIONAL AND EDUCATIONAL
SUPPORT. HOUSING TRANSITION PLANNING
AND OPPORTUNITIES FOR COMMUNITY AND CIVIC ENGAGEMENT.
>> THIS TRANSFORMATIVE PROGRAM IS ONE OF A KIND OFFERING A
RESIDENTIAL ALTERNATIVE TO INCARCERATION WHERE
PARTICIPANTS CAN LIVE WITH THEIR CHILDREN WHILE RECEIVING
COMPREHENSIVE SUPPORT SERVICES WITH THEY FOCUS ON GENDER
RESPONSIVENESS AND A COMMITMENT TO CREATING A SAFE, NURTURING
ENVIRONMENT. CAMEO HOUSE EMPOWERS WOMEN TO
REBUILD THEIR LIVES AND FOSTER STRONGER FAMILY BONDS.
>> SINCE ITS INCEPTION, THE PROGRAM HAS BEEN A BEACON OF
HOPE HELPING PARTICIPANTS NAVIGATE CHALLENGES OF
REINTEGRATION AND THRIVE AS VALUABLE COMMUNITY MEMBERS.
THE HOME ACCOMMODATES 11 WOMEN AND UP TO 24 CHILDREN AT ANY
GIVEN TIME PROVIDING EACH FAMILY UNIT WITH THEIR OWN
PRIVATE BATHROOMS AND BEDROOMS. >> I WANT TO PAINT A PICTURE OF
THIS HOME. >> THE SPACE IS WARM,
WELCOMING, BRIGHT AND LOVING. >> WITH PRIVATE ACCOMMODATIONS
AND COMMUNAL SPACE FOR FAMILY PLAY, CHILD DEVELOPMENT
AND COMMUNITY BUILDING THERE'S A COZY LIVING ROOM TWO DINING
ROOMS, THREE LARGE FULL KITCHENS, TWO LAUNDRY ROOMS,
TWO INFANT AND TODDLER PLAYROOMS WITH TOYS AND BOOKS
AND AN OLDER CHILDREN'S ROOM FULL OF BOOKS WITH A POOL TABLE
FOOSBALL AND BOARD GAMES OUT BACK AND ENCLOSED YARD FEATURES
PLAY STRUCTURES FOR THE KIDS AND SPACES FOR ADULTS TO RELAX
AND CONNECT. >> THE HOUSE HOSTS COMMUNAL
MINI MEALS GROUP GATHERINGS, BIRTHDAY CELEBRATIONS
AND FAMILY EVENTS TO NURTURE COMMUNITY AND UPLIFT FAMILIES.
IN FISCAL YEAR 2425. CAMEO HOUSE SERVED 22 WOMEN
AND 44 CHILDREN WITH 20 KIDS LIVING ON SITE WITH THEIR MOMS.
PROGRAM OUTCOMES DEMONSTRATE STRONG AND LASTING IMPACT.
>> 80 1% OF PROGRAM PARTICIPANTS PROGRAM EXITS
TRANSITION INTO PERMANENT STABLE HOUSING.
>> 63 PERCENT OF PARTICIPANTS REDUCED THEIR SUBSTANCE USE.
88% OF PARTICIPANTS DID NOT RE-OFFEND.
UNDERSCORING THE EFFECTIVENESS OF COMMUNITY BASED ALTERNATIVES
TO INCARCERATION. THESE OUTCOMES REFLECT THE
POWER OF PROVIDING STABILITY, DIGNITY AND OPPORTUNITY NOT
ONLY TRANSFORMING INDIVIDUAL LIVES BUT STRENGTHENING
FAMILIES AND A BROADER COMMUNITY.
THANK YOU SO MUCH TO CAMEO HOUSE STAFF.
>> CURRENT AND FORMER RESIDENTS WHO HAVE PERSEVERED THROUGH
THIS PROGRAM AND TO SEE JESSIE J FOR YOUR VISION
AND DETERMINATION IN CREATING AND SUSTAINING SUCH A MODEL
PROGRAM. CONGRATULATIONS AND PLEASE GO
AHEAD. >> THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU. GOOD AFTERNOON.
THANK YOU. PRESIDENT, MANAGER, MANAGEMENT
AND BOARD. BOARD SUPERVISOR MEMBERS.
THIS IS MY FIRST TIME EVER DOING THIS SO I'M A LITTLE
NERVOUS. SO BEAR WITH ME.
THANK YOU FOR THIS ACCOMMODATION AND FOR
RECOGNIZING CAMEO. THANK YOU JACKIE FIELDER
AND JEN FERRIGNO FOR REACHING OUT.
COMING TO SEE OUR HOME BECOME PART OF OUR HOME AND OFFERING
YOUR SUPPORT. WE REALLY APPRECIATE YOU.
APPRECIATE YOU. AND JEN, IT WAS A PLEASURE
HAVING YOU IN OUR HOME. CAMEO HOUSE WAS IT WAS CREATED
TO ENSURE THAT JUSTICE INVOLVED WOMEN ARE NOT SEPARATED FROM
THEIR FAMILIES WHILE THEY'RE WORKING TO REBUILD THEIR LIVES.
FOR THE FAMILIES WE WE SERVE, THIS PROGRAM OFFERS STABILITY,
DIGNITY AND A SAFE PLACE TO HEAL AND REUNIFY WITH YOUR
CHILDREN. AND A REAL SECOND CHANCE.
EVERY DAY WE WITNESS THE POWERFUL TRANSFORMATIONS.
MOTHERS REUNITING WITH THEIR CHILDREN SECURE IN EMPLOYMENT,
RETURNING TO SCHOOL AND TRANSITIONING TO PERMANENT
HOUSING. BUT BEYOND THESE OUTCOMES WE
SEE SOMETHING JUST AS IMPORTANT .
CHILDREN WAKING UP IN A SAFE HOME WITH THEIR MOTHERS
AND FAMILIES TOGETHER. >> IN LIGHT OF THE EXPLOSION
THAT OCCURRED LAST NIGHT, IT SERVED AS A STARK REMINDER OF
HOW UNPREDICTABLE LIFE CAN BE. >> THANKS TO THE QUICK THINKING
AND THE CALM RESPONSES OF KIM, YOUR STAFF MONETTE AND DAISY,
ALL THE WOMEN AND CHILDREN WERE SAFELY EVACUATED.
WE ARE ALSO DEEPLY GRATEFUL FOR OUR CONTRACTOR MARTY, WHO
REMAINED ON SITE THROUGHOUT THE ENTIRE EVENT.
>> HE WAS STUCK ON THE ROOF BUT HE WENT INTO QUICK ACTION.
HE ENSURED THAT ALL THE SYSTEMS WERE PROPERLY SHUT OFF
AND CONFIRMED THAT EVERYONE WAS SAFELY OUT OF THE BUILDING.
THEIR ACTIONS HELPED PREVENT FURTHER HARM AND KEPT EVERYONE
SAFE. WE ALSO WANT TO ACKNOWLEDGE THE
C.J. CJ'S ENTIRE AGENCY FOR PICKING IN IMMEDIATELY
AND HELPING SECURE SHELTER AND ACCOMMODATIONS FOR ALL THE
FAMILIES. >> THIS RECOGNITION AFFIRMS SAN
FRANCISCO COMMITMENT TO COMPASSION, ACCOUNTABILITY
AND COMMUNITY BASED SOLUTIONS. THAT TRULY WORKS IS THE
DEDICATION OF OUR CAMPBELL STAFF.
THE STRENGTH OF OUR CAMEO RESIDENTS AND THE PARTNERSHIPS
SUCH AS SAN FRANCISCO SHERIFF'S OFFICE, THE WOMEN'S RESOURCE
CENTER, THE WOMEN'S HOUSING COALITION POSITIVE DIRECTORS
DIRECTION SISTER CIRCLE AND MANY, MANY MORE COMMUNITY
PARTNERS. IN FACT WE HAD A PROPERTY
MANAGER STEP UP AND OFFER THREE MAKING APARTMENTS FOR OUR
WOMEN. THEY STAYED THERE UNTIL WE CAN
GET THEM INTO A SHELTER WHERE THEY CAN HAVE BEDS AND STUFF.
>> ALL OF THIS COLLABORATION MAKES THIS POSSIBLE.
IT MAKES IT WORK. IT IS VITAL THAT THIS RESOURCE
REMAINS IN THIS COMMUNITY REMAINS REMAINS IN THIS
COMMUNITY. SORRY.
I WANT TO SAY THANK YOU FOR HONORING KIM YOUR HOUSE AND FOR
YOUR CONTINUED INVESTMENT IN KEEPING FAMILIES TOGETHER.
WE ARE DEEPLY GRATEFUL. >> THANK YOU.
I THINK HE'S UP FOR THE NEXT ONE.
>> ALL RIGHT. I NOTE THAT WE HAVE BEEN JOINED
ALSO BY OUR FORMER BOARD PRESIDENT NORMAN YEE WHO I
THINK IS HERE FOR OUR NEXT SPECIAL COMMENDATION.
>> DISTRICT SEVEN SUPERVISOR MELGAR.
THANK YOU, PRESIDENT. COLLEAGUES, I AM HONORING TODAY
ON BEHALF OF THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS DR. PATRICIA
SULLIVAN KNOWN TO MOST OF US AS PAT.
>> DR. SULLIVAN WAS A SCHOLAR, EDUCATOR ADVOCATE WHO PASSED
AWAY UNEXPECTEDLY EARLIER THIS YEAR.
I REALLY WISH WE HAD HAD THE OPPORTUNITY TO HONOR HER WHEN
SHE WAS STILL WITH US. TODAY WE ARE JOINED BY HER
FAMILY, FRIENDS, COLLEAGUES, MENTEES AND COMMUNITY MEMBERS
AND EVERYONE WHO WAS TOUCHED BY HER COMPASSION, HER FIERCE
ADVOCACY AND LIFELONG COMMITMENT TO SAN FRANCISCO'S
CHILDREN AND FAMILY. SO IF YOU'RE HERE FOR A PAT IF
YOU COULD STAND UP PLEASE JUST THANK YOU.
THIS IS PAT'S COMMUNITY AND SO THANK YOU, DR. SULLIVAN.
>> AND PAT WAS BORN IN DETROIT, MICHIGAN TO JEAN SULLIVAN, AN
ARMY RADIO MAN AND COLLEEN SULLIVAN, AN ART STUDENT AT THE
TIME WHEN PAT WAS A CHILD. HER PARENTS WITH HER OLDEST
SISTER KATHLEEN, A YOUNGER BROTHER MICHAEL MOVED TO L.A.
WHERE BOTH PARENTS COULD PURSUE THEIR CAREERS.
BUT IN L.A. A NATIONAL TRAGEDY STRUCK WHICH REDIRECTED THE
YOUNG FAMILY. >> HER PARENTS WERE ALREADY
INVOLVED POLITICALLY. HER FATHER ATTENDED BLACK
PANTHER MEETINGS. PAT'S MOTHER WORKED FOR BOBBY
KENNEDY DURING HIS PRESIDENTIAL RUN IN 1968 AND WAS IN THE
BALLROOM OF THE AMBASSADOR HOTEL THE NIGHT HE WAS
ASSASSINATED. THE FBI THINKING ACHILLE MIGHT
HAVE BEEN A WITNESS DECIDED TO MOVE THE FAMILY TO SAFETY.
AND WHEN ASKED WHERE THEY WANTED TO GO, JEAN AND COLLEEN
SAID SAN FRANCISCO. WHAT THEY DIDN'T TELL THE FBI
WAS THAT THEY THOUGHT THE REVOLUTION WAS GOING TO START
IN SAN FRANCISCO AND THEY WANTED TO BE RIGHT THERE IN THE
CENTER OF THINGS. SO FROM THE VERY BEGINNING PAT
HAD ROOTS AS A FIGHTER FOR JUSTICE IN SAN FRANCISCO.
>> PAT ATTENDED APTN NIEMI JUNIOR HIGH SCHOOL, WASHINGTON
HIGH SCHOOL CITY COLLEGE AND SAN FRANCISCO STATE
UNIVERSITY. >> SHE HAD SEVERAL JOBS AFTER
SCHOOL LEAVING SCHOOL BACK UP AS A SINGER, AS A SINGER IN A
BAND, AS A BARTENDER, AS A FAST FOOD MANAGER.
BUT IT WAS WHEN SHE WORKED WITH CHILDREN AT THE YMCA NEAR
JAPANTOWN AT THE BUCHANAN YMCA THAT SHE FOUND HER CALLING.
PAT DECIDED TO START HER OWN DAYCARE CENTER BABY STEPS
FAMILY CHILD CARE. BY THE TIME PAT HAD HER OWN SON
MATTHEW AND SHE DEDICATED THE REST OF HER LIFE TO SERVING THE
CHILDREN STUDENT AND PARENTS OF SAN FRANCISCO.
>> IT WAS NOT ENOUGH TO RUN BABY STEPS.
>> PAT ALSO DECIDED TO RETURN TO SAN FRANCISCO STATE TO LEARN
MORE ABOUT THE FIELD SHE HAD ENTERED EARNING A BACHELOR'S
DEGREE THEN A MASTER'S AND THEN FINALLY HER DOCTORATE OF
EDUCATION SPECIALIZING IN EARLY CHILD DEVELOPMENT.
>> PAT BROUGHT A DEEP UNDERSTANDING OF COMMUNITY OF
EQUITY A BELONGING TO HER RESEARCH AND IN PRACTICE HER
DISSERTATION A TRAIL OF BREADCRUMBS BLACK EARLY
CHILDHOOD EDUCATION STUDENTS SUCCESS IN HIGHER EDUCATION.
REFLECTED ON HER LIFELONG COMMITMENT TO ADVANCING
EDUCATION, PERSONAL OPPORTUNITY AND EQUITY.
HER DISSERTATION RESEARCH EXAMINED THE EXPERIENCES
AND STRATEGIES FOR SUCCESSFUL BLACK EARLY CHILDHOOD EDUCATION
STUDENTS IN SAN FRANCISCO'S STATE HIGHLIGHTING THE
RESILIENCE, INSIGHT AND AGENCY OF STUDENTS WHO PERSISTED
IN HIGHER EDUCATION. >> DESPITE ALL THE SYSTEMIC
BARRIERS FRAMING HER ANALYSIS THROUGH THE LENSES OF STUDENT
RETENTION MICROAGGRESSION AND STEREOTYPE THREAT OFFERING
A STUDENT CENTER PERSPECTIVE THAT EMPHASIZED SUCCESS RATHER
THAN ATTRITION HER FINDINGS CONTINUE TO INFORM APPROACHES
TO IMPROVING DEGREE COMPLETE COMPLETION AND EQUITY FOR BLACK
STUDENTS IN EARLY CHILDHOOD EDUCATION AND BEYOND.
PAT RECEIVED A FELLOWSHIP FROM THE DAVID AND LUCILLE PACKARD
FOUNDATION TO STUDY EARLY CHILDHOOD TEACHER CREDENTIALING
. >> AFTER EARNING HER DOCTORATE,
PAT TAUGHT IN THE EARLY CHILDHOOD EDUCATION PROGRAMS
BOTH AT SAN FRANCISCO STATE AND CITY COLLEGE.
>> HER TEACHING DREW DEEPLY FROM HER YEARS AS A FAMILY
CHILD CARE PROVIDER AND OWNER OF BABY STEPS FAMILY CHILDCARE
WHERE SHE MENTORED GENERATIONS OF EARLY EDUCATORS.
SHE WAS ALSO A PUBLISHED AUTHOR WHOSE SCHOLARSHIP AND TEACHER
RESEARCH APPEARED IN VOICES FOR PRACTITIONERS AND OTHER
PROFESSIONAL PUBLICATIONS. HER MOST RECENT CHAPTER APPEARS
IN A BOOK EDITED BY DANIEL MEIER EXTENDING HER LIFELONG
COMMITMENT TO ELEVATING THE VOICES AND WISDOM OF EARLY
CHILDHOOD EDUCATORS. >> PAT WAS KNOWN FOR HER
LEADERSHIP AS A DIRECTOR OF THE FAMILY CHILD CARE ASSOCIATION
OF SAN FRANCISCO, FORMER BOARD PRESIDENT OF THE FAMILY CHILD
CARE ASSOCIATION OF SAN FRANCISCO AND AS A CO-CHAIR OF
EARLY CARE EDUCATORS. SHE WAS ALSO APPOINTED TO
REPRESENT FAMILY CHILD CARE PROVIDERS ON THE OVERSIGHT
AND ADVISORY COMMITTEE FOR EARLY EDUCATION WHERE I SERVED
WITH HER THROUGHOUT HER CAREER. DR. SULLIVAN SERVED AS A BRIDGE
BETWEEN HIGHER EDUCATION AND THE FAMILY CHILD CARE
COMMUNITY WORKING TIRELESSLY TO IMPROVE SYSTEMS FOR CHILDREN,
FAMILIES AND EDUCATORS ACROSS CALIFORNIA.
PAT WAS A BELOVED COLLEAGUE, A MENTOR OR A MOTHER, SISTER
AND AUNTIE A FRIEND WHO BROUGHT WARMTH, HUMOR AND AN UNWAVERING
SENSE OF JUSTICE TO EVERY SPACE SHE ENTERED.
HER LIFE'S WORK CONTINUES TO GUIDE OUR COLLECTIVE EFFORTS TO
SUPPORT, HONOR AND LEARN FROM THE PRACTITIONERS WHO MAKE
EARLY CHILDHOOD EDUCATION A FORCE FOR EQUALITY FOR CARE
AND FOR THE FUTURE. PAT IS SURVIVED BY HER SON
MATTHEW, SISTER KATHLEEN AND HER FAMILY.
HER BROTHER MICHAEL IN HIS FAMILY AND BY HUNDREDS HUNDREDS
OF CHILDREN AND TEACHERS SHE INSPIRED THROUGHOUT HER WORK
AND LOVE. I JUST WANT TO ACKNOWLEDGE ALL
OF THE INCREDIBLE EARLY CARE EDUCATORS AND ADVOCATES WHO ARE
HERE IN THE CHAMBER TODAY AND INCLUDING MY PREDECESSOR,
FORMER PRESIDENT NORM. >> MANY I.
PLEASE PLEASE STAND AT WELL. >> HER LEGACY LIVES THROUGH ALL
OF YOU AND THE WORK SHE LED FOR BETTER WORKING CONDITIONS FOR
EARLY CARE EDUCATORS AND FOR HISTORIC INVESTMENTS FOR BY
FAMILY CHILDCARE PROVIDERS AND FOR BLACK FAMILIES IN OUR
CITY AND THROUGHOUT AND THROUGH THE PRESIDENT AND I.
BEFORE WE HAVE OTHER SUPERVISORS SPEAK, I WAS
WONDERING IF WE COULD HEAR FROM FORMER PRESIDENT AND FORMER
DISTRICT SEVEN SUPERVISOR NORMAN YEE WHO KNEW PAT FOR
MOST OF HER LIFE IF YOU COULD COME UP PRESIDENT YEE I WOULD
APPRECIATE IT. THE FLOOR IS YOURS.
THANK YOU. SUPERVISOR MELGAR AND IT'S BEEN
A LITTLE WHILE SINCE I'VE BEEN IN THIS CHAMBER.
PRESIDENT MANAGEMENT AND SUPERVISOR WALTON MY FORMER
COLLEAGUES. NICE SEEING YOU HERE.
THE REST OF YOU, YOU'RE ALL NEW BUT GLAD TO SEE YOU HERE
SERVING YOUR CITY. >> IT TOOK SOMETHING FOR ME TO
COME BACK HERE. >> I MEAN AND THE PERSON THAT
WE'RE HONORING TODAY IS WHAT IT TOOK.
>> IT'S A LUMPY REPEATING A LOT OF THINGS THAT SUPERVISOR MEL
HAS HAVE SAID. BUT I THINK IT'S WORTH
REPEATING THE IMPACT THAT SHE HAD WITH ALL THE DIFFERENT
PEOPLE IN SAN FRANCISCO. SO YOU KNOW, EVERY GENERATION
OR SO SAN FRANCISCO IS BLESSED WITH SOMEBODY SPECIAL.
AND PAT EXCUSE ME DR. PATRICIA SULLIVAN IS ONE OF THESE
INDIVIDUALS. SHE IS ONE OF THESE
INDIVIDUALS. AND ANYBODY I HAD THE HONOR OF
MEETING HER WILL UNDERSTAND WHAT I'M TALKING ABOUT.
SHE CAME TO US BY WAY OF DETROIT AND WAS RAISED AS A
TEEN IN THE CITY. SHE EVEN WENT TO APEC IN ANY
AND GRADUATED FROM WASHINGTON HIGH SCHOOL REAL LOCAL.
SHE LOVED THE CITY. SHE LOVED ITS CHILDREN.
SHE LOVED ITS FAMILIES. >> SHE DEDICATED HER ENTIRE
LIFE TO GIVE HUNDREDS IF NOT THOUSANDS OF YOUNG CHILDREN TO
START IN LIFE THAT EVERY CHILD SHOULD RECEIVE.
>> SHE DID THIS THROUGH NOT ONLY THE 30 PLUS YEARS OF
OPERATING HER OWN FAMILY CHILD CARE HOMES.
SHE COULD BE WALKING DOWN THE STREET AND GET THE SAME LOVE TO
A STRANGER. SHE COULD BUILD A PLAYGROUND
AND GIVE THE SAME LOVE TO A CHILD.
WE NOW KNOW THAT'S NOT HOW YOU TALK TO PEOPLE.
SO SHE'S ALWAYS EDUCATING. AND THAT'S SOMETHING THAT THAT
BASICALLY THE IMPACT THAT SHE HAS HAD ON CHILDREN
AND FAMILIES WILL LAST FOREVER .
>> SHE WELL, YOU KNOW, FOR MOST PEOPLE THAT'S ENOUGH HAVING TO
OPERATE YOUR OWN FAMILY CHILD CARE HOME DAY IN AND DAY OUT
ALL THE LITTLE ONES I THINK I THINK WELL SHE HAD TO NOT ONLY
SIX BUT FOR 12 OR 14 OF THEM RUNNING AROUND AND THAT'S
EXHAUSTING. BUT WHILE SHE WAS OPERATING
IN HER FAMILY CHILDCARE HOME, SHE ALSO DID GO BACK TO SCHOOL,
GOT HER PH.D. AND STARTED TEACHING AS A PROFESSOR AT SAN
FRANCISCO STATE AND AND CITY COLLEGE.
SO SHE'S VERY UNIQUE IN THAT WAY.
MOST PEOPLE WOULD JUST DEDICATE THEIR LIVES TO ONE AGE BRACKET.
AND HERE SHE'S NOT ONLY WORKING WITH THE YOUNG ONES BUT SHE'S
TRAINING THE NEXT GENERATIONS OF EARLY EDUCATORS TO MAKE SURE
THAT THEY HAVE THE SAME INSPIRATION THAT SHE HAS FOR
CHILDREN. THE SAME LOVE THAT SHE HAS FOR
CHILDREN, THE SAME WAY OF INSPIRING CHILDREN.
>> AND THAT'S WHAT SHE WAS ABOUT.
>> SHE REALLY DOES SACRIFICE SELF.
I MEAN IT WAS INTERESTING TO LISTEN TO HER FAMILY AND OTHER
FRIENDS TALK ABOUT HER EARLIER. RIGHT BEFORE THE SESSION INSANE
. >> I KNOW HER SISTER COULDN'T
BE ME WITH HER BECAUSE SHE'S TOO BUSY ON THE PHONE TALKING
TO PEOPLE AND GUIDING THEM AND SO FORTH AND SO FOR HER IT
WAS AN EIGHT HOUR JOB. IT WAS A 24 SEVEN.
SHE WAS ALWAYS ON IF YOU NEED HELP SHE'S THERE.
SO SOMEHOW BETWEEN RUNNING HER OWN FAMILY CHILD CARE HOME
AND TEACHING ADULTS, SHE MANAGED TO STILL VOLUNTEER FOR
A BUNCH OF OTHER THINGS. SO ON ONE OF THEM BEING THAT
SHE BECAME THE HEAD OF THE FAMILY CHILDCARE ASSOCIATION
WHICH IS A FULL TIME JOB IN ITSELF SO I DON'T KNOW HOW
SHE DID IT. I MEAN IT WAS LIKE THREE FULL
TIME JOBS AND SHE'S JUGGLING IT AND SO FORTH.
>> AND SHE DID IT FOR WHAT ABOUT 7 OR 8 YEARS
IN ASSOCIATION AND SHE JUST NEVER SLOWED DOWN.
>> THAT'S THE TYPE OF PERSON SHE IS.
THAT'S THE TYPE OF PERSON I LIKE TO THAT'S THE TYPE OF
PERSON IS WHY I COME HERE TO SPEAK ABOUT HER, THE LOVE THAT
SHE HAS AND IS GIVEN BACK BY OTHER PEOPLE HERE IN THE ROOM
IS SOMETHING THAT YOU JUST DON'T SEE WITH A LOT OF MANY OF
OUR OUR PEOPLE IN SAN FRANCISCO .
SO YOU KNOW, FOR FOR SOME OF YOU THAT DON'T KNOW WHAT WHAT
IS THE FAMILY CHILDCARE ASSOCIATION AND YOU MIGHT THINK
OH WELL YOU KNOW THIS THERE'S THIS 20 YEAR 20 HOMES THAT THEY
TRY TO COORDINATE. WELL NO SHE WAS COORDINATING
THE EFFORTS OF 630 PLUS FAMILY CHILDCARE HOMES THAT WERE
ACTIVE. THERE WERE SOME LOT MORE THAT
WERE INACTIVE BUT 630 OF THEM WERE ACTIVE WITH DIFFERENT
ISSUES AND SHE HEARD THEM ALL AND SHE WAS ABLE TO REPRESENT
THEM IN A ROOM OTHER COMMITTEES SHE SAID.
AND SHE SAT. SO AND IT WAS IMPORTANT FOR HER
TIME OR NOT THAT SHE GETS TO THAT ROOM AND REPRESENT THE
COMMUNITY THAT SHE LOVES. AND IT'S BEEN AND I THINK
THAT'S THE ONE MOTIVATOR FOR HER AS I HEARD EARLIER AND I
KNOW THIS ABOUT HER, SHE'S GOT TO BE IN THAT ROOM.
IF NOT HER, THEN WHO? SO THIS IS SOMETHING I HOPE
THAT YOU WILL REMEMBER ABOUT HER.
SHE'S LOVED BY ALL OF US. SHE'S SHE'S STILL IN OUR
PRESENCE TODAY. THAT'S WHO SHE IS.
I MEAN WE ALL THINK ABOUT FOR HER.
AND IF I HAVE AN ISSUE THAT I CAN'T FIGURE OUT I SAID I WOULD
ASK THE QUESTION WELL, WHAT WOULD PAT DO?
>> AND USUALLY I COULD GET SOME KIND OF ANSWER.
SO I WANT TO SEE THAT SHE'S SHE WAS A GIANT IN HER SUPPORT FOR
CHILDREN, FAMILIES AND EARLY EDUCATORS.
>> AND LIKE I SAID, SHE'S STILL IN OUR PRESENCE.
AND I REALLY WANT TO THANK THE BOARD FOR HONORING HER TO SEE
FOR HER FAMILY AND HER FRIENDS TO SEE THIS HAPPEN.
I KNOW THIS IS IT SHOULD HAVE BEEN DONE MANY, MANY YEARS AGO
BUT IT'S BETTER LATE THAN NEVER.
>> SO THANK YOU VERY MUCH. SUPERVISOR WONG THANK YOU.
>> I GOT TO KNOW DR. SULLIVAN OVER THE PAST TWO OR SO YEARS
WHEN I WAS WORKING AS A POLICY DIRECTOR AT CHILDREN'S COUNCIL
OF SAN FRANCISCO. I HAD THE OPPORTUNITY OF
WORKING FOR ANNETTE WHO ALONG FOR A COALITION OF ADVOCACY
ADVOCACY GROUPS SUPPORTING U.S. AND THERE ARE A NUMBER OF
THINGS THAT WE WORK TOGETHER ON INCLUDING COMING TO CITY HALL
PUSHING THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS ON EASY ISSUES,
PUTTING TOGETHER A POLICY RETREAT TO BRING TOGETHER THE
CHILD CARE COMMUNITY. AND SHE WAS ALSO A CITY COLLEGE
FACULTY MEMBER AND VERY PASSIONATE ABOUT HER WORK.
>> SHE STEPPED UP TO JOIN THE CHANCELLOR'S SELECTION OR
RECOMMENDATION COMMITTEE AT CITY COLLEGE AND HELPED BE ONE
OF MY MY APPOINTEES TO HELP GUIDE US THROUGH THAT THAT
PROCESS. AND I REMEMBER ONE LAST THINGS
THAT SHE SAID TO ME WAS THAT I LOVE CITY COLLEGE.
>> I REALLY LOVED THAT PLACE AND YOU KNOW THAT THOSE ARE
WORDS THAT STUCK TO ME. >> AND ONE LAST THING THAT SHE
SAID TO ME WHEN I LAST SAW HER AND HER PASSING IS A TREMENDOUS
LOSS TO OUR CITY AND EVERYONE WHO CARES ABOUT ISHII IN HER
WORK AT UCSF, I, I GOT TO KNOW ABOUT HER HER WORK CURRENT DAY
AND HOW SHE WORKED WITH ALL THE ALL THE COMMUNITY TO TO PUT UP
A VOICE FOR FOR THAT FOR A COMMUNITY AND YOU KNOW ALSO
READING PRESIDENT THIS BOOK I LEARNED ABOUT THE PAST HISTORY
ABOUT HOW THEY'VE GOT A LONG HISTORY OF ADVOCACY IN THE PAST
AND HOW SHE STEPPED UP TO THE MANTLE TOO FOR THAT CURRENT DAY
FOR FOR ME I THINK THAT THIS IS A A REMINDER OF YOU KNOW, ONE
OF THE REASONS WHY I'M HERE TO BE ABLE TO ADVOCATE FOR
EDUCATION AND FOR FOR YOUTH AND THAT'S SOMETHING THAT WHEN
I THINK OF HER THAT I WILL CONTINUE TO COMMIT MYSELF TO
DOING. ONE OTHER NOTE I WANT TO
MENTION IS I GOT TO VISIT HER HER HOME WITHOUT SHE SHE ALSO
SERVES THE COMMUNITY FOR CHILD CARE AND AND ALSO GOT TO KNOW
SOPHIA ALUM THERE AND JUST SEEING HOW SHE WORKS WITH THE
CHILDREN AND HER LOVE FOR HER WORK, HER PASSION FOR HER
PROFESSION THE PEOPLE THAT SHE SHE CARES FOR.
IT'S SO UPLIFTING TO SEE SOMEBODY THAT IS OUT THERE
ADVOCATING SUPPORTING, SERVING THE COMMUNITY AND WE'RE
GRATEFUL FOR HER LIFE AND THE IMPACT THAT SHE HAS MADE ON OUR
CITY AND OUR THOUGHTS ARE WITH HER LOVED ONES AND HER LEGACY
WILL CONTINUE TO INSPIRE ALL OF US.
>> THANK YOU. THANK YOU.
WE ARE NOW JOINED BY DR. SULLIVAN'S FAMILY.
PLEASE ACCEPT THIS SPECIAL COMMENDATION ON BEHALF OF YOUR
FAMILY POSTHUMOUSLY. YOU HAVE OUR DEEPEST REGRETS
IN CONDOLENCES AND ALSO LOVE AND ADMIRATION FOR AND FOR DR.
SULLIVAN. SO IF YOU WANTED TO SAY A FEW
WORDS YOUR NOW IS THE TIME. WELL, I WANT TO THANK YOU ALL
SO MUCH FOR ACKNOWLEDGING PAT'S LIFETIME OF WORK AND COMMITMENT
TO THE FAMILIES, CHILDREN, TEACHERS, ALL EDUCATORS OF THE
CITY OF SAN FRANCISCO. SHE PASSIONATELY LOVED THE CITY
AND FELT LIKE AS WE WERE SAYING, OUR FAMILY MOVED HERE
BECAUSE WE THOUGHT THIS WAS WHERE THE REVOLUTION WAS GOING
TO START AND WE WANTED TO BE AT THE EPICENTER.
>> SO WE WERE RAISED TO BE REVOLUTIONARIES AND SO PAT'S
LIFE IS AN EXAMPLE OF HOW MUCH EVERYONE CAN BE AN ACTIVIST
AND SHE RAISED THE CHILDREN TO ALWAYS KNOW THAT THE CITY, THE
COUNTRY, THE WORLD THIS IS THEIR PLACE.
THEY HAVE A PLACE IN THIS AND WHAT HAPPENS HERE IS
DECIDED BY THEM AND THAT'S WHAT BABY STEPS REALLY WAS AND I
HOPE THAT SHE GOT THAT ACROSS TO ALL OF HER STUDENTS AND ALL
OF THE TEACHERS THAT SHE WORKED WITH.
>> AND THANK YOU VERY MUCH
. >> DISTRICT TEN SUPERVISOR
WALTON THANK YOU SO MUCH PRESIDENT MENDHAM
AND COLLEAGUES TODAY I AM PROUD TO RECOGNIZE THE BAY VIEW
UNITED GIRLS SOCCER TEAM THAT REALLY GETS YOU TO TO COME UP
AND STAND THIS EXCEPTIONAL GROUP OF YOUNG ATHLETES WHOSE
SUCCESS REFLECTS BOTH ATHLETIC EXCELLENCE AND THE POWER OF
EQUITY AND ACTION. FOUNDED IN 2019 AND OPERATED BY
THE SAN FRANCISCO RECREATION AND PARKS DEPARTMENT, BABY
UNITED IS SAN FRANCISCO'S FIRST PRIMARILY BLACK YOUTH SOCCER
PROGRAM PROVIDING A HIGH QUALITY SOCCER EXPERIENCE FOR
YOUTH IN BAYVIEW HUNTERS POINT BY REMOVING FINANCIAL
AND ACCESS BARRIERS. THE PROGRAM HAS EXPANDED
OPPORTUNITIES FOR NEARLY 50 YOUNG ATHLETES TO PARTICIPATE
IN THE WORLDS GAME WITH PRIDE AND PURPOSE.
>> THIS SEASON THE SIXTH GRADE GIRLS TEAM CAPTURED THE SAN
FRANCISCO YOUTH SOCCER PREMIER DIVISION CHAMPIONSHIP WITH A
FOUR TWO TITLE AND AN EXTRAORDINARY ACHIEVEMENT MADE
EVEN MORE IMPRESSIVE BY THE FACT THAT THE TEAM IS MADE UP
LARGELY OF FOURTH GRADERS ALONG WITH A FEW FIFTH GRADERS
AND EVEN ONE THIRD GRADER. >> THEIR SUCCESS SPEAKS NOT
ONLY TO SKILL AND DETERMINATION BUT TO TEAMWORK, RESILIENCE
AND COMMUNITY SUPPORT. PRACTICING AND PLAYING AT
YOUNGBLOOD COLEMAN PLAYGROUND AND REPRESENTING BAYVIEW ON
FIELDS ACROSS THE CITY. THESE YOUNG ATHLETES CARRY
THEIR NEIGHBORHOOD WITH THEM EVERY SINGLE TIME THEY COMPETE.
WE ALSO RECOGNIZE THE COACHES, FAMILIES AND MENTORS WHO HAVE
BUILT A PROGRAM ROOTED IN FUN. >> DEVELOPMENT AND NEIGHBORHOOD
PRIDE. BAYVIEW UNITED IS MORE THAN A
SOCCER TEAM. IT IS AN INVESTMENT IN HEALTH
LEADERSHIP AND OPPORTUNITY FOR YOUTH AND A MODEL FOR HOW
INCLUSIVE COMMUNITY CENTERED PROGRAMS CAN HELP YOUNG PEOPLE
THRIVE. >> CONGRATULATIONS TO THE
BAYVIEW UNITED'S SIX GREAT GIRLS SOCCER TEAM ON ITS
OUTSTANDING ACCOMPLISHMENT. PLEASE JOIN ME AND APPLAUDING
THEIR HARD WORK AND SUCCESS AND I KNOW WE HAVE COACH
FULLERTON MITCHELL. >> WE CALL HIM FULLY CHRIS KANE
AND I KNOW LAMONT BISHOP IS HERE FROM REC AND PARK.
>> I DON'T KNOW WHO'S SPEAKING BUT HAVE AT IT.
>> GOOD AFTERNOON SUPERVISOR WELCOME TO THE ENTIRE BOARD OF
SUPERVISORS. THANK YOU FOR HAVING US
AND THANK YOU FOR RECOGNIZING THIS DYNAMIC TEAM.
I WON'T SPEAK LONG BECAUSE I DEFINITELY WANT TO HAVE COACH
FULTON COME UP AND TALK ABOUT THESE KIDS AND ALSO TALK ABOUT
THESE FAMILIES WHO HAVE SUPPORTED THESE KIDS.
BUT I DO WANT TO SAY OFTEN WHEN WE COME HERE IT IS IMPORTANT
FOR US TO QUANTIFY THE WORK THAT WE DO.
AND I WOULD JUST ASK THAT YOU WOULD JUST PAUSE FOR A MOMENT A
MOMENT AND QUALIFY THE WORK THAT WE DO IN THE FACES OF
THESE YOUNG CHILDREN THAT WE SERVE ALL OVER SAN FRANCISCO.
SO WITHOUT FURTHER ADO, I'D LIKE TO BRING UP COACH
MITCHELL. AND I'D ALSO LIKE TO INVITE ALL
OF THE PARENTS TO COME UP AND CELEBRATE WITH US DURING
THIS TIME. >> PLEASE.
THANK YOU, SIR. THIS IS AN HONOR.
>> WE STARTED THE PROGRAM LIKE YOU SAID IN 2019 AND WE BARELY
HAD ANY KIDS. >> WE STARTED OFF WITH BOYS
AND IT WAS COED. THEN WE WE HAD A LOT OF GIRLS
PLAYING ON OUR TEAM SO WE DECIDED TO CHANGE UP AND MAYBE
SWITCH UP AND ADD SOME GIRLS. AND IN THE BEGINNING IT WAS
LIKE PULLING TEETH TRYING TO GET GIRLS TO COME PLAY.
WE STARTED OFF IN MAYBE 4 OR 5 AND WE WERE LIKE BEGGING KIDS
TO COME PLAY. JUST LIKE, YOU KNOW, THIS YEAR
IN THE LAST SEASON WE HAD TWO WAITING LISTS.
>> SO IT JUST TELLS YOU WHERE WE COME FROM.
FILL OUR GENERAL MANAGER HE HAD A VISION AND HE WANTED TO BRING
SOCCER TO BAYVIEW AND HAVE AFRICAN-AMERICAN KIDS MORE
EXPOSED TO SOCCER BECAUSE THE EXPENSES JUST GOTTEN OUTRAGEOUS
AND WE REALLY YOU KNOW, A LOT OF PARENTS REALLY JUST CANNOT
AFFORD IT. >> SO THIS IS HOW WE STARTED
THIS PROGRAM. THE LAST SEASON THE LAST TWO
SEASONS THESE GIRLS WERE UNDEFEATED.
THIS SEASON THEY WERE FOUR AND TWO BUT THEY WERE PLAYING
UP JUST LIKE YOU MENTIONED. THEY WERE MAINLY MOST OF THEM
ARE FOURTH GRADERS WITH ABOUT THREE FIFTH GRADERS AND ONE
THIRD GRADER. SO WE HAVE NO SIXTH GRADERS
AND THEY WON A SIXTH GRADE DIVISION AND.
>> AND YOU SEE ALL THESE PARENTS ARE HERE.
IF YOU GUYS WERE TO CAME OUT TO THAT CHAMPIONSHIP GAME, YOU
WOULD HAVE THOUGHT THAT WE WERE AT THE WORLD CUP OR SOMETHING.
I MEAN WE HAD PROBABLY ABOUT 200 PEOPLE HERE JUST TO WATCH
THESE GIRLS PLAY. >> AND IT WAS PRETTY AMAZING.
>> I MEAN WITH THAT SAID, IT WAS IT WAS A GREAT SEASON
AND WE LOOK FORWARD TO CONTINUING.
THANK YOU GUYS AND WE APPRECIATE DONNA MY NAME REALLY
IN CLASS AND I WANT TO SAY
ALL RIGHT, DISTRICT FIVE SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD.
COLLEAGUES, IT IS MY HONOR TODAY TO RECOGNIZE ADRIAN
WILLIAMS AND YOU WANT TO COME UP.
>> ADRIAN IS A VISIONARY COMMUNITY LEADER AND FIERCE
ADVOCATE WHOSE LIFE'S WORK HAS TRANSFORMED THE FILLMORE
AND WESTERN. IN ADDITION, INSPIRING
GENERATIONS ACROSS SAN FRANCISCO.
>> FOR NEARLY FIVE DECADES ADRIAN HAS POURED HER HEART
AND HER REMARKABLE ENTREPRENEURIAL EXPERTISE INTO
UPLIFTING YOUTH AND FAMILIES. AS FOUNDER AND DIRECTOR OF THE
VILLAGE PROJECT LAUNCH IN 26, SHE BUILT ONE OF OUR CITY'S
MOST BELOVED AFTERSCHOOL AND SUMMER ENRICHMENT PROGRAMS.
>> THE VILLAGE PROJECT OFFERS A SAFE HAVEN WHERE CHILDREN
LEARN, EXPLORE AND DISCOVER PRIDE IN THEIR HERITAGE
AND CULTURE WHILE EMBRACING THE RICHNESS OF CULTURES BEYOND
THEIR OWN. >> ADRIAN'S LEADERSHIP IS
ROOTED IN A LIFETIME OF BREAKING BARRIERS.
SHE WAS THE FIRST AFRICAN-AMERICAN AND THE FIRST
WOMAN TO HOLD MAJOR EXECUTIVE SALES AND MARKETING ROLES AT
COMPANIES LIKE AMERICAN CAN PARK DAVIS MARIAN LABORATORY
AND ROYAL BUSINESS MACHINES. >> BEFORE THAT SHE HELPED
DESEGREGATE NORTHEAST STATE UNIVERSITY IN MONROE, LOUISIANA
A COURAGEOUS ACT THAT FORESHADOWED TO IT A CAREER
DEFINED BY RESILIENCE AND CHANGE MAKING A NATIONAL
ACHIEVEMENT SCHOLAR WITH 17 ACADEMIC SCHOLARSHIPS AND A
NORTHWESTERN UNIVERSITY ALUM. ADRIAN HAS EXCELLED IN EVERY
ENDEAVOR SHE HAS TAKEN ON. >> HER ENTREPRENEURIAL SPIRIT
IS JUST AS EXTRAORDINARY FROM OWNING AN INTERIOR DESIGN
AND FURNITURE DEALERSHIP IN CHICAGO TO RUNNING A COPIER
SALES AND REPAIR COMPANY IN SAN FRANCISCO TO LEADING HER OWN
CATERING BUSINESS AND CONSULTING FOR XEROX.
>> ADRIAN HAS ALWAYS MET CHALLENGES WITH VISION
AND DETERMINATION THE SAME QUALITIES SHE NOW POURS INTO
COMMUNITY PROGRAMS THAT SERVE HUNDREDS OF SAN FRANCISCANS.
HER COMMITMENT EXTENDS FAR BEYOND DAILY PROGRAMING.
ADRIAN PRODUCES MANY MAJOR ANNUAL COMMUNITY EVENTS
INCLUDING THE SEVEN DAY CITYWIDE KWANZAA CELEBRATION,
MARDI GRAS SAN FRANCISCO STYLE A SENIOR MOMENT A SENIOR PROM
AS WELL AS GRILLING IN THE MO. A FAMILY BARBECUE AND BLUES
CONCERT. >> THESE COMMUNITY EVENTS
SERVED TO STRENGTHEN CULTURAL CONNECTION AND JOY THROUGHOUT
OUR NEIGHBORHOODS AND THROUGHOUT THE WESTERN DISH
AND WELLNESS COALITION WHICH SHE CO-FOUNDED.
SHE HAS CREATED VITAL SPACES TO ADDRESS TRAUMA, PROMOTE HEALING
AND EMPOWER FAMILIES IMPACTED BY COMMUNITY VIOLENCE.
>> AT THE ONSET OF THE COVID 19 PANDEMIC SHE LAUNCHED A FOOD
PANTRY THAT CONTINUES TO DELIVER GROCERIES TO MORE THAN
400 SENIORS AND LOW INCOME RESIDENTS EVERY MONTH.
SERVING AS A REFLECTION OF HER UNWAVERING LOVE FOR THIS
COMMUNITY, ADRIAN'S STORY IS WEAVED TOGETHER BY COURAGE
AND SERVICE. SHE CONTINUES NURTURING THE
NEXT GENERATION WITH THE SAME CARE AND PASSION THAT DEFINES
HER LEADERSHIP. ADRIAN, THANK YOU FOR YOUR
TIRELESS ADVOCACY AND YOUR UNSHAKABLE COMMITMENT TO OUR
FAMILIES AND OUR FUTURE. YOUR EFFORTS HAVE STRENGTHENED
NOT ONLY THE FABRIC OF THE FILLMORE AND WESTERN TRADITION
BUT THE FABRIC OF SAN FRANCISCO AS A WHOLE.
>> THANK YOU. >> THANK YOU, SIR.
I AM HONORED TO BE BACK IN THIS CHAMBER.
IT'S BEEN A WHILE. I APPRECIATE YOU, SIR, FOR
RECOGNIZING THE WORK THAT I'VE DONE IN THE FILLMORE.
>> I AM JUST EXCITED TO BE HERE AND THANK YOU VERY MUCH FOR
ACKNOWLEDGING ALL THE WORK THAT I'VE DONE.
I'M TRYING TO RETIRE BUT IT JUST SEEMS LIKE I COULD NEVER
GET OUT OF HERE. THERE'S ALWAYS SOMETHING ELSE
TO DO. SO I AM HONORED TO BE IN THIS
CHAMBER RECEIVING THIS ACCOMMODATION.
>> THANK YOU SIR, VERY MUCH. MAY I
HAVE YOUR FIRST THAT. >> OH, OKAY.
>> DISTRICT SIX SUPERVISOR DORSEY THANK YOU, PRESIDENT
RANDLEMAN. >> COLLEAGUES ON THE OCCASION
OF HIS WELL-DESERVED RETIREMENT FROM CITY SERVICE TODAY I AM
PLEASED TO HONOR BOB BECK, THE DIRECTOR OF THE TREASURE ISLAND
DEVELOPMENT AUTHORITY OR TITLE. >> BOB, CAN YOU APPROACH THE
LECTERN? >> BOB?
BOB IS A CITY GOVERNMENT VETERAN WHO HAS SERVED THE
PEOPLE OF THE CITY AND COUNTY OF SAN FRANCISCO HONORABLY
AND WELL FOR MORE THAN 30 YEARS.
HE HAS LENT HIS LEADERSHIP SKILLS AND EXPERTISE TO ROLES
ACROSS MANY CITY DEPARTMENTS MAKING MAJOR CONTRIBUTIONS TO
PROJECTS THAT PROMISE TO BE AMONG SAN FRANCISCO'S MOST
ENDURING AND ICONIC CITY CIVIC ASSETS.
>> EARLY IN BOB CITY CAREER HE WORKED ON IMPORTANT PROJECTS
LIKE THE MARKET STREET RECONSTRUCTION PROJECT IN 1988
POST LOMA PRIETA EARTHQUAKE FIRE STATION INSPECTIONS
AND THE SEISMIC RETROFITS OF THE BILL GRAHAM CIVIC
AUDITORIUM AND WAR MEMORIAL OPERA HOUSE.
>> HE THEN LED A SERIES OF POSITIONS AT OUR PUBLIC
UTILITIES COMMISSION AND DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC WORKS
. HE WORKED AS A DESIGN ENGINEER,
ACTING DEPUTY DIRECTOR FOR OPERATIONS, ASSISTANT TO THE
DIRECTOR AND DEPUTY DIRECTOR FOR ENGINEERING, CITY ENGINEER
AND EVEN ACTING DIRECTOR OF PUBLIC WORKS.
WHEN THE LATE MAYOR ED LEE LEFT THAT ROLE TO SERVE AS CITY
ADMINISTRATOR, BOB LATER JOINED TRANSBAY AT THE TRANSBAY JOINT
POWERS AUTHORITY AS A SENIOR PROGRAM MANAGER HELPING TO LEAD
THE DESIGN, PLANNING AND EARLY CONSTRUCTION PHASES OF THE
TRANSBAY TRANSIT CENTER. IN 2012 BOB WOULD TAKE ON A NEW
CHALLENGE AS DIRECTOR OF TITER WITH THE GOAL OF IMPLEMENTING A
ONCE IN A GENERATION REDEVELOPMENT PROJECT.
HE FINALIZED THE CONVEYANCE AGREEMENT WITH THE NAVY AND THE
TRUST EXCHANGE AGREEMENT WITH THE STATE LANDS COMMISSION.
SO THE VISION OF A THRIVING INCLUSIVE RESIDENTIAL
NEIGHBORHOOD COULD FINALLY TAKE OFF.
UNDER HIS LEADERSHIP TITLE HAS MADE AN INCREDIBLE PROGRESS TO
DELIVER ON MAJOR TRANSPORTATION AND UTILITY INFRASTRUCTURE
INCLUDING NEW WATER STORAGE RESERVOIRS, A NEW ELECTRICAL
SWITCHYARD, A NEW FERRY TERMINAL, A U.S. FUNDED
WASTEWATER TREATMENT FACILITY AND WORLD CLASS PARKS.
HOUSING PRODUCTION IS ALSO WELL UNDERWAY WITH 974 NEW
RESIDENTIAL UNITS INCLUDING 297 AFFORDABLE UNITS ALREADY
CONSTRUCTED. BUT BOB DOES MORE THAN JUST
DELIVER ON PROJECTS AND CHECK THE BOXES WE ASK HIM TO CHECK.
HE IS AN ACTIVE AND ENGAGED PART OF THE TREASURE ISLAND
COMMUNITY WELL KNOWN AND WIDELY APPRECIATED FOR HIS
ACCESSIBILITY. BOB WORK SIDE BY SIDE WITH ONE
TREASURE ISLAND AND OTHER COMMUNITY PARTNERS TO
UNDERSTAND THE NEEDS OF RESIDENTS AND WHEN RESIDENTS
HAVE NEEDS ON THE ISLAND BOB RUSHES IN TO FILL THEM.
HE BELIEVES AS I DO IN THE POWER OF WHAT GOOD GOVERNMENT
CAN ACCOMPLISH TO IMPROVE PEOPLE'S LIVES, TO EXPAND
OPPORTUNITIES AND ACCESS AND TO FULFILL THE PROMISE OF
INCLUSIVE URBANISM FOR THE 21ST CENTURY.
BOB WILL BE FONDLY MISSED AS A COLLEAGUE, THOUGHT PARTNER
AND VISIONARY LEADER WHO CARES DEEPLY ABOUT SAN FRANCISCANS
NOT MERELY THOSE WHO RESIDE HERE TODAY BUT FOR GENERATIONS
OF SAN FRANCISCANS TO COME. BOB I AM DEEPLY GRATEFUL FOR
YOUR TRUSTED LEADERSHIP AND WISE COUNSEL.
YOU HAVE LEFT AN ENVIABLE AND INDELIBLE LEGACY ON OUR
CITY IN DISTRICT SIX AND ELSEWHERE AND ESPECIALLY
FOR AN EMERGING NEIGHBORHOOD I KNOW YOU AND I BOTH LOVE
IN TREASURE ISLAND AND YERBA BUENA ISLAND.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR SERVICE AND CONGRATULATIONS ON YOUR
WELL-EARNED RETIREMENT. >> BUT NOW WE DO HAVE BOB'S
FAMILY AND MANY OF HIS COLLEAGUES FROM TODAY AND THE
CITY ADMINISTRATORS OFFICE WITH US TODAY.
AND I KNOW I'VE ASKED BOB TO COME UP TO THE LECTERN, BUT I
DO WANT TO ASK FIRST IF I COULD INVITE DEPUTY CITY
ADMINISTRATOR JENNIFER JOHNSTON TO SAY A FEW WORDS AND THEN
WE'LL HEAR FROM BOB AND THEN SOMEBODY ELSE SUPERVISOR WALT
AND ALSO A SUPERVISOR. >> OKAY, I'LL DEFER TO THE
SUPERVISOR WHILE SO I'M I'M TRYING TO FIGURE OUT WHAT I CAN
SAY ABOUT YOU THAT'S APPROPRIATE IN THE CHAMBERS.
>> BUT I WILL SAY YOU'VE HAD AN INSURMOUNTABLE TASK IN MAKING
THE PROJECT AT TREASURE ISLAND A REALITY.
BUT LONG BEFORE MY ELECTION TO THE BOARD OF EDUCATION
AND EVENTUALLY TO THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS, I KNOW THAT YOU
WOULD PROBABLY WAKE UP ABOUT 430 IN THE MORNING AND BE ON
THE BASKETBALL COURT BY 6 A.M. AND YOU DID THAT FOR YEARS
AND THEN GO AND DEAL WITH THE POLITICS OF SAN FRANCISCO
AND WITH THE COMMUNITY THAT NEEDED TO SEE PROMISES
FULFILLED. AND EVEN THOUGH YOU ARE A YEAR
ON THE BASKETBALL COURT, YOU'RE A PUBLIC SERVANT THAT CARES
ABOUT THE COMMUNITY YOU WORK IN.
AND I JUST WANT TO THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR YOUR SERVICE AND FOR
THE WAY THAT YOU DO YOUR JOB BECAUSE IT'S IMPORTANT
AND PEOPLE RECOGNIZE IT AND CAN SEE IT THAT YOU'RE GENUINE
ABOUT ACHIEVING SUCCESS FOR THE COMMUNITY THAT YOU SERVE.
SO THANK YOU FOR YOUR SERVICE AND FOR BEING ALL AROUND THE
PERSON. >> NOW JENNIFER JOHNSON, THANK
YOU SO MUCH. THANK YOU SUPERVISORS FOR
RECOGNIZE BOB ON THIS ON THIS DAY BEFORE HIS RETIREMENT.
YOU ARE BOTH VERY TOUGH ACTS TO FOLLOW, I WILL SAY SO I HAVE TO
DELETE A LOT OF MY TALKING POINTS BUT I AM HERE ON BEHALF
OF CARMEN CHU WHO UNFORTUNATELY COULD NOT BE HERE AND I WILL.
I KNOW I'M A POOR SUBSTITUTE BUT I WILL DO MY BEST
AND YOU'VE MENTIONED A LOT OF HIS ACCOMPLISHMENTS AND HIS
DEEP PASSION AND DEDICATION TO SERVING THE PUBLIC TRULY
COMMUNITY FOCUSED TO SERVING THE PUBLIC.
I'M ALSO HONORED TO BE ABLE TO RECOGNIZE SUCH AN EXCEPTIONAL
PUBLIC LEADER. I'VE WORKED FOR THE CITY FOR
OVER 22 YEARS AND I I'M REALLY HARD PRESSED TO THINK OF
ANYBODY WHO'S AS COMMITTED AND HARD WORKING AND DEDICATED
AND REALLY, REALLY FOCUSED ON THE COMMUNITY.
SO REALLY QUITE REMARKABLE AND YOU KNOW, BOB, HIS FOCUS
OVER THE LAST 30 PLUS YEARS HAS BEEN FOCUSED ON, YOU KNOW,
SUPERVISOR DORSEY. YOU IDENTIFIED A NUMBER OF HIS
PROJECTS VERY FOCUSED ON INFRASTRUCTURE REALLY THE
FOUNDATIONS OF THE CITY AND TO IMPROVE THE LIVES OF PEOPLE WHO
LIVE IN THE CITY AND YOU COME AND VISIT THE CITY AND I HAVE
TO SAY THAT OVER THE LAST 12 YEARS AT TAI CHI HE REALLY HAS
PROFOUNDLY CHANGED THE ISLAND IN VERY REMARKABLE WAYS.
YOU KNOW THE STATE THAT IT WAS WHEN HE GOT THERE VERSUS NOW.
I MEAN HE REALLY HAS REALLY HELPED SHAPE INTO AN INCREDIBLE
ON ITS SUCCESSFUL PATH TO A NEW CITY NEIGHBORHOOD THAT'S REALLY
FOCUSED ON THE COMMUNITY. >> SO I WILL ALSO SAY THAT BOB
IS INCREDIBLY UNFLAPPABLE, UNWAVERING KING AND UNFAZED BY
CHALLENGES AND THERE HAVE BEEN A MYRIAD OF CHALLENGES ON
TREASURE ISLAND IN WORKING WITH THE COUNTLESS CHALLENGES
OBSTACLES, STAKEHOLDERS AND PARTNERS ON THE ISLAND.
IT REALLY IS NO EXAGGERATION TO SAY THAT BOB HAS OVERSEEN THE
MANAGEMENT PLANNING, OWNERSHIP PERMITTING, CONSTRUCTION,
ENTITLEMENT OR DISPOSITION OF LAND ASSETS INFRASTRUCTURE
AND ALSO FOCUSING ON THE COMMUNITY LIFE.
I KNOW THAT WE JUST HAD A CONVERSATION A FEW WEEKS AGO
ABOUT MAKING SURE THAT THERE'S AN ADEQUATE GROCERY STORE ON
THE ISLAND AND REALLY KIND OF HAVING THAT FULL KIND OF
CONCEPT OF LIFE FOR PEOPLE ON THE ISLAND.
SO WITH THAT I SAY CONGRATULATIONS TO BOB IN YOUR
RETIREMENT. YOU ABSOLUTELY DESERVE IT
DOESN'T MEAN I WILL NOT BE CALLING YOU INCESSANTLY AND I
APOLOGIZE TO YOUR POOR WIFE IN ADVANCE BUT I REALLY DON'T
KNOW HOW WE'RE GOING TO MOVE ON WITHOUT YOU AND ALL OF YOUR
ENCYCLOPEDIC KNOWLEDGE OF THE OF THE AGENCY AND THE HISTORY
AND I WILL BE CALLING YOU SO I APPRECIATE IT IN ADVANCE BUT I
WILL ALSO REALLY MISS YOU AS A COLLEAGUE AND A FRIEND AND AS A
PARTNER AND AND THAT'S IT. JUST THANK YOU.
THANK YOU FOR EVERYTHING YOU'VE DONE.
>> THANK THANK YOU DIRECTOR BACK WELL I JUST WANT TO SAY A
FEW WORDS OF THANKS TO JENNIFER'S SUPERVISOR TOWARDS
THE SUPERVISOR WALTON WANTED TO TO ACKNOWLEDGE TITUS STAFF WE
HAVE WE HAVE A TOTAL OF 13 STAFF AND THEY DO AMAZING WORK
AND AND ARE ENORMOUSLY PRODUCTIVE IN TRYING TO MOVE
THE PROGRAMS OF THE ISLAND FORWARD, MOVE THE OBJECTIVES OF
THE CITY FORWARD. I DID START MY CAREER AT PUBLIC
WORKS AND I JUST WANTED TO ACKNOWLEDGE THE HISTORY OF
PUBLIC WORKS AND THE STAFF OF PUBLIC WORKS.
THE THE THAT AGENCY IS SO CONNECTED TO THE POPULATION OF
THE CITY IN SO MANY WAYS AND IT STARTING THERE SHAPED MY MY
CAREER AND MY OUTLOOK WITH EVERYTHING THAT I'VE DONE SINCE
ALSO ON TREASURE ISLAND WE HAVE A FANTASTIC PARTNER IN ONE
TREASURE ISLAND FOR THOSE THAT AREN'T FAMILIAR, IT'S A
COMMUNITY BASED ORGANIZATION THAT'S BEEN PART OF THE
DEVELOPMENT PROGRAM ON TREASURE ISLAND SINCE ITS INCEPTION
AND THEY DO TREMENDOUS WORK FOR THE RESIDENTS OF THE ISLAND AS
WELL AS OUR DEVELOPMENT PARTNER IN TREASURE ISLAND COMMUNITY
DEVELOPMENT. YOU KNOW IT'S IT'S JUST
FANTASTIC TO BE PART OF A TEAM WITH SO MANY PEOPLE THAT ARE SO
FOCUSED ON DOING GOOD THINGS AND AGAIN IT'S IT'S BEEN A
TREMENDOUS HONOR AND A PRIVILEGE TO WORK FOR THE CITY
AND AND THANK YOU FOR THE RECOGNITION TODAY.
>> LET'S BRING OUR BACK AND I, I WOULD BE REMISS IF I DIDN'T
ALSO RECOGNIZE MY FAMILY, MY WIFE, HER PARENTS THAT ARE HERE
TODAY AND MY MY BROTHERS AND MY SISTER ALSO CAME OUT HERE
TODAY. SO I WANT TO MAKE SURE I
RECOGNIZE THEM TOO
AND I THREE ALL RIGHT. >> YOU GOT ONE MORE LISA LOU,
YOU MAY RISE. COLLEAGUES, FOR THE NEXT
SEVERAL MINUTES WE'RE GOING TO BE RESPONSIBLE FOR MAINTAINING
OUR OWN QUORUM. >> SO IF YOU SEE THAT WE'VE
GONE DOWN TO 7 TO 6, IMAGINE THAT THERE IS SOMEONE IN THE
DOORWAY KEEPING US BECAUSE THAT WOULD BE LISA IT'S BITTERSWEET
. TODAY IS THE LAST BOARD MEETING
FOR ONE OF OUR INCREDIBLY VALUABLE AND BELOVED
LEGISLATIVE CLERKS LISA LOU WHO IS ALSO OUR SERGEANT AT ARMS
TODAY SHE IS RETIRING AT THE END OF THE MONTH.
>> SHE STARTED WITH THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS ALMOST 11 YEARS
AGO STARTING IN THE OPERATIONS DIVISION IN 2015 AND SHE WAS
PROMOTED TO THE LEGISLATIVE DIVISION IN 2016.
EVERY WEEK SHE INTAKES ALL THE LEGISLATION WE INTRODUCE READS
IT MAKES EDITS AND ENSURES THAT THEY'RE READY TO MOVE FORWARD.
SHE'S COORDINATED OUR APPEALS, ANSWERED OUR QUESTIONS AND DONE
IT ALL WITH PROFESSIONALISM AND GRACE.
IF YOU'VE ENGAGED WITH LISA ON LEGISLATIVE MATTERS, YOU KNOW
SHE'S ONE OF THE MOST PATIENT CLERKS.
SHE TAKES HER TIME TO GUIDE AND HELP US UNDERSTAND THE
REASONING BEHIND THE RULES AND HOW TO NAVIGATE THE PROCESS
. AND SO WE WANTED TO TAKE THIS
MOMENT TO ACKNOWLEDGE LISA AND HER EXCEPTIONAL PUBLIC
SERVICE TO THE CITY AND COUNTY OF SAN FRANCISCO.
WE WISH YOU ALL THE BEST IN YOUR FUTURE ADVENTURES
AND THANK YOU FOR YOUR DEDICATION AND HARD WORK.
THE OFFICE OF THE CLERK OF THE BOARD WILL HAVE A BIG HOLE TO
FILL WITH YOUR ABSENCE BUT YOUR RETIREMENT IS WELL-DESERVED SO
CONGRATULATIONS AND ALL THE VERY BEST.
>> LISA AND YOU MAY NOT. YOU ARE NOT ALLOWED TO SPEAK
YET BECAUSE SUPERVISOR CHAN IS IN THE QUEUE.
>> THANK YOU PRESIDENT AMONG JUST ONE.
THANK YOU FOR ALL THE GOOD WORK THAT YOU HAVE DONE AND YOU KNOW
I THINK WHEN WE SUBMIT YOU KNOW RESOLUTION FOR ADOPTION WITH
OUR REFERENCE TO COMMITTEE WE'RE ALWAYS TRYING TO FIGURE
OUT IF YOU'RE GOING TO SAY IS THIS CONTROVERSIAL OR NOT
AND CAN WE JUST GET THROUGH GET PASSED BY YOU BUT NOTHING GET
PASSED BY YOU, LISA REIGN OF TERROR NOT CONTROVERSIAL, YOU
KNOW, BUT ALSO JUST ATTENTION TO DETAIL.
BUT I ALSO JUST WANT TO SAY HOW KIND YOU ALWAYS BEEN AND HOW
GENTLE YOU REALLY ALWAYS ARE EVEN AND WITH ALL EYES
AND DEFINITELY MYSELF INCLUDED JUST EVEN DURING, YOU KNOW,
LONG NIGHTS AND MAKING SURE THAT WE'RE TAKING CARE OF THAT
WE HAVE WATER AND SO MANY THINGS THAT WE DO ON THIS FLOOR
AND AT DIFFERENT TIMES IT'S JUST NOT A SMALL TASK TO HANDLE
BETWEEN US AND INTENSE CONVERSATIONS OR YOU KNOW,
KEEPING THE MEETINGS GOING AND WHILE WITH THE GENERAL
PUBLIC AND US COMING IN AND NOW IN THE BACK AS WELL JUST JUST
SO MUCH OF PEOPLE DON'T SEE AND DON'T APPRECIATE WHEN I SAY
PEOPLE I DON'T MEAN JUST JUST GENERAL PUBLIC I MEAN OURSELVES
INCLUDED AT TIMES AND WHO REALLY SEE YOU THERE
AND SOMETIMES WE WOULD JUST GO THROUGH THE DOOR AND DIDN'T
EVEN THINK YOU KNOW, TO TURN BACK AND COUNT IF WE HAVE A
QUORUM ON THE FLOOR. BUT YOU ALWAYS MAKE SURE THAT
WE DO ALL WHICH IS TO SAY IS WHILE SEEMINGLY NO ONE NO THE
GENERAL PUBLIC MAY NOT KNOW YOUR JOB DESCRIPTION BUT THEY
SHOULD ALL KNOW TODAY THAT YOU WILL REALLY HELP KEEP SO MUCH
OF IT RUNNING. >> THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR YOUR
SERVICE FORMER PRESIDENT WALTON THANK YOU SO MUCH PRESIDENT
MADAM AND AS A FORMER PRESIDENT I JUST WANT TO SAY THANK YOU SO
MUCH FOR ALL THE WORK THAT YOU DO TO MAKE SURE THAT WE
ACTUALLY HAVE FUNCTIONAL MEETINGS.
>> A LOT OF THINGS GO INTO HANDLING THE BUSINESS OF THIS
BOARD OF SUPERVISORS AND YOU HAVE BEEN AN INTEGRAL PART OF
MAKING SURE THAT THAT HAS HAPPENED.
SO THANK YOU FOR THE SUPPORT YOU HAVE GIVEN MY TEAM OVER THE
YEARS AND REALLY WANT TO CONGRATULATE YOU ON GETTING TO
YOUR RETIREMENT AND JUST SAY THANK YOU SO MUCH.
>> SUPERVISOR CHEN I THANK YOU FOR PRESENT AS A NEW MEMBER OF
THE BOARD I JUST WANT TO ALSO EXPRESS MY GRATITUDE TO ALL THE
SUPPORT FROM YOU TO MY TEAM AND TO MY OFFICE AND THANK YOU
AND I WISH YOU A WONDERFUL RETIREMENT AND ALSO, YOU KNOW,
ENJOY THE HOLIDAY. >> YOU LISA LIU THE FLOOR IS
YOURS. >> OH MY GOSH.
YOU GUYS I'M GOING TO KEEP IT SHORT AND SWEET BOY PRESIDENT
AND WOMAN MEMBERS OF THE BOARD MADAM CLERK ANGELA CAVIEZEL,
DEPUTY CLERK ELISA SUGIMURA AND COLLEAGUES AT THE CLERK OF
THE BOARD THANK YOU FOR THIS COMMENDATION.
I'M VERY HONORED TO HAVE SERVED THE BOARD AND ITS MEMBERS.
>> I'M HONORED TO HAVE WORKED WITH SUCH A GREAT TEAM OF
COLLEAGUES IN OUR OFFICE AND I AM SO GRATEFUL AND PROUD TO
HAVE COMPLETED THIS CHAPTER OF MY LIFE.
BUT THIS CITY AND COUNTY OF SAN FRANCISCO THANK YOU FOR THIS
HONOR. >> IT'S BEEN A PLEASURE.
ALL RIGHT, LISA, COME ON INTO THE WELL.
>> AND MADAM CLERK, DID YOU WANT TO BRING MORE OF YOUR TEAM
IN HERE? YES.
THOSE WHO ARE HERE IN THE CHAMBER WHO ARE IN THE OFFICE
OF THE CLERK OF THE BOARD PLEASE TAKE A PHOTOGRAPH WITH
LISA LOU
AND YES, ALL SURE. ANY SURPRISE ON A DAY LIKE
THAT? I JUST YOU WANT ONE, TWO,
THREE. ONE MORE BRIEF.
YOU THAT OH 21 510 000 ALL RIGHT, MADAM CLERK, CAN YOU
CALL OUR £0.03 SPECIAL ORDER YES.
>> ITEMS THROUGH 33 COMPRISE THE SPECIAL ORDER AT 3 P.M..
ITEM 30 IS THE PUBLIC HEARING OF PERSONS INTERESTED IN THE
DECISION OF PUBLIC WORKS DATED NOVEMBER 7TH 2025 TO APPROVE A
TENTATIVE PARCEL MAP FOR A THREE LOT VERTICAL SUBDIVISION
FIVE RESIDENTIAL AND TEN COMMERCIAL MIXED USE
CONDOMINIUM PROJECT AT 3333 MISSION STREET AND 190 CALL
STREET. ITEM 31 IS THE MOTION TO
APPROVE THE PUBLIC WORKS DECISION TO APPROVE THE
TENTATIVE PARCEL MAP. ITEM 33 IS THE ITEM 31 IS THE
MOTION THAT APPROVES THE PUBLIC WORKS DECISION.
ITEM 32 IS THE MOTION TO CONDITIONALLY DISAPPROVE THE
DECISION AND ITEM 33 IS THE MOTION TO DIRECT THE
PREPARATION OF FINDINGS. >> THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK.
SO AS OUR CLERK INDICATED WE HAVE AN APPEAL ON THE TENTATIVE
PARTIAL MAP APPROVAL FOR THE MIXED USE CONDOMINIUM PROJECT
AT 3333 MISSION STREET AND 190 COLORADO STREET COLADA STREET
AND SUPERVISOR FIELDER DO YOU HAVE ANY REMARKS?
>> THANKS, PRESIDENT GENTLEMEN, COLLEAGUES, THE PARTIES HAVE
ALL AGREED TO A CONTINUANCE ON THIS MATTER.
I AM NOW MAKING A MOTION TO CONTINUE THIS HEARING
AND ASSOCIATED MOTIONS TO THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS MEETING ON
FEBRUARY 3RD, 2026. >> RIGHT.
SO THERE'S A MOTION TO CONTINUE THIS THESE ITEMS TO FEBRUARY
3RD, 2026 MADE BY SUPERVISOR FIELD OR SECONDED BY SUPERVISOR
CHEN. BEFORE WE ACT ON THAT MOTION WE
HAVE TO TAKE A PUBLIC COMMENT ON THE CONTINUANCES.
THIS IS NOT GENERAL PUBLIC COMMENT.
THIS IS JUST THE MOTION TO CONTINUE THIS HEARING.
>> MADAM CLERK, CAN YOU PLEASE CALL FOR THAT RIGHT IF YOU'RE
HERE IN THE CHAMBER AND YOU WERE EXPECTING TO SPEAK ON 3333
MISSION STREET AND 190 COLERIDGE STREET APPEAL, PLEASE
COME FORWARD. ALL RIGHT.
SEEING NO ONE MR. PRESIDENT. >> ALL RIGHT.
PUBLIC COMMENT ON THE CONTINUANCE.
THIS IS CLOSED. NOPE.
NOPE, IT'S NOT. COME ON UP.
>> GOOD AFTERNOON, BORDER SUPERVISORS.
MY NAME IS CONNIE SHEA AND I'M THE HOUSING DEVELOPMENT PROJECT
MANAGER AT BERNAL HEIGHTS NEIGHBORHOOD CENTER AND I'M
ALSO A MEMBER OF THE 3333 MISSION DEVELOPMENT PROJECT.
I AM HERE TO ADVOCATE ON BEHALF OF THE ENTIRE DEVELOPMENT TEAM
TO KEEP THE CURRENT APPEAL HEARING DATE AS OF FEBRUARY
THIRD, 2026. >> AS YOU KNOW BUILDING
AFFORDABLE HOUSING IS A LENGTHY AND EXPENSIVE PROJECT EVERY DAY
THAT THE PROJECT IS DELAYED, ADDITIONAL FEES ARE INCURRED
AND SECURING ADEQUATE FUNDING BECOMES INCREASINGLY
CHALLENGING. WE REQUEST THAT THE FEBRUARY
3RD HEARING DATE BE MAINTAINED SO THAT WE PREVENT FURTHER
DELAYS AND FISCAL ROBUX WE ARE IN THE PROCESS OF APPLYING FOR
AFFORDABLE HOUSING A SUSTAINABLE COMMUNITIES WHICH
IS ALSO KNOWN AS THE A.S. GRANT A CRITICAL FUNDING COMPONENT
REQUIRED TO MOVE THIS 100% AFFORDABLE SENIOR HOUSING
DEVELOPMENT FORWARD. ANY DELAY IN THE APPEAL PROCESS
WOULD HAVE A NEGATIVE IMPACT ON THIS APPLICATION AND SO THANK
YOU FOR YOUR CONSIDERATION AND TIME.
>> THANK YOU JOELLE HI SUPERVISORS MR. DENNIS WILLIAMS
JR. SAN FRANCISCO BASED BLACK MICRO
DEVELOPER EXECUTIVE DIRECTOR THE FILM WORK COMMUNITY
DEVELOPMENT CORPORATION PRINCIPAL OF DC WILLIAMS
DEVELOPMENT COMPANY I THINK WE NEED TO DELAY THIS PROJECT
APPEALS PROCESS BECAUSE WE MUST CONTINUE TO CHALLENGE IN A
DEVELOPMENT MODEL THAT BENEFITS PRIVATE CAPITAL WHILE WEAKENING
EVERY COMMUNITY. SCUSE ME THAT DEPENDS ON
STABILITY, AFFORDABILITY AND LOCAL CONTROL WHEN
DEVELOPMENT MOVES FORWARD WITHOUT WORKERS, TENANTS,
COMMUNITY ORGANIZATIONS AND LOCAL DEVELOPERS AT THE
TABLE, THE OUTCOME IS STILL PREDICTABLE RISING RENTS LONGER
COMMUNITY COMMUTES, CULTURAL DISPLACEMENT AND LESS
DEMOGRAPHIC CONTROL. EVERYONE LOSES EXCEPT
BILLIONAIRES AND DEVELOPERS NOTABLY OUT OF STATE.
>> THANK YOU. >> ALL RIGHT.
LOOKS LIKE THAT IS IT ON THE PUBLIC COMMENT SO PUBLIC
COMMENT AND THE CONTINGENCIES IS CLOSED AND WE HAVE A MOTION
TO CONTINUE THESE HEARINGS OPEN TO THE FEBRUARY 3RD, 2026 BOARD
OF SUPERVISORS MEETING. CAN WE TAKE THAT WITHOUT
OBJECTION? WITHOUT OBJECTION.
THIS APPEAL HEARING AND MOTIONS ARE CONTINUE TO OPEN TO
FEBRUARY 3RD, 2026 >> AND WITH THAT MADAM CLERK, LET'S GO BACK
TO ITEM 21. >> ITEM 21 WAS REFERRED WITHOUT
RECOMMENDATION FROM THE BUDGET AND FINANCE COMMITTEE.
IT'S A RESOLUTION TO APPROVE THE SIXTH AMENDMENT TO THE
AGREEMENT BETWEEN THE CITY AND COUNTY ACTING BY
AND THROUGH THE DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC HEALTH AND THE BAYVIEW
HUNTERS POINT FOUNDATION TO PROVIDE MENTAL HEALTH
AND SUBSTANCE ABUSE SERVICES TO EXTEND THE TERM BY 18 MONTHS
FOR A NEW TOTAL TERM THROUGH JUNE 30TH 2028 AND TO INCREASE
THE AMOUNT BY APPROXIMATELY 7.5 MILLION FOR A NEW TOTAL AMOUNT
OF 25.6 MILLION. >> MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL THE
ROLL ON ITEM 21 SUPERVISOR RANDLEMAN I MANDAL MEN I
SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR I SUPERVISOR SAUTER SUTTER I
SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL EYES SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON I
SUPERVISOR ONE WONG I SUPERVISOR CHAN CHIN MAN EYES
SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN EYES SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY I
SUPERVISOR FIELDER FIELDER I AND SUPERVISOR MARGARET MAHMOOD
EITHER OR 11 EYES WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTION IS
ADOPTED MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM 22 ITEM 22 THIS IS A
RESOLUTION TO AUTHORIZE THE MAYOR THE MAYOR'S CHIEF OF
STAFF. THE CHIEF OF INFRASTRUCTURE.
THE ASSISTANT CHIEF OF INFRASTRUCTURE.
THE CHIEF OF HOUSING AND ECONOMIC DEVELOPMENT.
THE DIRECTOR OF PUBLIC AFFAIRS AND THE POLICY ADVISOR AND THE
GENERAL MANAGER OF THE RECREATION AND PARK DEPARTMENT.
THE DIRECTOR AND STAFF OF REC AND PARK DEPARTMENT A
PARTNERSHIP DIVISION THE REC AND PARK DEPARTMENTS DIRECTOR
OF CAPITAL PLANNING AND INDIA BASIN PROJECT MANAGER AND THE
INDIA BASIN EQUITABLE DEVELOPMENT PLAN MANAGER TO
SOLICIT DONATIONS FOR THE INDIA BASIN WATERFRONT PARK
INITIATIVE FROM NONPROFITS, PRIVATE ORGANIZATIONS, GRANT
MAKERS AND FOUNDATIONS FOR SIX MONTHS EFFECTIVE UPON APPROVAL
OF THIS RESOLUTION NOT WITHSTANDING THE BE HAS TWO
PAYMENT ORDINANCE AND I THINK WE CAN TAKE THIS ITEM SAME
HOUSE, SAME CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTION IS
ADOPTED. >> MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL OUT
23 ITEM 23 THIS IS A RESOLUTION TO AUTHORIZE THE SAN FRANCISCO
POLICE DEPARTMENT TO ENTER INTO A MEMORANDUM OF UNDERSTANDING
AGREEMENT WITH THE UNITED STATES CAPITOL POLICE TO
PROVIDE SUPPLEMENTAL LAW ENFORCEMENT SERVICES BEGINNING
ON JANUARY 1ST, 2026 AND ENDING ON DECEMBER 31ST, 2026.
>> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL. WITHOUT OBJECTION, THE
RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED. MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEM
24. >> ITEM 24 THIS IS A RESOLUTION
TO APPROVE A TOLLING AGREEMENT TO TOLL THE STATUTES OF
LIMITATION FOR SAN MATEO COUNTY DISTRICT ATTORNEY TO BRING
POTENTIAL CLAIMS AGAINST SAN FRANCISCO INTERNATIONAL AIRPORT
FOR CALIFORNIA HEALTH AND SAFETY CODE VIOLATIONS.
>> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION, THE
RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED. MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEMS
25 THROUGH 27 TOGETHER ITEMS 25 THROUGH 27 ARE THREE
RESOLUTIONS THAT APPROVE HISTORICAL PROPERTY CONTRACTS
BETWEEN VARIOUS ENTITIES AND THE HISTORIC PRESERVATION
COMMISSION. ITEM 25 APPROVES A CONTRACT
BETWEEN S.F. S.A. REAL ESTATE HOLDINGS LLC THE OWNERS OF 530
JACKSON STREET AND THE CITY. ITEM 26 APPROVES A CONTRACT
BETWEEN 1035 HOWARD LLC AND THE OWNERS OF 1035 HOWARD STREET
AND THE CITY AND ITEM 27 APPROVES A CONTRACT BETWEEN
DIABLO LLC THE OWNERS OF 331 PENNSYLVANIA AVENUE AND THE
CITY AND TO AUTHORIZE THE PLANNING DIRECTOR AND THE
ASSESSOR RECORDER TO EXECUTE AND RECORD THE HISTORICAL
PROPERTY CONTRACTS FOR EACH ITEM SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL
WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTIONS ARE ADOPTED.
>> MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEM 28 ITEM 28.
>> THIS RESOLUTION ADDS THE COMMEMORATIVE STREET NAME OF
BRYAN CRAIG KELLY WAY ON HOLLISTER AVENUE BETWEEN
JENNINGS STREET AND INGLES STREET TO RECOGNIZE WILL FOR
THE RECOGNITION OF BRYAN CRAIG KELLY AND TO ENSHRINE HIS
LEGACY IN THE BAYVIEW HUNTERS POINT COMMUNITY.
>> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION THE
RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED. MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEM
29 ITEM 29 THIS IS A MOTION TO APPROVE THE MAYOR'S NOMINATION
FOR APPOINTMENT OF MASA HAKIMI TO THE SUCCESSOR AGENCY
COMMISSION TERM ENDING NOVEMBER 3RD, 2028.
>> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL. WITHOUT OBJECTION THE MOTION IS
APPROVED. MADAM CLERK, LET'S GO TO OUR
COMMITTEE REPORTS. >> PLEASE CALL ITEM 34.
YES, I'LL FIRST STATE THAT ITEMS 34 THROUGH 37 WERE
CONSIDERED BY THE LAND USE AND TRANSPORTATION COMMITTEE AT
A REGULAR MEETING ON MONDAY DECEMBER 15TH.
ITEM 34 WAS RECOMMENDED AS A COMMITTEE REPORT.
IT IS AN ORDINANCE TO AMEND THE PLANNING CODE TO INDICATE
DISTRICTS WHERE REPRODUCTIVE HEALTH CLINICS ARE PRINCIPALLY
PERMITTED AND TO MAKE OTHER CONFORMING CHANGES TO THE
PLANNING CODE AND ZONING CONTROL TABLES AS REQUIRED BY
PROPOSITION OH PASSED BY THE VOTERS NOVEMBER 2024 AND TO
AFFIRM THIS EQUAL DETERMINATION AND TO MAKE THE APPROPRIATE
FINDINGS. >> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL
WITHOUT OBJECTION THE ORDINANCES PASSED ON FIRST
READING ITEM 35 WAS NOT FORWARDED TO THE BOARD SO
PLEASE CALL ITEM 36. >> ITEM 36 THIS ITEM WAS
RECOMMENDED AS A COMMITTEE REPORT.
IT IS AN ORDINANCE TO AMEND THE PLANNING CODE TO REQUIRE TENANT
PROTECTIONS RELATED TO RESIDENTIAL DEMOLITIONS
AND RENOVATIONS AND TO AFFIRM THE SECRET DETERMINATION AND TO
MAKE THE APPROPRIATE FINDINGS. >> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL.
WITHOUT OBJECTION THE ORDINANCE IS PASSED ON FIRST READING
MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM 37.
>> ITEM 37 THIS ITEM WAS RECOMMENDED AS AMENDED BEARING
A NEW TITLE. IT NOW READS RESOLUTION
IMPOSING INTERIM ZONING CONTROLS FOR 18 MONTHS TO
REQUIRE A CONDITIONAL USE AUTHORIZATION AND SPECIFIED
FINDINGS FOR PROPOSED LABORATORY USES THAT CONTAIN
DEVELOPMENT AND OR ENGINEERING LABORATORIES THAT OPERATE
OUTDOORS AND OR OUTSIDE OF AN ENCLOSED STRUCTURE IN THE PDR
DASH 1-G THE PRODUCTION, DISTRIBUTION AND REPAIR
DISTRICT TO URGE THE PLANNING DEPARTMENT TO INPUT FROM THE
OFFICE OF ECONOMIC AND WORKFORCE DEVELOPMENT TO
STUDY WHETHER ADDITIONAL CONTROL IS WOULD ENSURE THAT
LABORATORY USES ARE CONSISTENT WITH THE CITY'S GOALS FOR PDR
SPACE TO AFFIRM THE SECOND DETERMINATION AND TO MAKE THE
APPROPRIATE FINDINGS. >> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL
WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTIONS ADOPTED.
>> MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEM 38 I WILL FIRST SAY ITEMS
38 AND 39 WERE CONSIDERED BY THE RULES COMMITTEE AT A
REGULAR MEETING ON AT C ON 1215 AND WERE RECOMMENDED AS AMENDED
BEARING A NEW TITLE ITEM 13 ITEM 38 WAS RECOMMENDED BARRING
A NEW TITLE. ADDING THE APPOINTEES NAMES TO
THE TITLES IT NOW READS MOTION APPOINTING JOSE EDIMILSON TO
THE ASSESSMENT APPEALS BOARD NUMBER TWO TERM ENDING
SEPTEMBER SIX, 2027 AND WE CAN TAKE THAT SAME HOUSE SAME CALL
WITHOUT OBJECTION THE MOTION IS APPROVED.
MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEM 29 AND 39.
>> ITEM 39 IS A MOTION TO APPOINT SHARON WISE SOME LEE
AND CYNTHIA ALVAREZ TO THE HOUSING AUTHORITY OF THE CITY
AND COUNTY OF SAN FRANCISCO BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS.
TERMS TO BE DETERMINED. >> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL
WITHOUT OBJECTION AND THE MOTION IS APPROVED.
>> AND MADAM CLERK, LET'S GO TO A ROLL CALL FOR INTRODUCTIONS.
>> YES, MR. PRESIDENT, YOU ARE FIRST UP TO INTRODUCE NEW
BUSINESS. >> ALL RIGHT.
THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK. I'M ASKING THAT WE ADJOURN
TODAY'S MEETING IN MEMORY OF DANIEL CHESHIRE WHO PASSED AWAY
ON OCTOBER 31ST AT THE AGE OF 83.
DANIEL WAS BORN ON JUNE 10TH, 1942 IN BROOKLYN, NEW YORK,
RAISED IN CROWN HEIGHTS IN AN ORTHODOX HOUSEHOLD
AND ATTENDING THE YESHIVA SCHOOLS THROUGH HIGH SCHOOL,
DANIEL GREW UP DEEPLY IMMERSED IN JEWISH TRADITION
AND LITURGY. AFTER GRADUATING FROM YESHIVA
UNIVERSITY WITH A BACHELOR'S IN AMERICAN HISTORY AND EARNING
A MASTER'S IN POLITICAL SCIENCE AT NYU, HE MOVED TO SAN
FRANCISCO IN THE 1970S TO PURSUE A MASTER OF PUBLIC
HEALTH AT UC BERKELEY. >> UPON ARRIVING IN SAN
FRANCISCO, HOWEVER, HE DISCOVERED THAT AS A GAY
ORTHODOX JEW THERE WAS NO PLACE OF WORSHIP WHERE HE COULD BE
OPEN ABOUT BOTH ASPECTS OF HIS IDENTITY DESPITE REJECTION
AND RESISTANCE FROM THE ORGANIZED JEWISH COMMUNITY.
HE AND TWO OTHERS DECIDED TO RUN AN AD IN SAN FRANCISCO TO
GAY NEWSPAPERS. THE BAY AREA REPORTER AND THE
SENTINEL INVITING GAY AND LESBIAN JEWS TO GATHER
AND PRAY ON A FRIDAY NIGHT IN THE BORROWED BASEMENT OF
GLIDE MEMORIAL CHURCH. 30 PEOPLE ARRIVED FOR THAT
FIRST SHABBAT SERVICE AND CONGREGATION SHA ZAHAV WAS
BORN. OVER THE LAST NEAR HALF CENTURY
SHA ZAHAV HAS GROWN TO AROUND 350 MEMBERS AS THE CITY'S FIRST
GAY SYNAGOGUE. AS A HIGH WAS AT THE FOREFRONT
OF SAN FRANCISCO'S GAY RIGHTS MOVEMENT AND DANIEL TOOK HIS
ROLE AS A COMMUNITY LEADER SERIOUSLY.
SHORTLY AFTER ITS FOUNDING HE MODERATED A DEBATE AT SHA ZAHAV
BETWEEN HARVEY MILK AND RICK STOKES BOTH RUNNING TO BECOME
SAN FRANCISCO'S FIRST OPENLY GAY SUPERVISOR.
AS MANY OF THE AUDIENCE MEMBERS WERE STILL CLOSETED, NEWS
CAMERAS THAT ARRIVED TO FILM WERE ONLY ALLOWED TO SHOW THE
TWO CANDIDATES. AND DANIEL WHEN MILK WAS
ASSASSINATED JUST A YEAR AFTER THAT HISTORIC DEBATE.
SHARES OF HARVEY'S DECEMBER 1ST FRIDAY NIGHT SERVICE BECAME AN
IMPROMPTU MEMORIAL TO HIM WITH HUNDREDS OF PEOPLE ARRIVING TO
REMEMBER HIM AND REMIND EACH OTHER OF THE STRENGTH OF THEIR
COMMUNITY. DANIEL AND OTHER MEMBERS
RECALLED THAT NIGHT AS THE MOMENT WHEN SHA ZAHAV
ESTABLISHED ITSELF AS AN UNDENIABLE PART OF THE CITY OF
THE CITY'S POLITICS AND LIFE. >> HE HELPED LEAD SHA AS A HUB
FOR THE NEXT FIVE DECADES MOVING WITH THE SYNAGOGUE FROM
ONE RENTED SPACE TO ANOTHER AS THE EXPANDING CONGREGATION
QUICKLY OUTGREW EACH LOCATION. HE WELCOMED ANYONE MAN, WOMAN,
STRAIGHT, GAY, EVEN NON-JEWS THAT FELT A CONNECTION AND WAS
INTERESTED IN ATTENDING. ATTENDEES LOOKED UP TO HIM FOR
THE DEPTH OF HIS JEWISH KNOWLEDGE AND UNAPOLOGETIC
PRIDE IN BOTH OF HIS IDENTITIES AND EVEN AFTER HIS DECLINING
HEALTH REQUIRED HIM SWITCH TO ATTENDING SERVICES OVER ZOOM.
THE MERE MENTION OF HIS NAME COULD LIFT UP THE ENTIRE ROOM.
HE EARNED A LAW DEGREE FROM UC SCHOOL OF LAW IN SAN FRANCISCO
AND WORKED AS AN ATTORNEY FOR KAISER PERMANENTE IN OAKLAND
FOR MORE THAN TWO DECADES. HE MARRIED HIS PARTNER STEPHAN
RONNI ARC AS SOON AS HE WAS AS SOON AS IT WAS LEGAL AND THE
TWO HELPED RAISE TWO CHILDREN ASHER AND ZINA.
>> THE COUPLE LOVE TO TRAVEL, MAKING IT THEIR GOAL TO VISIT A
NEW SPOT ON THE GLOBE EACH YEAR.
FRIENDS AND FAMILY MEMBERS, FRIENDS AND FAMILY REMEMBER HIM
NOT ONLY AS A VISIONARY AND LEADER BUT ALSO AS A MAN
WHO WAS ENDLESSLY KIND AND GENEROUS, WHO LIVED HIS
LIFE WITH UNCOMPROMISING INTEGRITY.
REST IN PEACE AND POWER DANIEL CHESHIRE.
MAY YOUR MEMORY BE A BLESSING AND THE REST I SUBMIT.
>> THANK YOU, MR. PRESIDENT. SUPERVISOR MELGAR.
>> THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK. COLLEAGUE AS MANY OF YOU KNOW
EARLIER A FEW WEEKS AGO WE LOST CLAUDE THE ALLIGATOR THE
BELOVED ALBINO ALLIGATOR WHO LIVED AT THE CALIFORNIA ACADEMY
OF SCIENCES AND GOLDEN GATE PARK.
>> CLAUDE PASSED AWAY AT THE AGE OF 30 AFTER NEARLY TWO
DECADES AS ONE OF SAN FRANCISCO'S MOST RECOGNIZABLE
AND CHERISHED RESIDENTS. >> HE WASN'T JUST AN ATTRACTION
HE WAS A ROLE MODEL FOR HOW WE TREAT THOSE WHO ARE A LITTLE
BIT DIFFERENT FOR MILLIONS OF CHILDREN MANY OF THEM SAN
FRANCISCO FANS. CLAUDE WAS THEIR FIRST
ENCOUNTER WITH SCIENCE WITH CONSERVATION, WITH THE IDEA
THAT CARING FOR OUR PLANET STARTS WITH CURIOSITY
AND EMPATHY. ENTIRE GENERATIONS GREW UP
VISITING HIM ON SCHOOL FIELD TRIPS, FAMILY OUTINGS, FIRST
TRIPS TO THE ACADEMY. INCLUDING MY THREE DAUGHTERS.
AND YES, CLAUDE WAS A DISTRICT SEVEN RESIDENT.
AND THROUGHOUT MY TENURE I HAVE REPRESENTED HIM PROUDLY.
>> I AM INTRODUCING A RESOLU OCEAN TO ACKNOWLEDGE THIS ICON
OF OUR CITY TO LET THE PEOPLE OF SAN FRANCISCO DECIDE HOW WE
COULD COMMEMORATE HIS MEMORY. SO THIS RESOLUTION URGES THE
RECREATION AND PARKS COMMISSION TO COMMEMORATE TIVELY NAME A
STREET IN GOLDEN GATE PARK. CLAUDE THE ALLIGATOR WAY.
MY OFFICE HAS BEEN WORKING CLOSELY WITH THE PARKS
DEPARTMENT TO IDENTIFY SEVERAL STREETS THAT COULD ADOPT THIS
NAME IN THE PARK. AS WELL AS WITH MISSION LOCAL
TO LAUNCH A PUBLIC POLL IN WHICH STREET ASKING
RESIDENTS WHICH STREET SHOULD RECEIVE THIS HONORARY NAME.
AND I AM HAPPY TO REPORT THAT HUNDREDS OF PEOPLE HAVE ALREADY
VOTED EVEN THOUGH IT'S BEEN UP FOR A COUPLE OF DAYS.
AND THIS IS ABOUT HONORING THE JOY THAT CLAUDE BROUGHT, THE
EDUCATION THAT HE INSPIRED AND THE VALUES THAT HE
REPRESENTED SCIENCE STEWARDSHIP AND WONDER.
IT IS ALSO ABOUT GIVING EVERYDAY SAN FRANCISCANS AN
OPPORTUNITY TO VOICE HOW WE COULD COMMEMORATE HIS IMPACT.
>> SAN FRANCISCO IS A CITY THAT UNDERSTANDS THAT CULTURE ISN'T
ONLY DEFINED BY BUILDINGS OR MONUMENTS BUT THAT THE STORIES
WE TELL AND THE MEMORIES WE PRESERVE ALSO DO THAT AS WELL.
HONORING CLAUDE IN THIS WAY ENSURES THAT FUTURE GENERATIONS
WILL CONTINUE TO ASK WHO WAS THIS CLAUDE?
AND IN DOING SO LEARN SOMETHING ABOUT OUR CITY, OUR PARK, OUR
SHARED COMMITMENT TO EDUCATION, SCIENCE, CONSERVATION
AND EMBRACING THE MOST UNIQUE AMONG US.
I RESPECTFULLY ASK FOR YOUR SUPPORT AND THE REST I SUBMIT.
>> THANK YOU. SUPERVISOR MELGAR.
>> SUPERVISOR SAUTER THANK YOU .
COLLEAGUES, I HAVE A NUMBER OF ITEMS TO INTRODUCE TODAY.
FIRST I'M INTRODUCING AN ORDINANCE TO ESTABLISH THE
FISHERMAN'S WHARF ENTERTAINMENT ZONE.
WE'VE CRAFTED THIS ENTERTAINMENT ZONE
IN PARTNERSHIP WITH THE FISHERMAN'S WHARF COMMUNITY
BENEFIT DISTRICT AND THEIR MEMBERS INCLUDING MERCHANTS,
HOTELS AND THE MARITIME INDUSTRY.
THIS BUILDS ON THE MOMENTUM WE'RE MAKING IN REINFORCING
FISHERMAN'S WHARF TO BE A DESTINATION FOR LOCALS
AND TOURISTS ALIKE. RECENT PROGRESS HAS INCLUDED AN
18 MONTH EXTENSION OF THE SUCCESSFUL SKY WHEEL MULTIPLE
LEASES FOR NEW RESTAURANTS AND A PORT LED INITIATIVE TO
BRING A BEAUTIFUL NEW PUBLIC PLAZA TO TAYLOR STREET, THE
FISHERMAN'S WHARF ENTERTAINMENT ZONE JOINS MANY OTHER
SUCCESSFUL ZONES. WE'VE HELPED STAND UP THIS YEAR
INCLUDING ELLIS STREET IN 39 AND JOINS EXISTING SUCCESSFUL
ENTERTAINMENT ZONES AT MIDLAND AND THE FIRST IN THE STATE AT
FRONT STREET. THANK YOU TO TITA BELL AND MY
OFFICE BEN VAN HOUTEN AT OPW AND VICTORIA WANG IN THE CITY
ATTORNEY'S OFFICE FOR THEIR HELP TO PREPARE THIS ORDINANCE.
I LOOK FORWARD TO ALL OF THE EVENTS AND CREATIVITY THAT THIS
NEW ENTERTAINMENT ZONE WILL ENABLE IN FISHERMAN'S WHARF.
NEXT I'M INTRODUCING LEGISLATION FOR THE FIRST PHASE
OF OUR CLEAN STREETS ACT. THIS LEGISLATIVE PACKAGE WILL
RESULT IN CLEANER STREETS BY UPDATING THE PUBLIC WORKS CODE
TO IMPROVE OUR DEPARTMENT'S DELIVERY SERVICES.
IT WILL ALSO STRENGTHEN ACCOUNTABILITY MEASURES TO MAKE
SURE OUR DOLLARS ARE BEING USED AS EFFICIENTLY AS POSSIBLE.
OUR INITIAL ORDINANCE ACHIEVES A FEW THINGS.
IT UPDATES THE HEALTH CODE TO REVISE AND CLARIFY CONFUSING
AND NOW DATED TERMS CONCERNING GARBAGE RECEPTACLE
REQUIREMENTS. IT AUTHORIZES A PROCESS FOR
APPLYING ADMINISTRATIVE FINES AND IT REQUIRES THE DEPARTMENT
OF PUBLIC WORKS TO PERIODICALLY CONDUCT EVALUATIONS
AND PERFORMANCE REPORTS A MECHANICAL STREET SWEEPING
OPERATIONS A SERVICE THAT MUCH OF DISTRICT THREE DOES NOT
RECEIVE. THANKS TO TITA BELL, MY OFFICE
AND CHRIS TOM FROM THE CITY ATTORNEY'S OFFICE FOR THEIR
WORK HERE. THIS IS JUST THE FIRST PHASE OF
OUR EFFORTS WITHIN THE CLEAN STREETS ACT AND I LOOK FORWARD
TO MORE WORK AHEAD IN THE NEW YEAR TO ENSURE THAT SAN
FRANCISCO'S STREETS, SIDEWALKS AND PUBLIC SPACES ARE CLEANER
FOR ALL. FINALLY, I WANT TO INDICATE MY
CO-SPONSORSHIP OF THE MAYOR'S FIRE CODE UPDATES TODAY ALONG
ALONGSIDE SUPERVISOR SHERYL. WE HAVE CRAFTED THESE
AMENDMENTS IN RESPONSE TO AN ALMOST OVERWHELMING CONCERN
FROM RESIDENTS IN OUR DISTRICTS.
THESE AMENDMENTS MAINTAIN A COMMITMENT TO FIRE SAFETY
UPGRADES WHILE RECOGNIZING THE TREMENDOUS HARDSHIP AND LIKELY
DISPLACEMENT THAT COULD RESULT FROM THE 2022 MANDATE FOR FIRE
SPRINKLERS. >> I WILL ALSO BE COSIGNING A
LETTER OF INQUIRY ALONGSIDE SUPERVISOR SHERYL ASKING THE
PUC FOR INFORMATION ON THE 126 IMPACTED BUILDINGS SO THAT WE
CAN HAVE IMMEDIATE ANSWERS TO THE OPERATIONAL FEASIBILITY OF
INSTALLING AND SUPPORTING FIRE SPRINKLERS AT THESE SPECIFIC
BUILDINGS AND THE REST. >> I SUBMIT THANK YOU
SUPERVISOR SAUTER. >> SUPERVISOR SHERYL.
COLLEAGUES TODAY HAVE A FEW INTRODUCTIONS.
FIRST, AS SUPERVISOR SAUTER JUST OUTLINED IN PARTNERSHIP
WITH MAYOR LURIE, WE'RE INTRODUCING AMENDMENTS TO THE
FIRE CODE TO EXTEND THE COMPLIANCE DEADLINE FOR THE
2023 SPRINKLER RETROFIT MANDATE BY THREE YEARS.
>> SUPERVISORS SAUTER SUMMARIZED THIS VERY, VERY
WELL. WE'VE HEARD FROM HUNDREDS OF
CONSTITUENTS VERY CLEARLY, MANY OF WHOM ARE RETIRED SENIORS ON
FIXED INCOMES THAT NOT ONLY IS THE CURRENT MANY NOT UNDERSTOOD
BUT IT IS ALSO WIDELY UNAFFORDABLE AND FOR MANY
STRUCTURAL REASONS IS OFTEN NOT FEASIBLE FOR MANY OF THESE
BUILDINGS. AND SO YOU KNOW, EXTENDING THIS
COMPLIANCE DEADLINE, THE FIRST COMPLIANCE DEADLINE IS AN
IMPORTANT FIRST STEP TO HELP AFFECTED RESIDENTS GAIN
CERTAINTY ABOUT WHAT'S EXPECTED OF THEM IN THE FIRE CODE.
AND CERTAINTY REALLY IS THE THING WE'RE GETTING TOWARDS
HERE. >> THIS STEP OF EXTENDING THE
FIRST DEADLINE DOES NOT RESOLVE THE UNDERLYING ISSUE THAT
FRANKLY THIS THIS MANDATE PAUSE POSES SOME EXISTENTIAL
FINANCIAL BURDENS FOR AFFECTED RESIDENTS.
SO GOING FORWARD I'LL WORK ALONGSIDE THE MAYOR AND
SUPERVISOR SAUTER TO BRING CLARITY TO BRING SPECIFICITY
AND TO BRING CERTAINTY TO THE DEFINITION OF UNDUE HARDSHIP
THAT IS ALREADY EMBEDDED IN THE FIRE CODE.
AND THAT IS THE PROCESS THAT WE USE FOR EXEMPTING BUILDINGS
IN WHICH THIS SPRINKLER MANDATE IS DEEMED UNFEASIBLE.
THIS IS GOING TO BE DONE TRANSPARENTLY, TRANSPARENTLY.
IT'S GOING TO BE DONE IN COORDINATION WITH THE
AFFECTED BUILDINGS. IT'S GOING TO BE DONE
IN COORDINATION WITH EXPERTS IN THE FIELD.
AND IT'S BE DONE IN COORDINATION WITH THE FIRE
DEPARTMENT. I WANT TO COMMEND CHIEF CRISPIN
FOR HIS PARTNERSHIP ON THIS AND LEANING IN TO THIS AND FOR
WORKING ON THE VERY DIFFICULT BALANCE BETWEEN FIRE SAFETY
AND AFFORDABILITY. AFFORDABILITY IS THE BUZZ WORD
NATIONWIDE AND DEFINITELY HERE IN SAN FRANCISCO.
WE NEED TO MAKE SURE THAT PEOPLE ARE NOT DISPLACED
UNNECESSARILY, THAT PEOPLE DON'T LOSE THEIR HOMES.
THAT WE CONTINUE TO PRIORITIZE AFFORDABILITY FOR ALL SAN
FRANCISCANS AS WE MOVE FORWARD AS PART OF THIS EFFORT.
SUPERVISOR SAUTER AND I ARE ALSO SUBMITTING A JOINT LETTER
OF INQUIRY TO THE PUC REQUESTING A FEASIBILITY
ANALYSIS OF THE SPRINKLER MANDATE WITH REGARD TO EXISTING
WATER INFRASTRUCTURE. AND WE WILL MAKE THOSE FINDINGS
PUBLIC AS SOON AS THEY ARE AVAILABLE.
DENNIS RIERA AND HIS TEAM AT THE PUC.
I WANT TO THANK THEM AHEAD OF TIME FOR THEIR PARTNERSHIP
AND THEIR ASSISTANCE AND FRANKLY WITH WITH ALL OF
YOU WITH MY COLLEAGUES, ALL STAKEHOLDERS IN AFFECTED
RESIDENTS WE LOOK FORWARD TO WORKING TOGETHER AS WE MOVE
THIS FORWARD. FINALLY, COLLEAGUES, I'M PROUD
TO BE CO-SPONSORING A RESOLUTION ALONGSIDE
MAYOR LURIE THAT WILL FINALLY APPROVE THE INFRASTRUCTURE
FINANCING PLAN FOR THE 3333 AND 3700 CALIFORNIA STREET
PROJECTS IN DISTRICT TWO. SINCE TAKING OFFICE OVER THE
PAST YEAR I'VE TALKED WITH NEIGHBORS THROUGHOUT THE
DISTRICT WHO ASK ME WHEN WILL THIS PROJECT FINALLY GET
SHOVELS IN THE GROUND? AND I'M PROUD THAT THIS
LEGISLATION WILL TAKE US TO THE LEGISLATIVE FINISH LINE.
AND ONE CRITICAL STEP CLOSER TO BUILDING MORE HOMES AFFORDABLE
SENIOR HOUSING, SUPPORTIVE SENIOR HOUSING, CHILD CARE
FACILITIES AND RETAIL. THE PASSAGE OF THE FAMILY
ZONING PLAN AND THE SIGNING OF THAT PLAN LAST WEEK IS ONLY THE
FIRST STEP IN OUR JOURNEY TOWARDS MORE FOR MORE
AFFORDABILITY HERE IN SAN FRANCISCO.
ZONING ON ITS OWN DOES NOT BUILD HOUSING.
WE NEED TO DO MORE AS A BODY AND AS A CITY TO ENSURE THE
SHOVELS GET INTO THE GROUND TO BUILD THE DESPERATELY NEEDED
RESPONSIBLE NEIGHBORHOOD CENTRIC HOUSING THAT WE ALL
WANT TO SEE. ENHANCED INFRASTRUCTURE
FINANCING DISTRICTS ARE A CRITICAL TOOL IN OUR TOOLBOX
IN OUR FIGHT FOR AFFORDABILITY AND OUR FIGHT TO MAKE SAN
FRANCISCO MORE WELCOMING FOR EVERYONE.
AND I'M PROUD TO BE ABLE TO CO-SPONSOR THIS THIS ITEM.
THANK YOU TO THE MAYOR'S TEAM, TO THE OFFICE OF ECONOMIC
AND WORKFORCE DEVELOPMENT LED BY WHOSE EFFORTS IN THIS WERE
LED BY LILA MINSKY. THANK YOU TO MY AIDE LORENZO
ROSAS FOR HIS WORK ON THIS AND TO MY COLLEAGUES WHO SERVE
ON THE PUBLIC FINANCING AUTHORITY.
SUPERVISORS CHEN MELGAR AND WALDEN.
AND TO THE MANY CONSTITUENTS AND NEIGHBORS WHO HAVE VOICED
THEIR SUPPORT FOR THIS PROJECT. WE ARE PUSHING HARD ON IT EVERY
DAY. >> THANK YOU COLLEAGUES AND THE
REST I SUBMIT. THANK YOU.
SUPERVISOR CHERYL SUPERVISOR WALTON.
>> THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK. COLLEAGUES TODAY I'M
INTRODUCING A REQUEST FOR INFORMATION TO OUR CITY
DEPARTMENTS REGARDING THE POTENTIAL IMPACTS OF A RENT
FREEZE IN SAN FRANCISCO AS WE CONTINUE TO FACE A SEVERE
AFFORDABILITY CRISIS. RESIDENTS ACROSS OUR CITY ARE
STRUGGLING WITH RISING HOUSING COSTS, ECONOMIC UNCERTAINTY
AND DISPLACEMENT PRESSURES. OTHER MAJOR CITIES INCLUDING
NEW YORK HAVE RECENTLY ADOPTED OR CONSIDERED RENT FREEZE
POLICIES IN RESPONSE TO SIMILAR CHALLENGES.
BEFORE THIS BOARD CONSIDERS ANY COMPARABLE LEGISLATIVE ACTION,
IT IS CRITICAL THAT WE FULLY UNDERSTAND THE POTENTIAL
CONSEQUENCES BOTH POSITIVE AND NEGATIVE FOR TENANTS, SMALL
PROPERTY OWNERS, HOUSING SUPPLY AND CITY'S FISCAL HEALTH.
THIS INQUIRY ASK OUR HOUSING PLANNING AND FINANCIAL
DEPARTMENTS TO PROVIDE FORECASTS AND ANALYSIS ON HOW A
RENT FREEZE COULD IMPACT HOUSING STABILITY,
AFFORDABILITY, MAINTENANCE OF EXISTING HOUSING, NEW
DEVELOPMENT AND CITY REVENUES. IT ALSO SEEKS LESSONS LEARNED
FROM OTHER JURISDICTIONS INCLUDING LEGAL, ADMINISTRATIVE
AND ENFORCEMENT CONSIDERATIONS. LET ME BE CLEAR THIS IS NOT A
PROPOSAL TO ENACT A RENT FREEZE TODAY.
>> THIS IS ABOUT GATHERING DATA, UNDERSTANDING TRADEOFFS
AND ENSURING ANY FUTURE POLICY DECISIONS ARE GROUNDED IN FACTS
. OUR RESPONSIBILITY AS
POLICYMAKERS IS TO PROTECT TENANTS WHILE ALSO ENSURING THE
LONG TERM HEALTH AND STABILITY OF OUR HOUSING SYSTEM.
I LOOK FORWARD TO RECEIVING THIS INFORMATION AND HAVING A
THOUGHTFUL TRANSFER AND DISCUSSION WITH THE BOARD
AND THE PUBLIC. >> THE REST I SUBMIT.
>> THANK YOU. SUPERVISOR WALTON SUPERVISOR
HUANG I HAVE REQUESTED FROM S.F. MTA A COMPREHENSIVE
EVALUATION OF POTENTIAL OPPORTUNITIES TO INCREASE ON
STREET PARKING AVAILABILITY IN DISTRICT FOUR.
WHAT THIS INQUIRY IS ASKING IS SIMPLY WHETHER THERE ARE
OPPORTUNITIES WITHIN OUR EXISTING STREET AND CURB SPACE
TO BETTER MEET COMMUNITY NEEDS. THE SUNSET HAS OLDER HOUSING
STOCK AND LIMITED OFF STREET PARKING AND MANY RESIDENTS
INCLUDING SENIORS, FAMILIES AND SMALL BUSINESS CUSTOMERS
RELY ON CARS AS A PART OF THEIR DAILY LIVES.
PARKING ACCESS IS ONE OF THE MOST CONSISTENT CONCERNS WE
HEAR AND IT AFFECTS NEIGHBORHOOD ACCESS, SMALL
BUSINESSES AND OVERALL SAFETY. >> THE REQUESTS S.F. MTA TO
TAKE A CAREFUL ENGINEERING BASED LOOK AT WHERE EXISTING
STREET WIDTH OR CURB CONFIGURATIONS MIGHT ALLOW FOR
CHANGES SUCH AS ANGLED OR PERPENDICULAR PARKING AS
OPPOSED TO PARALLEL WHILE MAINTAINING EMERGENCY ACCESS.
PEDESTRIAN SAFETY AND COMPLIANCE WITH DESIGN
STANDARDS. WE ALSO ASK FOR REVIEW OF CURB
MANAGEMENT TOOLS INCLUDING LOADING ZONES AND RED ZONES TO
SEE WHETHER SMALL ADJUSTMENTS COULD BE MADE WITHOUT
COMPROMISING SAFETY. FOR EXAMPLE, I OFTEN RUN ALONG
SUNSET ROADS AND I SEE SO MANY WIDE ROADS THAT COULD CONVERT
PARALLEL PARKING INTO TWO DIAGONAL OR PERPENDICULAR
AND INCREASE PARKING SPACES EASILY.
>> IMPORTANTLY THIS IS AN EVALUATION AND NOT A
PREDETERMINED OUTCOME. IT IS ABOUT UNDERSTANDING WHAT
SPACE MAY BE AVAILABLE AND WHAT TRADEOFFS EXIST BEFORE ANY
DECISIONS ARE MADE. DISTRICT FOUR IS A MULTIMODAL
NEIGHBORHOOD AND I STRONGLY SUPPORT HAVING MULTIPLE WAYS
FOR PEOPLE TO GET AROUND WEATHER BY TRANSIT WALKING,
BIKING OR DRIVING. I'M ABOUT WIN WIN SOLUTIONS.
>> COMMUNICATION IS CENTRAL TO THIS REQUEST.
AFTER YOU IDENTIFY POSSIBLE PARKING INCREASE OPPORTUNITIES
,ANY POTENTIAL CHANGES WOULD INVOLVE CONSULTATION WITH
NEIGHBORHOOD RESIDENTS, MERCHANTS AND STAKEHOLDERS SO
THAT SOLUTIONS REFLECT LOCAL NEEDS AND PRIORITIES.
I'VE ASKED S.F. MTA TO RESPOND BY JANUARY 15TH AND MY OFFICE
WILL SHARE UPDATES AS WE RECEIVE THEM AND CONTINUE
WORKING COLLABORATIVELY WITH THE AGENCY AND THE COMMUNITY.
THANK YOU. THE REST TAKES A MINUTE.
>> THANK YOU. SUPERVISOR WONG.
SUPERVISOR CHEN SUBMIT. >> THANK YOU.
SUPERVISOR CHEN. THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK.
>> COLLEAGUE THIS LAST SATURDAY EVENING WAS THE SOUND OF
HISTORY BEING MADE AGAIN FOR THE BALBOA HIGH SCHOOL FOOTBALL
TEAM. >> THE BALBOA BUCCANEERS ARE
THE 2025 STATE CHAMPIONS IN DIVISION SEVEN AA YAY!
RUNNING BACK MOUSE ME SCORED IT FOR TOUCHDOWNS AND CORNERBACK
JOSEPH SMITH HARD IN A 49 YARD TOUCHDOWN PASS FROM RYLAN JONES
RYLAN VAN JONES WHO ALSO RUSHED FOR A SCORE.
>> PHILLY FINISHING THE SEASON WITH A 12 TO 2 RECORD.
THIS MARKS BALBOA SECOND STRAIGHT TITLE AND IS THIRD
OVERALL. >> BEFORE THAT BALBOA SECURED
THE SAN FRANCISCO SECTION CHAMPIONSHIP BY BEATING
WASHINGTON HIGH SCHOOL IN NOVEMBER.
>> BALBOA HAS EMERGED AT THE TOP OF SAN FRANCISCO'S PATRICK
LEE. WE ARE INCREDIBLY PROUD OF OUR
BUCCANEERS. CONGRATULATIONS TO OUR
INCREDIBLE TEAM AND COACHING STAFF.
GO BATS. THANK YOU.
>> THE REST I. THANK YOU.
SUPERVISOR CHEN SUPERVISOR DORSEY.
>> THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK. COLLEAGUES BY NOW I AM SURE WE
HAVE ALL SEEN AND READ A MULTITUDE OF NEWS ACCOUNTS
AND OBITUARIES FOR ROBIN MICHELLE REINER WHO DIED SUNDAY
AT THEIR LOS ANGELES HOME IN AN APPARENT HOMICIDE.
THIS DEVOTED MARRIED COUPLE OF 36 YEARS BEARS AN HISTORICALLY
SIGNIFICANT CONNECTION TO SAN FRANCISCO.
FEW MAY FULLY KNOW ABOUT BUT WHICH I THINK IS WORTHY OF OUR
REMEMBRANCE TODAY. AND I WOULD ASK MY BOARD
COLLEAGUES TO JOIN ME IN ADJOURNING TODAY'S BOARD
MEETING IN THEIR HONOR. ROBIN MARSHALL REINER WERE NOT
SOLELY CELEBRATED FIGURES IN AMERICAN CINEMA
AND PHILANTHROPY. THEY WERE FEARLESS AND LONG
TIME ADVOCATES FOR WORTHWHILE LIBERAL CAUSES IN CALIFORNIA
THAT RANGED FROM SUPPORTING UNIVERSAL PRESCHOOL ALL TO
TAKING ON BIG TOBACCO. THEIR PARTNERSHIP WITH SAN
FRANCISCO CAME ABOUT IN THE WAKE OF 2000 EIGHT'S PASSAGE OF
PROPOSITION EIGHT WHICH BANNED EQUAL MARRIAGE RIGHTS FOR SAME
SEX COUPLES THAT HAD ONLY MONTHS EARLIER BEEN SECURED
IN A LANDMARK STATE SUPREME COURT DECISION.
THE CITY AND COUNTY OF SAN FRANCISCO THROUGH ITS CITY
ATTORNEY'S OFFICE THEN LED BY DENNIS HERRERA, HAD BEEN THE
LEAD PLAINTIFF IN THAT STATE LITIGATION FOR MORE THAN FOUR
YEARS AT THAT POINT AND IN THAT LONG STRUGGLES DARKEST HOUR AS
CALIFORNIA'S LGBTQ PLUS COMMUNITY WATCHED WITH
HEARTBREAK TO SEE OUR HARD WON MARRIAGE RIGHTS STRIPPED AWAY
BY POPULAR VOTE. ROB AND MICHELLE REINER JOINED
THE CAUSE. TOGETHER THEY WERE INSTRUMENTAL
IN CONVENING AN ORGANIZATION AND A MOVEMENT IN THE AMERICAN
FOUNDATION FOR EQUAL RIGHTS OR A FOR THAT WOULD JOIN SAN
FRANCISCO AND HELP REGROUP FOR AN UPHILL FEDERAL CHALLENGE TO
PROPOSITION EIGHT CONSTITUTIONALITY AS DESCRIBED
IN THE AWARD WINNING BOOK BY NEW YORK TIMES REPORTER JO
BECKER. FORCING THE SPRING INSIDE THE
FIGHT FOR MARRIAGE EQUALITY, ROB AND MICHELLE REINER WERE
SINGULARLY RESPONSIBLE FOR BRINGING TOGETHER LGBTQ PLUS
COMMUNITY LEADERS AND COUPLES INCLUDING CHAD GRIFFIN, DUSTIN
LANCE BLACK, BRUCE COHEN, KRISTIN PERRY AND SANDY STIER
AND PAUL KHATAMI AND JEFFREY ZARELLA.
THEY HIRED LEGAL POWERHOUSES TED OLSON AND DAVID BOIES ONCE
REPUBLICAN AND DEMOCRATIC LEGAL FOLKS RESPECTIVELY WHO HAD
FAMOUSLY SQUARED OFF IN THE 2000 BUSH V GORE CASE.
AND TOGETHER IF REPRESENTED COUPLES IN PARTNERSHIP WITH SAN
FRANCISCO SHOWS REPRESENTATION OF THE BROADER SOCIETAL STAKE
FOR MARRIAGE EQUALITY AT A DIFFICULT YET PIVOTAL MOMENT
FOR THE LGBTQ PLUS COMMUNITY. AND FOR SAN FRANCISCO CITY
ATTORNEY'S OFFICE ROBIN MICHELLE REINER'S COURAGE
MATTERED AND IT WASN'T SOLELY MEASURED IN THE DOLLARS THEY SO
GENEROUSLY GAVE BUT IN THE SUPPORT BOTH DEMONSTRATED
PERSONALLY SHOWING UP AT TRIAL GIVING VOICE TO THE CAUSE WE
SHARED AND ENCOURAGING LAWYERS AND SUPPORT STAFF IN WAYS THAT
WENT THE WAY THAT MEANT THE WORLD TO THEM.
THE CASE THEY FUNDED AND HELPED TO LEAD INITIALLY ENTITLED
PERRY VERSUS SCHWARZENEGGER AND LATER HOLLINGSWORTH VERSUS
PERRY WOULD BE A ROLLER COASTER RIDE FOR THE NEXT FOUR YEARS.
BUT IN ITS DECISIVE FINAL RULING ON JUNE 26TH, 2013, THE
U.S. SUPREME COURT STRUCK DOWN PROP EIGHT ONCE AND FOR ALL
RESTORING MARRIAGE EQUALITY TO LGBTQ PLUS COUPLES
IN CALIFORNIA AND SETTING THE STAGE LEGALLY AND MORALLY FOR
THE HIGH COURT'S RECOGNITION FOR MARRIAGE EQUALITY
NATIONWIDE. TWO YEARS LATER, HISTORY WILL
LONG REMEMBER THOSE CASES. BUT FOR THE MANY CALIFORNIANS
INVOLVED IN THAT DECADE LONG LEGAL FIGHT, WE WILL REMEMBER
SOMETHING MORE PERSONAL ROBIN MARSHALL REINER'S UNWAVERING
AND GENEROUS COMMITMENT TO SEE JUSTICE DONE EVEN ACKNOWLEDGING
AS WE ALL DID AT THE TIME THAT JUSTICE MIGHT NOT HAPPEN WAS
INSPIRING, INFLUENTIAL AND IN THE END CONSEQUENTIAL.
THEY BELIEVED IN OUR CAUSE. THEY BELIEVED IN SAN FRANCISCO
AND TODAY AS WE MOURN THEIR LOSS.
SANFORD CISCO REMEMBERS THEM WITH GRATITUDE.
REST IN PEACE. ROB AND MICHEL REINER MADE
THEIR MEMORY BE A BLESSING AND AN ENDURING REMINDER OF THE
PROGRESS THAT CAN BE MADE WHEN BRAVE PEOPLE OF PRINCIPLE
COMMIT THEIR NAMES, THEIR RESOURCES AND THEIR HEARTS TO
THE CAUSE OF JUSTICE AND THE REST.
>> I SUBMIT. >> THANK YOU.
SUPERVISOR DORSEY SUPERVISOR FIELDER.
>> THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK. COLLEAGUES, I AM EXCITED TO
ANNOUNCE THAT I WILL BE INTRODUCING LEGISLATION THAT
ACTUALLY DATES BACK TO AN AUGUST VISIT THAT MY STAFF
AND I TOOK ON A SELF-FUNDED TRIP TO MEXICO CITY TO MEET
WITH MUNICIPAL AND FEDERAL OFFICIALS AND IN OUR MEETING
WITH THE OFFICE OF THE SECRETARY OF FOREIGN AFFAIRS WE
TALKED ABOUT HOW MEXICAN NATIONALS COMMONLY FALL PREY TO
FRAUD IN NOTARY OFFICES AROUND THE UNITED STATES SIMPLY
BECAUSE OF A LANGUAGE AND CULTURAL MISUNDERSTANDING
THAT SOME NOTARIES EXPLOIT IN MANY LATIN AMERICAN
COUNTRIES NOTORIOUS OATHS OFFER IMMIGRATION LEGAL SERVICES BUT
MANY NOTARIES SERVING SPANISH SPEAKING IMMIGRANTS TAKE
ADVANTAGE OF THAT UNDERSTANDING AND FRAUDULENTLY OFFER LEGAL OR
PSEUDO LEGAL ADVICE ABOUT IMMIGRATION.
CALIFORNIANS STATE LAW REQUIRES NOTARIES TO POST SIGNAGE
STATING THAT THEY ARE NOT AN ATTORNEY NOR AUTHORIZED TO GIVE
LEGAL ADVICE ABOUT IMMIGRATION OR ANY OTHER LEGAL MATTERS.
>> HOWEVER, LACK OF COMPLIANCE AND ENFORCEMENT HAS LEFT THE
DOOR OPEN TO UNSCRUPULOUS ACTORS.
IN SAN FRANCISCO THERE HAVE BEEN MANY REPORTS OF SUCH
ACTIVITY INCLUDING THE VERY HIGH PROFILE LAWSUIT FILED BY
OUR OWN CITY ATTORNEY DAVID CHIU AGAINST NOTARY LEONARDO
LEONARD LACAYO RESULTING IN THE COURTS REQUIRING HIM TO PAY
$600,000 DUE TO HIS PREDATORY BEHAVIOR AGAINST HUNDREDS OF
IMMIGRANTS HERE IN SAN FRANCISCO.
>> THIS UNLAWFUL CONDUCT HAS LIFE THREATENING CONSEQUENCES
FOR IMMIGRANT FAMILIES. AND SO TODAY I'M INTRODUCING AN
ORDINANCE TO REQUIRE INDIVIDUALS WHO NOTARIZE OR
ASSIST PEOPLE IN COMPLETING IMMIGRATION DOCUMENTS TO
PROVIDE A LISTING OF LOW COST OR FREE IMMIGRATION LEGAL
SERVICE PROVIDERS AND CONSULATES PROVIDED BY OUR
OWN OFFICE OF CIVIC ENGAGEMENT AND IMMIGRATION AFFAIRS.
ADDITIONALLY, THIS LEGISLATION AUTHORIZES THE HUMAN RIGHTS
COMMISSION TO PROVIDE ASSISTANCE TO MEMBERS OF THE
PUBLIC WHO WISH TO FILE A COMPLAINT WITH A STATE
LICENSING OR ENFORCEMENT ENTITY AGAINST A NOTARY OR IMMIGRATION
CONSULTANT WHO ALLEGEDLY VIOLATED THE LAW BY PROVIDING
FRAUDULENT LEGAL ADVICE. I WANT TO THANK CITY ATTORNEY
BRAD RACINE, DIRECTOR GEORGE RIVAS AND OCA DIRECTOR
AND MOLLY TO BENU AND HRC DIRECTOR KATIE TING WITH THE
SAN FRANCISCO OFFICE OF SMALL BUSINESS.
THE FOLKS AT GARRISON MISSION ACTION AND OTHER COMMUNITY
PARTNERS FOR YOUR HELP ON THIS PIECE.
I ALSO WANT TO THANK MY LEGISLATIVE AIDE JENNIFER
FERRIGNO AND SUPERVISORS WALTON CHEN AND CHAN FOR EARLY
CO-SPONSORSHIP AS WELL AS HONOR LOUISE SURVEY FORMER CONSUL
GENERAL OF MEXICO IN SAN FRANCISCO AND THE MEXICO OFFICE
OF THE SECRETARY OF FOREIGN AFFAIRS FOR MEETING WITH US
IN AUGUST TO DISCUSS HOW TO SUPPORT OUR SHARED
CONSTITUENTS. I HOPE YOU ALL JOIN ME
IN SUPPORTING THIS LEGISLATION. THE REST I SUBMIT THANK YOU.
>> SUPERVISOR FIELDER SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD.
>> COLLEAGUES, SAN FRANCISCO HAS LONG PRIDED ITSELF ON GOOD
GOVERNANCE BASED ON TRANSPARENCY, ACCOUNTABILITY
AND RULES THAT REFLECT OUR SHARED VALUES.
TERM LIMITS WERE ADOPTED WITH THAT INTENTION TO ENSURE
RENEWAL AND LEADERSHIP AND TO PREVENT THE CONCENTRATION OF
POLITICAL POWER OVER TIME. >> HOWEVER, OUR CITY CHARTER
CURRENTLY CONTAINS A LOOPHOLE THAT UNDERMINES THAT PURPOSE.
IT ALLOWS ELECTED OFFICIALS TO SERVE TWO TERMS STEP AWAY FOR
ONE AND THEN RETURN AGAIN REPEATING THAT CYCLE
INDEFINITELY. THIS LOOPHOLE THAT ALLOWS
CAREER POLITICIANS TO COME IN AND OUT OF OFFICE HAS
STAGNATED PROGRESS FOR FAR TOO LONG.
GOOD GOVERNANCE REQUIRES THAT WE PERIODICALLY REVIEW OUR
SYSTEMS AND ASK WHETHER THEY ARE STILL SERVING THE PUBLIC AS
INTENDED. >> IN THIS CASE THIS LOOPHOLE
DESERVES ATTENTION PARTICULARLY AS MANY RESIDENTS ESPECIALLY
YOUNG PEOPLE WOMAN AND NEW VOICES FEEL INCREASINGLY LEFT
OUT AND LOCKED OUT OF OUR POLITICAL LEADERSHIP.
CASE IN POINT JUST A YEAR AGO THERE WASN'T A SINGLE
MILLENNIAL ON THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS ZERO.
>> TODAY WE HAVE SIX ON THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS.
THERE'S SIX SUPERVISORS WHO ARE WORKING PARENTS, IMMIGRANTS
AND RENTERS OF A YOUNGER GENERATION FIVE OF WHICH EVEN
HAVE A FULL HEAD OF HAIR. ME HAVE OF COURSE NOT INCLUDED
. >> A MAJORITY OF THE BOARD OF
SUPERVISORS NOW COMES FROM A NEW GENERATION THAT FELT
UNREPRESENTED BEFORE AND THAT NEW GENERATION OF LEADERSHIP
HAS LED TO RESULTS OVER THE LAST YEAR RESULTS ON HOUSING,
ON SAFETY, ON SMALL BUSINESS. >> THIS YEAR ALONE WE PASSED
THE FAMILY ZONING PLAN AS WELL AS THE TENANT PROTECTION
ORDINANCE JUST TODAY WHICH WILL ENSURE THAT WE CAN BUILD
HOUSING FOR ALL OF OUR NEIGHBORS AND FUTURE
GENERATIONS AND STRENGTHEN TENANT PROTECTIONS FOR YEARS TO
COME. >> ON SAFETY CRIME IS DOWN 30%
ONE OF THE LOWEST IN OUR CITY'S HISTORY AND ONE OF THE LOWEST
OF ANY MAJOR CITY IN THE NATION.
RESTORING PEACE OF MIND TO FAMILIES AND CHILDREN SO THEY
CAN FEEL SAFE WALKING DOWN THE STREET GOING TO SCHOOL OR
PICKING UP THEIR GROCERIES. >> AND FOR THE FIRST TIME
IN YEARS PEOPLE ARE EXCITED ABOUT OUR CITY AGAIN.
>> BUSINESSES ARE INVESTING. TOURISTS WANT TO VISIT AND MOST
IMPORTANTLY THE RESIDENTS FEEL WE'RE ON THE RIGHT TRACK.
>> SO TODAY I'M INTRODUCING A CHARTER AMENDMENT TO CLOSE THIS
TERM LIMIT LOOPHOLE AND PLACE THE QUESTION BEFORE THE PEOPLE
OF SAN FRANCISCO. >> THIS IS ABOUT THE STRUCTURE
OF OUR CITY'S DEMOCRATIC SYSTEM AND WHETHER IT CONTINUES TO
PROMOTE FAIRNESS, OPPORTUNITY AND PUBLIC TRUST.
SAN FRANCISCO WORKS BEST WHEN WE GOVERN WITH CLARITY,
INTEGRITY AND AN EYE TOWARDS THE FUTURE.
>> I'D LIKE TO THANK DEPUTY CITY ATTORNEY BRAD RUSSELL FOR
DRAFTING THIS. JESSICA GUTIERREZ, GARCIA
AND SAM LOGAN IN MY OFFICE THE SAN FRANCISCO YOUNG DEMOCRATS
FOR CO-SPONSORING THE PETITION TO LEAD TO THIS LEGISLATION
AND ORDINANCE AS WELL. AS WELL AS SUPERVISORS CHERYL
DORSEY, SAUTER MELGAR AND WANG FOR THEIR EARLY CO-SPONSORSHIP.
THE REST I SUBMIT THANK YOU. >> SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD
AND SUPERVISOR WALTON U.S. TO BE REFERRED.
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH MY APOLOGIES COLLEAGUES.
COLLEAGUES I'M ALSO REQUESTING A FISCAL AND POLICY ANALYSIS
REGARDING THE ANTICIPATED EXPLORATION OF FEDERAL
EMERGENCY HOUSING VOUCHER FUNDING AND BORDER INSTABILITY
AND HOUSING CHOICE VOUCHERS. SECTION EIGHT RESOURCES AND THE
POTENTIAL ROLE OF THE CITY AND COUNTY OF SAN FRANCISCO
IN PREVENTING DISPLACEMENT AND HOMELESSNESS THROUGH LOCAL
INVESTMENT FROM THE COMPTROLLER'S OFFICE AND THE
BILL TO THE SAN FRANCISCO HOUSING AUTHORITY HAS NOTIFIED
ITS V PARTICIPANTS THAT FEDERAL FUNDING IS EXPECTED TO BE FULLY
EXHAUSTED BY OCTOBER 31ST, 2026 WITH THE FINAL SUBSIDY PAYMENT
ISSUED FOR OCTOBER 2026. SB HOUSEHOLDS INCLUDE
INDIVIDUALS OF FAMILIES PRIORITIZED BECAUSE THEY FACE
THE HIGHEST RISK OF HOMELESSNESS SURVIVORS OF
VIOLENCE, PEOPLE EXITING HOMELESSNESS AND FAMILIES WITH
EXTREMELY LOW INCOMES. >> ALLOWING THESE HOUSEHOLDS TO
LOSE RENTAL ASSISTANCE WILL REVERSE HARD WON PROGRESS,
INCREASE HOMELESSNESS AND CONTRADICT THE CITY'S
STATED COMMITMENT TO PREVENTION, RACIAL EQUITY
AND HOUSING STABILITY. SAN FRANCISCO HAS REPEATEDLY
DEMONSTRATED THAT PREVENTING DISPLACEMENT IS SIGNIFICANTLY
MORE COST EFFECTIVE THAN RESPONDING TO HOMELESSNESS
AFTER IT OCCURS. THIS MOMENT PRESENTS AN
OPPORTUNITY FOR THE CITY TO PROACTIVELY EVALUATE LOCAL
FUNDING STRATEGIES THAT COULD MITIGATE THE LOSS OF FEDERAL
ASSISTANCE AND STABILIZE VULNERABLE HOUSEHOLDS BEFORE
THEY REENTER CRISIS SYSTEMS. TO SUPPORT INFORMED PREVENTION
FOCUSED POLICYMAKING, I RESPECTFULLY REQUEST THAT THE
COMPTROLLER AND THE BIELA ANALYZE AND REPORT ON THE
FOLLOWING COSTS TO PREVENT DISPLACEMENT, SCOPE, EQUITY
AND NEIGHBORHOOD IMPACTS. COST OF INACTION.
POTENTIAL LOCAL FUNDING STRATEGIES AND SCENARIOS.
BUDGET TIMING AND LEGISLATIVE CONSIDERATIONS.
THIS ANALYSIS IS ESSENTIAL TO ENSURING THAT SAN FRANCISCO
DOES NOT KNOWINGLY ALLOW THOUSANDS OF RESIDENTS TO FALL
BACK INTO HOMELESSNESS DUE TO THE EXPIRATION OF A TEMPORARY
FEDERAL PROGRAM PARTICULARLY WHEN LOCAL INTERVENTION MAY BE
MORE FISCALLY RESPONSIBLE THAN ABSORBING THE LONG TERM COSTS
OF DISPLACEMENT. >> THE RISK ASSESSMENT.
>> THANK YOU, SUPERVISOR WALTON.
MR. PRESIDENT, THAT'S THE CONCLUSION OF ROLL CALL FOR
INTRODUCTIONS. LET'S GO TO PUBLIC COMMENT.
ALL RIGHT. >> FOR THOSE OF YOU IN THE
PUBLIC GALLERY, THIS IS YOUR OPPORTUNITY TO LINE UP ON THE
RIGHT HAND SIDE OF THE CHAMBER. YOU MAY SPEAK TO THE MAYORAL
APPEARANCE THE MINUTE SAYS PRESENTED AND THE ITEMS 42
THROUGH 48 ON THE ADOPTION WITHOUT COMMITTEE REFERENCE
CALENDAR OTHER GENERAL MATTERS NOT ON THE PUBLISHED AGENDA BUT
MUST BE WITHIN THE BOARD'S SUBJECT MATTER JURISDICTION.
IF YOU DO BRING UP CONTENT THAT IS NOT WITHIN THE BOARD SUBJECT
MATTER JURISDICTION. WE WILL INTERRUPT YOUR SPEECH.
ALL RIGHT. WE'LL SETTING THE TIMER FOR TWO
MINUTES. >> WELCOME FOR UNTO YOU IS BORN
THIS DAY IN THE CITY OF DAVID A SAVIOR WHICH IS CHRIST THE LORD
. AND THIS SHALL BE ASSIGNED TO
YOU. THIS IS ASSIGNED TO YOU BECAUSE
WE ARE FORCED TO KEEP TIME BY WHEN HE WAS BORN.
IT SHOWS HIS DOMINANCE AT EVERY NEW WILL BEFORE EVERY TONGUE
WILL CONFESS THAT JESUS IS LORD .
NOW MY TEXT COMES TODAY FROM EZEKIEL 23.
THE WORD OF THE LORD CAME AGAIN AND TO ME SAYING SON OF MAN
THERE WERE TWO WOMEN THE DAUGHTERS OF ONE MOTHER
AND THEY COMMITTED AUTUMNS IN EGYPT.
THEY COMMITTED AUTUMNS IN THEIR YOUTH.
THERE WERE THEIR PRESSED AND THERE THEY BRUISED THE
TEATS OF THEIR VIRGINITY AND THE NAMES OF THEM WERE A
WHOLE LA THE ELDER AND THE WHOLE ABAR HER SISTER.
AND THEY WERE MINE AND THEY BEAR SONS AND DAUGHTERS.
THUS WERE THEIR NAMES. >> SAMARIA IS A WHOLE LAW
AND JERUSALEM A WHOLE URBAN GOES ON TO TALK ABOUT HOW GOD
JUDGE THEM FOR FORSAKING HIM AND HOW ASSYRIA TOOK THEM INTO
CAPTIVITY AND THEN 100 SO YEARS MORE BABYLON CAME IN, DESTROYED
THE TEMPLE. >> BUT WHAT'S FASCINATING ABOUT
IT IS THAT WHEN THIS HAPPENED IT WAS ALL TIMED BY THE
ALMIGHTY. >> WE READ THAT FOR 40 YEARS
ISRAEL WANDERED IN THE WILDERNESS AND WHENEVER THE
TABERNACLE THE PILLAR OF CLOUD BY DAY MOVED THEY SOUNDED
TRUMPETS. THEY TOOK DOWN THE TENTS
AND THEY MOVED IN. THEY FOLLOWED THE TABERNACLE.
THEY FOLLOWED THE PILLAR OF FIRE.
IF IT WAS AT NIGHT OR CLOUD BY DAY AS THE ANGEL LED THEM
DURING 42 DURING 40 YEARS IT WAS 42 TIMES THEY MOVED.
OKAY. DO YOU KNOW WHAT THE SUM OF ONE
THROUGH 42 IS? IT'S 910 YEARS.
>> JUST LET THAT SINK IN. GOD IS REAL.
YOU CANNOT AVOID HIM. SAME SEX MARRIAGE IS EVIL.
IT'S WICKED. IT'S WRONG.
YOU CAN'T MAKE IT RIGHT BECAUSE YOURSELF IS AN EVIL AND DON'T
WANT TO LISTEN TO GOD. JESUS CHRIST IS THE ONLY WAY TO
BE SAVED. >> SO JUST NOW THAT YOU
CONCLUDED YOUR SPEECH, YOUR CRITICISM MAY BE HARSH OR
UNFAIR, IT CAN EVEN BE OBNOXIOUS OR UPSETTING TO US.
BUT IF YOU DO CROSS OVER INTO PROTECTED CATEGORIES, MARK, WE
WILL INTERRUPT YOU. >> THIS IS THE NOW.
>> THANK YOU. NEXT SPEAKER PLEASE.
>> THIS IS ME. I'M A PROFESSED ATHEIST.
ORDINARILY I WOULD TALK ABOUT PARTIAL TAXES BUT I'LL LEAVE
THAT FOR A MATTER I JUST HAVE A LITTLE VIGNETTE ABOUT MY
FAVORITE CORNER IN THIS CITY WHICH IS ON 24TH STREET
AND CASTRO AND WE WATCH THE THE POPULACE GO BY.
CHRISTMAS SHOPPING MONSTER BUSSES NOT ALL FROM SAN
FRANCISCO TO SAN FRANCISCO. >> BUSSES ARE ACTUALLY FAIRLY
MODEST IN SIZE. THE MONSTER BUSSES TAKING THE
POOR PEOPLE DOWN TO THE SOUTH AND THEN THE THE SMALL LITTLE
INCIDENT THAT OCCURRED YESTERDAY WHERE ALL OF A SUDDEN
ANOTHER MONSTER TRUCK PULLS UP AT THIS LITTLE CORNER AND IT
WAS TOWING A LARGE TANKER AND APPARENTLY SOMEBODY HAD
REPORTED THAT THERE WERE FECES ON THE CORNER OF CASTRO AND AND
24TH STREET. >> WELL, THOSE FECES TURNED OUT
TO BE A BLACK GLOVE THAT SOMEBODY DROPPED.
BUT WHY ARE WE SPENDING PROBABLY I WOULD SAY THAT
INCIDENT COSTS THE CITY 500 OR MORE DOLLARS BECAUSE THE MAN
WHO DROVE THE BUS AND INVESTIGATED AND FOUND THE
GLOVE AND THREW THE GLOVE IN THE TRASH HAD TO FILL OUT A
LARGE REPORT AND HE WAS THERE FOR 45 MINUTES.
WELL, I DON'T KNOW WHETHER THIS IS THE PROPER WAY TO SPEND
MONEY BUT WE SHALL SEE AS THEY SAY.
WE SHALL SEE. AND BACK TO THE PARCEL TAXES.
>> I WILL NOT THEY APPARENTLY PUT A PROVISION IN THAT ELDER'S
DON'T HAVE TO PAY AND BUT I WILL PAY MY PARCEL TAX OF 100
AND I THINK IT'S 149 $159 WILLING LIKE THANK YOU FOR YOUR
COMMENTS. WELCOME TO THE NEXT SPEAKER.
WALTER PAULSON THANK YOU SUPERVISORS FOR YOUR WORK
SUPERVISORS THANK YOU FOR YOUR WORK FORMER SUPERVISORS ANGELA
WHO WORKS SO HARD OVER THERE ALWAYS ALL THE TIME AND FORMER
MAYORS AND S.F. CHEATS AND THE FORMER EMPLOYEES THERE
AND THANK YOU FOR YOUR WORK SO I'LL JUST SAY SOMETHING
RELIGIOUS A LITTLE BIT RELIGIOUS LET IT BE LET IT BE
LET IT BE LET IT BE THERE WILL BE AN ANSWER LET IT BE AND WHEN
THE NIGHT IS CLOUDY THERE IS STILL A LIGHT THAT SHINES ON ME
SHINE UNTIL TOMORROW LET IT BE AND DON'T QUITE GIVE UP ON THE
CITY BECAUSE ANTICIPATE SHUN ANTICIPATE ATION MIGHT BE JUST
MAKING IT LATE IT'LL KEEPING YOU AWAY YAY YAY YAY EATING
THANK YOU. >> THANK YOU WALTER.
NICE TO SEE YOU WELCOME TO NICE TO SEE YOU AGAIN TOO.
>> GOOD LUCK AND HAVE A GOOD HAPPY HOLIDAY.
THANK YOU. WELCOME TO OUR NEXT SPEAKER.
>> WELCOME. BLESS THEIR HEART MR. DENNIS
WILLIAMS AND MICHAEL DEVELOPER EXECUTIVE DIRECTOR THE FILLMORE
CDC SUPPORTED AND HERE ON BEHALF OF THE LABOR
AND COMMUNITY LEADERS OF THE SEIU 1020 TO ASK IN A VERY
ALLIED ORGANIZATIONS JUST WANT TO REPORT IS A FIGHT COMING
2026 LONGSTANDING RESIDENTS AGAINST THE BILLIONAIRES
CORPORATIONS MAYOR LOUISE PERMIT AS A REFORMS DO NOT KEEP
PEOPLE ROOTED IN OUR CITY THEY FAST TRACK DISPLACEMENT SAN
FRANCISCO HAS THOUSANDS OF VACANT HOMES YET THE CITY KEEPS
PUSHING NEW LUXURY AND MARKET RATE DEVELOPMENTS DESIGNED FOR
CORPORATE WORKFORCES NOT LONG TIME RESIDENTS.
OUR HISTORIC BLACK COMMUNITIES OF THE FILLMORE BAYVIEW
TENDERLOIN ARE BEING RESHAPED WITHOUT US, WITHOUT LOCAL
DEVELOPERS AND COMMUNITY BASED ORGANIZATIONS ARE STILL BEING
SHUT OUT WHILE BILLION DOLLAR PROJECTS RACE AHEAD.
I'M GOING TO GIVE APPROVAL FROM THIS BODY AND WE'VE ALREADY
SEEN WHAT HAPPENS WHEN A CITY OVERBUILDING SPECULATIVE
MARKETS THE.COM CRASH TAUGHT US THIS LESSON AS IT DESTROYED OUR
HISTORICAL MISSION NEIGHBORHOOD WE RAISE RENTS IGNORING THIS
AGAIN WILL PUSH EVEN MORE. SAN FRANCISCO'S OUT SAN
FRANCISCO DOESN'T WE NEED OVERCROWDING FOR CORPORATE
INTERESTS OR OUR BUILDING EVERY TIME A NEW DEVELOPMENT OR
EXCUSE ME A NEW CORPORATION COMES INTO THE CITY WE NEED
EQUITY ACCOUNTABILITY LOWER RENTS, REAL INVESTMENT INTO OUR
COMMUNITIES AND DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS THAT EMPOWERS OUR
COMMUNITY, INVEST IN THE PEOPLE WHO BUILT THIS CITY.
THE WATERFRONT VIEWS ARE THE MISSION OF SCUSE ME THE
WATERFRONT VIEWS OF THE MARINA DISTRICT SHOULD BE ENJOYED BY
GENERATIONS TO COME AS I HAVE NOT SACRIFICED TO DEVELOP AGREE
TO SMALL TIME THE SMALL TOWN FEEL OF COAL VALLEY NO VALLEY
AND THE CASTRO DESERVES PRESERVATION TO OUTER SUN SAY
BEFORE DISTRICT ONE HAS THE RIGHT TO PROTECT ITS CHARACTER
AND COMMUNITY PLEASE STOP STRESSING OUR ELDERS CITYWIDE
THE DIMLY LIT RESTAURANTS AND SMALL BUSINESSES ALONG THE
HILLS OF BEAUTIFUL BERNAL HEIGHTS REPRESENT MORE THAN
COMMERCE. THEY REPRESENT MEMORY, CULTURE
AND BELONGING. THIS IS SAN FRANCISCO WE HAVE
FOUGHT FOR. IT IS SAN FRANCISCO WORTH
PROTECTING? >> THANK YOU DENNIS WILLIAMS
THANK YOU SIR FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
OKAY. I ONLY GOT TWO MINUTES.
I'LL TRY TO BE REALLY QUICK. FIRST I WANT TO START OFF THE
ST PIECE IS A DAUGHTER OF DIALOG AND REASON.
OKAY LET'S DIALOG AND REASON FIRST I WANT TO SAY THE CITY'S
GOING TO POT LITERALLY I BELIEVE THE FEDS SHOULD HAVE
COME IN AND CLOSED THE MARIJUANA DISPENSARIES BECAUSE
THERE'S RAMPANT SMOKING ON THE STREET AND THE MARIJUANA
THEY'RE NOT PROSECUTING. OKAY RIGHT NOW TODAY IN A VERY
BEEN HAPPENING FOR A LONG TIME 30 2763 WHITE TRUCK OUTSIDE OF
WELLS FARGO WAS SELLING MARIJUANA TO THE COMMUNITY.
>> OKAY WE NEED TO GET SOMETHING DONE ON THAT
EXECUTIVE ORDER. WE SHOULD HAVE HER AS A NEW
SHERIFF IN TOWN. I WANT TO SAY ALL YOU SHIP ALL
LAW AND ORDER THANK YOU FOR YOUR SERVICE.
WE SHOULD HAVE A SECOND ORDER FOR CITY GOVERNMENT TO WORK
WITH CLOSELY WITH THE FEDERAL GOVERNMENT CONCERNING THE DRUG
CASES. ANY NO MORE OUT OF CUSTODY DRUG
CASES I MEAN WHEN THEY HAVEN'T THEY SHOULD BE OUT OF CUSTODY
WHEN THEY'RE GOING TO THROUGH THE DRUG CASES THEY WILL ONLY
BE RELEASED AFTER THE CASE IF THEY'RE PROSECUTED.
>> WELL, WHATEVER. OKAY.
HERE'S A BIG PROBLEM IN THE CITY WITH THE SCOOTERS ON THE
SIDEWALKS AS YOU WALK SCOOTERS DRIVING ON THE SIDEWALKS.
WHY THE PROSECUTING THESE PEOPLE?
>> ANOTHER THING TO RETAIL THEFT IS REALLY IS RIDICULOUS
WHAT'S HAPPENING HERE IN CITY IN A RETAIL THEFT, THE
SAFEWAYS, WALGREENS AND ALL THAT.
>> LET ME GET BACK TO THE MARIJUANA THING AGAIN IN UTAH.
>> RECREATIONAL USE IS NOT IS ILLEGAL IS RECREATION USE OF
MARIJUANA IN UTAH STADIUMS ARE ILLEGAL.
SAN FRANCISCO WE COULD DO BETTER.
LURIE SAYS HE TRYING TO CLEAN UP THE STREETS AND THIS
AND THAT. >> I THINK WE CAN DO BETTER WAY
BETTER. >> THAT WAS JUST A STICKING
POINT FOR HIM TO GARNER LIKE HE'S GOING TO DO SOME GREAT
HERE IN THE CITY BUT I THINK SAN FRANCISCO BE THE TEMPLATE
TO ALL IT'S THE NATION HOW WE CONDUCT BUSINESS AS FAR AS THE
SAFETY ON THE STREET, THE ERADICATION OF THE DRUGS
AND AND THE RESPECT OF OUR LAW AND ORDER.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH. THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
>> WELCOME TO OUR NEXT SPEAKER BOARD OF SUPERVISORS A
MAYOR OFFICE OF SAN FRANCISCO. THE TITLE OF THIS SPEECH IS 28
ALLIANCE INTERNATIONAL ON MAY OF 2020 FOR ABOUT SIX MONTHS
AGO I WAS RUNNING HASTILY IN PORTLAND NEIGHBORHOOD AND I
WAS STAPLING POSTERS TO THE TREE PROMOTING MY AGENDA.
I RAN INTO ONE MEMBER OF THE BOARD SUPERVISOR WHO SITS HERE
TODAY IN HIS CHAMBER HEY HELP ME HAND OUT ALL THESE POSTERS
I'M RUNNING FOR POLICY ADVISOR ALL RIGHT, WELL I'M ALSO
RUNNING FOR OFFICE. I REPORT DIRECTLY TO ELON MUSK
AS TWITTER MASTER OF X ABOUT TWO MONTHS AGO I WALK INTO THE
DOORSTEP OF THIS PARTICULAR PERSON RIGHT IN THE DOORSTEP AS
PROMISES WERE ETCHED INTO THE NAME OF THIS CLEARING I
REMEMBERED LARGE POSTER HAND IT TO ME MY JOB HERE OPEN MY MOUTH
SMIRKED TODAY I STAND A FEW FEET IN FRONT OF THIS MEMBER
TODAY I STATED I REPORT DIRECTLY TO ELON MUSK KOTA AS
BLACK NO PART AGO I ALSO HOLD ACCOUNT OF WARREN BUFFETT I'M
THAT DESIGNATE LEADER OF ENTIRE DEMOCRATIC PARTY AS A 48TH
PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATE I'M THE FOUNDING MEMBER OF
DOJ'S DEPARTMENT OF GOVERNMENT IF WE PRINT AS BOSS DEPARTMENT
OF DEMOCRATS SUPERIORITY MY TASK IS TO SPEARHEAD THE
DRAFTING A NEW CONSTITUTION CALL WORLDWIDE CONSTITUTION JOE
BIDEN IS TASKED TO DRAFT US. HOWEVER BERNIE SANDERS IS
CHARGED CODIFIED THE DETAILS I STAND BEFORE THE BOARD FOR MY
PIVOTAL ROLE TO SEE THE EXECUTION OF 20 EIGHT ALLIANCE
INTERNATIONAL. >> THANK YOU.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. WELCOME TO OUR NEXT SPEAKER.
>> HELLO. MY ONLY COMMENT IS MERCY
AND GRACE. >> THANK YOU FOR THOSE COMMENTS
. >> WELCOME.
WELCOME. GOOD AFTERNOON ANGELA.
I WAS ACROSS THE WAY OVER AT THE S.F. MTA BOARD MEETING.
MY NAME IS BARRY TORONTO. I'M WITH THE TAXI WORKERS
ALLIANCE AND TODAY IN CLOSED SESSION THE MTA IS AGAIN
LOOKING FOR THE THOUSANDS TIME THE LAWSUIT BETWEEN THE CREDIT
UNION AND DANCE OF MTA THE CITY OF SAN FRANCISCO.
>> WE NEED SOME SOLUTION TO THIS PROBLEM OF DEBT RELIEF FOR
THE PURCHASE BIDDING HOLDERS AND THE INCOME THEY MAKE FROM
THE AIRPORT IS NOT ENOUGH. SO I URGE YOU TO GET SOME
ANSWERS BECAUSE YOU DID IN A PRIOR MAKE UP THE BOARD PASSED
A RESOLUTION ASKING FOR PARTICIPATION FROM
REPRESENTATIVES FROM THE PURCHASE KNOW DOWNLOADERS
AND THEY HAVE BEEN KEPT OUT OF THE LOOP FOR THE LONGEST TIME.
SO I URGE YOU GETS ON MY CLOCK I URGE YOU TO TO PLEASE ASK
SOME QUESTIONS ALSO I APPRECIATIVE OF I KNOW I WAS
SHOULDN'T SAY OF A SUPERVISOR FEEL THEY'RE INTERESTED AND IN
LOCAL REGULATION OR CONTROL OF THE WAY MOST ON CITY STREETS I
URGE YOU TO REACH OUT TO YOUR STATE LEGISLATORS ASKING THEM
TO PASS LEGISLATION A REVITALIZED AT 915 IN ORDER
DAVE CURTIS'S LEGISLATION AND ORDERED ALLOW LOCAL
ENTITIES TO HAVE SOME SAY ON WHERE THEY CAN GO HOW MUCH THEY
CAN CHARGE AND HOW MANY CAN BE ON THE STREETS.
YOU SHOULDN'T HAVE AN UNLIMITED NUMBER OF OF OF AUTONOMOUS
VEHICLES ON THE CITY STREETS. YEAH, I DON'T KNOW HOW MANY
TIMES YOU'VE SEEN THEM 3 OR 4 AT A TIME CLOGGING THE STREETS
AND HAVING BARELY ABLE TO GET AROUND THEM SO AND AND THEY
SHOULDN'T BE KILLING OUR PETS AS WELL.
IT'S A SAD STATE THAT YOU FEEL YOU'RE HELPLESS IN THIS AREA
AND I URGE YOU ON THIS HOLIDAY SEASON HAPPY HANUKKAH.
HAPPY HOLIDAYS, MERRY CHRISTMAS AND HAPPY KWANZAA THAT YOU THAT
YOU CAN GET MORE INVOLVED ON WHAT HAPPENS ON THE CITY
STREETS BECAUSE THEY DON'T REALLY CONTRIBUTE MUCH
FINANCIALLY. AND IN CLOSING, I ASK YOU TO
ASK THE STATE LEGISLATURE TO RAISE THE CEILING FOR HOW MUCH
THEY CAN CHARGE FOR A RIDE SO YOU HAVE MORE MONEY FOR IT TO
IMPROVE. >> THANK YOU VERY THANK YOU.
GOOD TO SEE YOU. THANK YOU.
WELCOME TO OUR NEXT SPEAKER IS MR. PRESIDENT MADAM CLERK
ANGELA. UH, IT'S NICE TO HEAR THINK
ABOUT ROB REINER. HE'S DEFINITELY WAS AN ARTIST
SON FOR VERY UNFORTUNATE. >> YOU KNOW, THERE'S NOBODY
THERE'S NOBODY ON THIS BOARD WHO'S FROM MY GENERATION.
>> IT'S NOT BOTHERING ME THAT MUCH.
WE HAD OUR CHANCE. I'M READING A BOOK BY ROBERT
AND IT'S THE NAME OF THE TITLE IS COMING UP SHORT.
WELL, YOU KNOW, IT'S YEAH, IT'S KIND OF UPON BUT THE FACT IS MY
GENERATION CAME UP SHORT AND SO WILL THE I'M NOT SURE IF
THERE'S ANY GENS ON HERE BUT THERE YOUR TIME WILL COME
AND YOU WON'T BE ON THE BOARD ANY MORE THAN THE MILLENNIALS
WON'T BE ON THE BOARD ANYMORE. AND YOU KNOW AFTER THAT THE
POST MILLENNIALS I HAVEN'T I HAVEN'T A THEM I HAVEN'T THEM
WHO'S A POST POST MILLENNIAL I HAVE A GREAT I HAVE A GREAT
SOMETHING A NIECE OR A NEPHEW I'M NOT SURE WHICH WHAT I AM
CONCERNED ABOUT ON THIS BOARD IS TYPE A PERSONALITIES
AND BECAUSE I'VE SEEN ENOUGH OF THEM IN BOTH THE LEFT AND THE
RIGHT BUT YOU KNOW WHAT I'M I'M PRETTY SURE THAT EVEN AS THE
LAW IS WRITTEN AS IT'S RIGHT NOW, SCOTT WIENER IS PROBABLY
NOT GOING TO COME BACK AND BE A MEMBER OF THIS BOARD.
>> THANK YOU THANK YOU OUT AUTO DUFFY FOR YOUR COMMENTS WELCOME
TO OUR NEXT SPEAKER MY PORTION HERE GOOD AFTERNOON IS IT ON?
YES GOOD AFTERNOON MR. SUPERVISOR AND SUPERVISORS.
I'M VIRGINIA MARSHALL. I'M A RETIRED EDUCATOR AND I
SMILE IN EVERY DAY. I CAME DOWN FOR AN AGENDA ITEM
THAT YOU PUT ON THE TOP OF THE AGENDA REPARATIONS.
>> I AM SO VERY HAPPY ABOUT THAT MA'AM IS I'M PAUSING YOUR
TIME BUT THAT ITEM IS NOT ELIGIBLE FOR PUBLIC COMMENT.
I'M NOT UNDERSTANDING THAT MY COMMENT THAT WAS JUST A PERK
IN THE COMMENT SO I RESUME YOUR TIME.
THANK YOU SO MUCH. YOU CAN MAKE ME FORGET MY
THOUGHT SO II2 THINGS I WANT TO TALK ABOUT IS DIVERSITY.
WHEN I LOOK AT MERYL LURIE AND ALL THE PEOPLE STAND BEHIND
HIM MOST TIMES THEY DON'T LOOK LIKE ME.
THEY'RE LIKE OCCASIONS. I KNOW THERE WAS THAT MANY
OCCASIONS IN SAN FRANCISCO WHEN I LOOK AT THIS BOARD OTHER THAN
SUPERVISOR WALTON THEY DON'T LOOK LIKE ME.
I'M VERY HAPPY TO SEE A SUPERVISOR WONG RIGHT HERE.
>> SO WHEN YOU WHEN YOU GO YOUR TIME IS UP PLEASE MAKE EVERY
EFFORT TO MAKE SURE SOMEONE REPLACES YOU WHO LOOKS LIKE
MORE LIKE SAN FRANCISCO WHEN I SEE YOU I FEEL SAD.
I'LL SAY IT AGAIN WHEN I SEE MERYL LURIE AT A PRESS
CONFERENCE. ALL BEHIND HIM ARE ALWAYS
PEOPLE WHO DO NOT LOOK LIKE ME .
SO DIVERSITY DOES COUNT AND I'M SO VERY HAPPY TO BE A BOY IS A
CHAMPIONSHIP. I REMEMBER A TURKEY DAY A
WOODROW WILSON HIGH SCHOOL. YOU DON'T KNOW WHERE WOODROW
WILSON IS. IT IS NOW VERY HIGH SCHOOL.
SO ANYWAY, THANK YOU SO MUCH KEITH.
PLEASE KEEP IN MIND DIVERSITY AND PLEASE HELP THAT THERE ARE
SO MANY YOUNG PEOPLE WHO ARE BORN HERE IN SAN FRANCISCO BUT
THEY CANNOT AFFORD TO BUY A HOME IN SAN FRANCISCO.
THEY WORK EVERY DAY TO INCOMES BUT I STILL CANNOT AFFORD TO
BUY A HOME. >> SO DIVERSITY AND HOUSING IS
VERY, VERY IMPORTANT. >> THANK YOU SO MUCH.
THANK YOU, MARSHALL FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
>> WELCOME TO OUR NEXT SPEAKER. HI MY NAME IS LEE A PENCIL OR
I'M A UNION ORGANIZER WITH THE INTERNATIONAL BROTHERHOOD OF
TEAMSTERS AND THE JOINT COUNCILS OF OUR NORTHERN
CALIFORNIA AMAZON ORGANIZER AND FORMER WORKER AT DC SIX I'M
JUST HERE FOR NUMBER 43 ON THE DOCKET.
I JUST WANTED TO THANK THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS ESPECIALLY
PRESIDENT RANDLEMAN FOR YOUR SUPPORT AND BACKING US IN OUR
FIGHT TO BRING AMAZON TO THE BARGAINING TABLE.
>> WE'RE LOOKING TO GET A CONTRACT WITH FAIR WAGES
AND FAIR WORKING CONDITIONS BECAUSE THIS COMPANY VALUED AT
OVER $2 TRILLION AT THE VERY LEAST WE SHOULD HAVE A UNION
CONTRACT THAT PROTECTS US AND GIVES US THE DIGNITY
AND RESPECT WE DESERVE ON THE JOB.
>> SO I'M JUST HERE TO SAY THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR YOUR
CONTINUED SUPPORT. OKAY?
YEAH, THANKS. THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
WELCOME TO OUR NEXT SPEAKER. HELLO, MY NAME IS GINNY
ROBERTS. I AM A CURRENT AMAZON WORKER
AND ALSO A FIELD ORGANIZER FOR THE INTERNATIONAL BROTHERHOOD
OF TEAMSTERS. >> I ALSO WANTED TO THANK THE
BOARD FOR YOUR UNWAVERING SUPPORT BEHIND THOSE WORKERS.
WE ARE WORKING HARD TO PROVIDE A SERVICE FOR THE CITY.
AND THE ONLY THING THAT WE WANT IN RETURN IS, YOU KNOW, SOME
DIGNITY AND RESPECT FOR THE WORK THAT WE DO A LIVABLE WAGE
IN THE CITY OF SAN FRANCISCO AND BETTER BENEFITS FOR THOSE
OF US WHO HAVE WEAR AND TEAR ON OUR BODIES FROM DOING, YOU
KNOW, HOURS AND HOURS ON END THE SAME WORK YEAR AFTER YEAR
AND ALSO AROUND THIS TIME WHILE WE ARE LITERALLY DELIVERING
CHRISTMAS. SO IT REALLY MEANS THE WORLD
FOR US THAT YOU GUYS HAVE OUR BACK AND AND STANDING WITH US
AS WE ARE FIGHTING AMAZON FOR A CONTRACT THAT REFLECTS THE HARD
WORK THAT WE PROVIDE FOR THE CITY.
>> THANK YOU THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
ANY OTHER MEMBERS OF THE PUBLIC LIKE TO ADDRESS THE BOARD
DURING GENERAL PUBLIC COMMENT. >> ALL RIGHT, MR. PRESIDENT.
ALL RIGHT. THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK.
PUBLIC COMMENT IS NOW CLOSED AND LET'S GO TO OUR FOR
ADOPTION OF THAT COMMITTEE REFERENCE AGENDA ITEMS 42
THROUGH 48 ITEMS 42 THROUGH 48 WERE INTRODUCED FOR ADOPTION
BUT WITHOUT COMMITTEE REFERENCE A UNANIMOUS VOTE IS REQUIRED
FOR ADOPTION OF A RESOLUTION ON FIRST APPEARANCE TODAY.
ALTERNATIVELY, A MEMBER MAY REQUIRE A RESOLUTION ON FIRST
APPEARANCE TO GO TO COMMITTEE SUPERVISOR CHERYL CAN WE
DISCUSS NUMBER 43 SEPARATELY PLEASE?
>> SO FOR SOME 43 I'M GOING TO COVER IT SO MAYBE WE'LL DO IT
AT THE SEVER NUMBER 43 YEAH AT THAT POINT APOLOGIES.
>> SO WE'RE GOING TO FOR 43 I WOULD ALSO LIKE TO SEVER 44
SUPERVISOR CHANNEL 42. ALL RIGHT.
I DON'T SEE ANYBODY ELSE SO ON THE REMAINING BALANCE OF THE
ITEMS, MADAM CLERK, COULD YOU PLEASE CALL THE ROLL ON ITEMS
OF 45 THROUGH 48 SUPERVISOR GENTLEMEN HI MANDELL MAN I
SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR I SUPERVISOR SADR SADR I
SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL I SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON I
SUPERVISOR WONG WONG I SUPERVISOR CHAN CHIN I
SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN I SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY I
SUPERVISOR FIELDER FIELDER I AND SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD
I THERE ARE 11 EYES WITHOUT OBJECTION THE MOTIONS ARE
APPROVED CHAFFETZ MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM 42 ITEM 42
THIS IS A RESOLUTION TO SUPPORT THE PASSAGE OF THE HOUSING BOOM
BUILDING OCCUPANCY OPPORTUNITIES FOR MILLIONS ACT
THAT WILL BE AUTHORED AND INTRODUCED BY UNITED STATES
SENATOR ADAM SCHIFF AND U.S. REPRESENTATIVE LATIFA SIMON TO
INCREASE FEDERAL INVESTMENT AND EXPAND INCENTIVES TO
ENCOURAGE HOUSING PRODUCTION AND TO HELP ADDRESS ROOT CAUSES
OF THE HOUSING AFFORDABILITY CRISIS.
>> SUPERVISOR CHAN THANK YOU PRESIDENT GENTLEMEN.
COLLEAGUES, AS I HAVE SAID TIME AND AGAIN IN ORDER TO BUILD
HOUSING WE NEED TWO KEY ELEMENTS LAND AND MONEY
ESPECIALLY IF THE CITY IS TO BUILD HOUSING THAT SAN
FRANCISCO RESIDENTS CAN ACTUALLY AFFORD EVEN OUR
HOUSING ELEMENTS THE DOCUMENTS THAT WE'VE BEEN REFERRING TO
THROUGHOUT OUR ZONING CONVERSATION AND THE
LEGISLATIVE PROCESS STATED THAT THE CITY IS EXCEEDING ITS
MARKET RATE HOUSING GOAL BUT HAVE CONTINUED TO FALL FAR
SHORT AND FAR BEHIND ON BUILDING AFFORDABLE HOUSING
COUPLED WITH THE INCREASING PRESSURE CREATED BY THE
SPECULATIVE REAL ESTATE MARKET, THIS DYNAMIC IS LEADING TO AN
INCREASE OF DISPLACEMENT AND OUTMIGRATION OF LOW
AND MIDDLE INCOME HOUSEHOLDS MANY OF WHOM ARE THE ECONOMIC
DRIVING FORCES AND THE WORKFORCE BACKBONE OF THE
WORKFORCE OF SAN FRANCISCO'S LOCAL ECONOMY.
WE NEED TO BUILD HOUSING AND WE NEED TO BUILT FAST TO ENSURE WE
KEEP OUR HEALTH CARE WORKERS, TEACHERS, FIRST RESPONDERS
AND NONPROFIT WORKERS, TRANSIT OPERATORS, CONSTRUCTION WORKERS
AND SMALL BUSINESS OWNERS TO BE ABLE TO CONTINUE TO LIVE IN OUR
CITY. WE NEED TO SUPPORT HOUSING THAT
THEY CAN AFFORD. THIS IS WHY I INTRODUCE A
RESOLUTION IN SUPPORT OF SENATE BILL NUMBER 3464 INTRODUCED BY
SENATOR ADAM SCHIFF'S ALSO BILL AS HOUSING BOOM BUILDING
OCCUPATION OCCUPANCY OPPORTUNITIES FOR MILLIONS ACT
WHICH WILL INCREASE FEDERAL INVESTMENT AND EXPAND NEW
POLICIES TO ACCELERATE HOUSING PRODUCTION ACROSS THE NATION.
THE ACT WILL EXPAND THE LOW INCOME HOUSING TAX CREDIT
AND OTHER LOAN PROGRAM THAT MANY HOUSING DEVELOPERS RELIED
ON INVEST $15 BILLION MORE AND MORE ANNUALLY FOR STATES TO
SUPPORT DEVELOPMENT OF WORKFORCE RENTAL HOUSING SO WE
CAN STABILIZE HOUSING COSTS FOR WORKERS, INCENTIVIZE LOCAL
AND STATE GOVERNMENT TO CONVERT UNDERUTILIZED PUBLIC LAND LIKE
OUR SFM TO SITE INTO HOUSING AND GET THE MOST AFFORDABLE
HOUSING UNITS THAT WE CAN AND AND THEN IT ALSO TACKLE THE
ROOT CAUSES OF AFFORDABILITY CRISIS BY FUNDING BEHAVIOR
HEALTH HOMELESSNESS SERVICE AND TENANTS SUPPORT PROGRAM
AND STRENGTHENING FAIR HOUSING AND LANGUAGE ACCESS REGULATION
AGAIN THIS ALSO INCLUDES THE UNDERSTANDING THAT WE MUST ALSO
BUILD WORKFORCE AND MIDDLE INCOME HOUSING.
SO COLLEAGUES WITH THAT WE HAVE LEARNED AND GOTTEN MORE
INFORMATION. IT'S A REASON WHY I HAVE
CIRCULATED A NON SUBSTANTIVE AMENDMENTS TO UPDATE A SENATE
BILL NUMBER SINCE INTRODUCTION LAST WEEK AND I'D LIKE TO MAKE
THE MOTION TO AMEND OR I'D LIKE TO MAKE THE MOTION TO AMEND
AND IT'S YOU CAN SEE INDICATED PAGE ONE TWO INSERTS THE SENATE
BILL NUMBER. SENATE BILL NUMBER 3464
AND THAT'S ON LINE THREE AND THEN ONLINE FIVE A
COMPANION BILL THAT WILL BE AUTHOR AND INTRODUCE AND TO
CLARIFY THAT A SEPARATE BILL IS ACTUALLY ON LINE SIX
IN SEPARATE BILL ACTUALLY IS BEING AUTHOR INTRODUCED BY OUR
CONGRESSWOMAN LATIFA SIMON IN DISTRICT 12 AND.
>> THANK YOU AND I HOPE TO HAVE YOUR SUPPORT.
ALL RIGHT THERE'S A MOTION FROM SUPERVISOR CHIN AND SECOND FROM
SUPERVISOR WALTON TO AMEND THE RESOLUTION AS DESCRIBED BY
SUPERVISOR CHAN AND SHOWN IN THE DOCUMENT SHE HAS
CIRCULATED. COLLEAGUE CAN WE TAKE THAT
MOTION WITHOUT OBJECTION I THINK WE CAN.
THE MOTION IS APPROVED AND THEN ON THE AMENDED RESOLUTION I
THINK WE CAN TAKE THAT SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL WITHOUT
OBJECTION THE AMENDED RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED THAT.
THANK YOU SUPERVISOR JIM MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEM 43.
>> ITEM 43 RESOLUTION TO SUPPORT THE INTERNATIONAL
BROTHERHOOD OF TEAMSTERS IN THEIR EFFORTS TO BARGAIN
WITH AMAZON WEB SERVICES ON BEHALF OF WORKERS AT THE DC DC
K SIX WAREHOUSE. THANK YOU MADAM CLERK NOW
CIGARETS CHERYL THANK YOU CHAIR PRESIDENT AMENDMENT I AM
EXTREMELY DISAPPOINTED TO REPORT THAT I'VE BEEN ADVISED
TO RECUSE MYSELF ON THIS MATTER BY THE CITY ATTORNEY.
MY OFFICE HAS BEEN IN TOUCH WITH THE CLERK TO EQUALLY
DISAPPOINTINGLY REMOVE MYSELF AS A CO-SPONSOR AND I WILL STEP
AWAY FROM MY OFFICE FOR MY DESK EXCUSE ME FOR THIS VOTE.
>> THANK YOU. YOU CAN LEAVE.
I'LL MAKE A MOTION TO EXCUSE YOU NOW YOU KNOW YOU YOU LEAVE
. >> GO, GO, GO.
I'D LIKE TO MAKE A MOTION TO EXCUSE SUPERVISOR CHERYL FROM
THIS VOTE SECONDED BY SUPERVISOR MAHMUD.
I THINK WE CAN TAKE THAT WITHOUT OBJECTION.
>> SUPERVISOR CHERYL IS EXCUSED .
ALL RIGHT, COLLEAGUES, THANKS TO ALL OF YOU WHO WERE ABLE TO
BE OUT ON THE STEPS WITH US EARLIER TODAY.
I KNOW THAT WE WERE ALL THERE IN SPIRIT.
WE HAD AMAZON WORKERS AND TEAMSTERS LOCAL SIX, SIX
FIVE AND LOTS OF OTHER TEAMSTERS LOCALS OUT THERE THAT
ARE PART OF. JOINT COUNCIL SEVEN AND THE
POINT IS TO SUPPORT THE WORKERS AT THE DC K SIX WAREHOUSE
IN THE BAYVIEW. IT'S BEEN MORE THAN A YEAR
SINCE MORE THAN 100 WORKERS IN THE WAREHOUSE SIGNED CARDS
TO DEMAND UNION RECOGNITION. AMAZON HAS RESISTED RECOGNIZING
THEM AND BARGAINING AND THERE HAVE NOW BEEN I THINK A COUPLE
OF NLRB COMPLAINTS ISSUED. FOR ILLEGAL UNION BUSTING
ACTIVITY AT THE FACILITY AND AND THEN A SECOND ONE ABOUT
MORE ILLEGAL UNION BUSTING ACTIVITY.
>> AND SO AS WAS SAID BY A NUMBER OF US OUT THERE TODAY,
SAN FRANCISCO IS A UNION TOWN. >> WE DO EXPECT ALL OF OUR
BUSINESSES TO RESPECT LABOR. AND SO THIS RESOLUTION GIVES
THE BOARD THE OPPORTUNITY TO TO EXPRESS SUPPORT FOR THE
ORGANIZING EFFORT AND FOR THE FIGHT FOR A FAIR CONTRACT AT
THE DC K SIX WAREHOUSE. SO THANKS TO THANKS TO THE
TEAMSTERS AND THE AMAZON WORKERS FOR STICKING WITH US
THROUGH THE ENTIRETY OF THE MEETING AND I THINK WE'RE GOING
TO GIVE YOU A. PROBABLY A UNANIMOUS VOTE.
I THINK WE HAVE ALMOST EVERYBODY'S CO-SPONSORSHIP ON
THIS. SO THANKS TO ALL.
>> AND WITH THAT, MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL THE ROLL ON THIS
ITEM ON ITEM 43. SUPERVISOR GENTLEMEN.
ALL RIGHT, GENTLEMEN, I SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR I
SUPERVISOR SAUTER SUTTER I SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON EYES
SUPERVISOR WONG WONG EYES SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN EYES
SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN EYES SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY EYES
SUPERVISOR FIELDER FIELDER I. AND SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD
EITHER ATTORNEYS WITHOUT OBJECTION THE MOTION THE
RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM 44 ITEM
44 THIS IS A RESOLUTION TO CONDEMN THE TRUMP
ADMINISTRATION'S ATTACK ON HIGHER EDUCATION AND TO AFFIRM
THE CITY AND COUNTY OF SAN FRANCISCO'S COMMITMENT TO
PROTECTING HIGHER EDUCATION FROM POLITICAL INTERFERENCE.
>> THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK. SO THIS RESOLUTION AFFIRMS SAN
FRANCISCO'S COMMITMENT TO ACADEMIC FREEDOM IN THE FACE OF
THE TRUMP ADMINISTRATION'S ATTACKS ON HIGHER EDUCATION AS
AS OUR CLERK INDICATED SINCE INAUGURATION DAY AND FOR NEARLY
A FULL YEAR THE TRUMP ADMINISTRATION HAS MOUNTED A
SUSTAINED AND AGGRESSIVE CAMPAIGN AGAINST INSTITUTIONS
OF HIGHER EDUCATION. IT'S LEVERAGED BILLIONS OF
DOLLARS IN FEDERAL FUNDING TO COERCE UNIVERSITIES TO CONFORM
TO A VARIETY OF DEMANDS WHICH INCLUDE DISMANTLING DIVERSITY,
EQUITY AND INCLUSION INITIATIVES.
STOPPING SCIENTIFIC RESEARCH INTO ISSUES INCLUDING PUBLIC
HEALTH AND CLIMATE CHANGE, SUPPRESSING FREE SPEECH
AND PROTESTS AND RESTRICTING THE ENROLLMENT OF INTERNATIONAL
STUDENTS. THESE ACTIONS UNDERMINE
FUNDAMENTAL RIGHTS AND PLACE LIFESAVING RESEARCH AT RISK.
HOWEVER, IN ORDER TO PREVENT MASSIVE CUTS TO THEIR PROGRAMS
AND UNDER THE THREAT OF FEDERAL INVESTIGATIONS.
NUMBER OF INSTITUTIONS ACROSS THE COUNTRY HAVE MADE DEALS
CONCEDING TO THE TRUMP ADMINISTRATION'S DEMANDS.
THESE CONCESSIONS INCLUDE PAYING MILLIONS OF DOLLARS
IN SETTLEMENTS, BANNING TRANSGENDER ATHLETES FROM
COMPETING AND OUSTING UNIVERSITY OFFICIALS THE TRUMP
ADMINISTRATION DEEMS UNCOOPERATIVE.
HIGHER EDUCATION INSTITUTIONS IN CALIFORNIA ARE CURRENTLY
UNDER IMMENSE PRESSURE FROM THE TRUMP ADMINISTRATION TO DO THE
SAME. RECENTLY THE CITY COUNCIL THE
CITY OF LOS ANGELES ADOPT ADOPTED A RESOLUTION URGING OUR
COLLEGES AND UNIVERSITIES TO STAND STRONG, TO UPHOLD FREE
SPEECH, ACADEMIC FREEDOM AND EQUITY, EQUITABLE ACCESS TO
EDUCATION. AND ADVOCATES ARE ASKING OTHER
CITIES TO CHIME IN WITH THIS RESOLUTION.
THE SAN FRANCISCO BOARD OF SUPERVISORS WILL DO SO.
DIVERSITY OF THOUGHT COMMITMENT TO SCIENTIFIC INTEGRITY
AND OPEN DISCUSSION HAVE MADE OUR HIGHER EDUCATION SYSTEM THE
BEST IN THE WORLD ACADEMIC FREEDOM IS ESSENTIAL TO OUR
LIBERTY AND OUR SUCCESS AND WE HAVE TO DO EVERYTHING WE CAN TO
OPPOSE ITS EROSION. I DO WANT TO THANK FORMER L.A.
CITY ATTORNEY MIKE FEUER AND CRIMSON COURAGE, A GROUP OF
HARVARD ALUMNI WORKING WITH UNIVERSITIES ACROSS THE COUNTRY
TO STAND UP TO TRUMP'S DEMANDS FOR BRINGING THIS LEGISLATION
OR THIS PROPOSED PROPOSAL FOR A RESOLUTION TO US.
>> AND I ALSO WANT TO THANK SUPERVISOR SAUTTER FOR HIS CO
SPONSORSHIP AND I TRUST I WANT I'M GOING TO THANK ALL OF YOU
FOR YOUR SUPPORT. >> MADAM CLERK, COULD YOU
PLEASE CALL THE ROLL ON THIS ITEM ON ITEM 44 SUPERVISOR
MENDELSON HI MENDELSON I SUPERVISOR MILKER MELGAR I
SUPERVISOR SUTTER SUTTER I SUPERVISOR FOR CHERYL CHERYL I
SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON I. SUPERVISOR WONG WONG I
SUPERVISOR CHEN CHEN I SUPERVISOR CHEN CHEN I
SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY I SUPERVISOR FIELDER FIELDER I
AND SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD EITHER ARE LEBANESE.
>> WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED.
>> ALL RIGHT MADAM CLERK DO WE HAVE ANY IMPERATIVE AGENDA
ITEMS? >> THERE ARE NONE TO REPORT.
>> MR. PRESIDENT, WOULD YOU PLEASE READ THE IN MEMORIAM SO
YESTERDAY'S MEETING WILL BE ADJOURNED IN MEMORY OF THE
FOLLOWING BELOVED INDIVIDUALS. ON BEHALF OF SUPERVISOR MANDEL
MEN FOR THE LATE MR. DANIEL CHESSER ON BEHALF OF SUPERVISOR
CARR FOR THE LATE DR. PATRICIA SULLIVAN ON BEHALF OF
SUPERVISOR DORSEY FOR THE LATE ROBERT REINER AND MICHELE
REINER. I THINK THAT BRINGS US TO THE
END OF OUR AGENDA, MADAM CLERK, DO WE HAVE ANY FURTHER BUSINESS
BEFORE US TODAY? >> ONLY TO STATE, MR.
PRESIDENT, THAT THE BOARD WILL RESUME ON JANUARY 6TH, 2026.
>> THANK YOU MADAM CLERK. >> WE ARE ADJOURNED.
THANK YOU